<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Hacking - Category - Malicious Link - Blog by mubix - Rob Fuller</title>
        <link>https://malicious.link/categories/hacking/</link>
        <description>Hacking - Category - Malicious Link - Blog by mubix - Rob Fuller</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>mubix@hak5.org (Rob Fuller)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>mubix@hak5.org (Rob Fuller)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2008 03:29:38 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://malicious.link/categories/hacking/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>The Root of All Evil-(grade)</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008-10-12-the-root-of-all-evil-grade/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2008 03:29:38 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008-10-12-the-root-of-all-evil-grade/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[So there I was&hellip;
Today I was sitting at home watching Irongeek’s post of John Strand’s talk Defense In Depth is Dead, Long Live Defense In Depth. And I had one really evil thought:
Someone (such as Bob), could sit at an airport. We all do this it isn’t difficult. He could then turn on his laptop and connect it the airport wireless. Another task, difficult for some, but lets go with Bob being able to.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Crazed Bovine Traversal in RL</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/200893crazed-bovine-traversal-in-rl-html/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 18:13:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/200893crazed-bovine-traversal-in-rl-html/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[As you may have heard me rant and rave about a special USB stick that downloads contact, messaging, and other information from phones just by plugging them in on Episode 5 of Securabit or read about it via an earlier posting on my blog (Crazed Bovine Traversal). A company called Paraben Corporation went out and made it (Motorola and Samsung support only so far)
I first learned about it via CNet’s report “CSI Stick grabs data from cell phones” and you can find it directly on http://csistick.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Multi-Boot Security LiveCD DVD</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008827multi-boot-security-livecd-dvd-html/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2008 03:40:34 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008827multi-boot-security-livecd-dvd-html/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[**EDIT: I got to talk about this DVD on the latest episode of **Securabit** (**Episode 9)
Edit 2: There is a cool new Live DVD by the guys at Sun Tzu Data. (Click here for post)
NERV-LABS subsidiary Badfoo.net has released quite the awesome DVD. Now, the lucky few of you who have suffered through my constant microsoft-bashing linux evangelism alright have heard about all the Multiboot LiveDVDs out there. Until now, they have all been booting various generic Linux distro.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>DEFCON 16: The Tools not the Toools</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008824defcon-16-the-tools-not-the-toools-html/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2008 22:12:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008824defcon-16-the-tools-not-the-toools-html/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Originally posted to the Zero Day blog on Ziff Davis: http://blogs.zdnet.com/security/?p=1735
This article was also referenced in a Dark Reading blog post by John Sawyer: http://www.darkreading.com/blog.asp?blog_sectionid=447&amp;doc_id=162049
All updates will reside here as I have no control over the article on Ziff Davis.
DEFCON, the 9000+ attendee hacker conference in Vegas has become a sort of hydra conference. It has become more like a global fair than what most people think of conferences; even the badge is highly unique.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Defcon presents come early!</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/200886defcon-presents-come-early-html/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2008 16:18:57 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/200886defcon-presents-come-early-html/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[So, just monitoring twitter for Defcon tweets and came across this one: Matthewneely status update 878833018
Screencap:
Link to video: HERE
So what is cool about this tool? It generates an SQL injection that skirts the 64k size limit using MS Debugger on the victim end.
And of course the DEFCON 16 via Wired Mag (Artcile)]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>ATT partially patched. Yay!</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008729att-partially-patched-yay-html/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2008 19:58:35 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008729att-partially-patched-yay-html/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[So, according to my iPhone, the DNS servers that it uses is patched. (209.183.33.23 - schinetdns.mycingular.net) However, when I tried to send an image of the doxpara page through email it gave me an SSL error and asked me to accept the certificate&hellip;. Um, no thank you. So, for the time being I will not be checking my email for a while, or for that matter anything I need to authenticate with.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>iPhone &#43; ATT &#43; DNS = Bad Juju</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008722iphone-att-dns-bad-juju-html/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 14:00:09 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008722iphone-att-dns-bad-juju-html/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[So, now that your feed reader is full up of all the DNS problems, I would like to present you with one more tidbit. How many of you have checked your iPhone, Blackberry, or other web enabled mobile device against this vulnerability? I did, and wasn’t happy.
For more information please check out these links:
In depth explination: http://www.mcgrewsecurity.com/?p=151
To check to see if you are vulnerable: http://www.doxpara.com/
http://www.mckeay.net/2008/07/21/patch-dns-now/
http://www.matasano.com/log/mtso/]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>CBT Response</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008629cbt-response-html/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2008 18:24:36 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008629cbt-response-html/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Since I wasn’t able to catch the commenter before they went offline I will leave it anonymous but they make a good point about my Crazed Bovine Traversal post:
In response to your “Crazed Bovine Traversal” blog post, a ringtone virus would likely depend upon some sort of code execution bug in the audio parsing code of the mobile device. Propagation could simply be done via text messaging or web site.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Distributed Honeypot Project</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008623distributed-honeypot-project-html/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2008 14:24:16 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008623distributed-honeypot-project-html/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[So I had another one of my harebrained ideas and it goes something like this:
Do you use your “DMZ” feature on your router at home? If you do, you shouldn’t. It’s like putting your computer directly on the net. Bad idea all around. Well, instead of having all those packets hit a brick wall, why not put them to good use?
So, create a Virtual Machine that you have running on your system and point your DMZ switch at.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Crazed Bovine Traversal</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008617crazed-bovine-traversal-html/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2008 13:17:16 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008617crazed-bovine-traversal-html/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[So I was at a ‘talk’ recently where the topic was geared toward technically inclined, but the whole talk was geared toward managers and low level IT bubbas, if you will. But as I sat there stabbing myself in the eye with my pencil (hence the mad cow reference) I can up with some hair brained ideas. Now, some of these ideas might already be out there or thought of, and I haven’t googled any of them, just wanted to write them down somewhere for people to comment on.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
