<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iphone on Malicious Link</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/categories/iphone/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iphone on Malicious Link</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 04:30:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://malicious.link/categories/iphone/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Jailbreak SSH horrors strike back</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2010/2010-08-04-jailbreak-ssh-horrors-strike-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 04:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2010/2010-08-04-jailbreak-ssh-horrors-strike-back/</guid>
      <description>Back in 2009 the &amp;ldquo;ikee&amp;rdquo; rick-rolling worm went around the iPhone world via the password of &amp;lsquo;alpine&amp;rsquo; on the root account. You are now warned to change your root password when you pop into Cydia and Rock the first time. But this thing just wont stay down.
If you have jailbroken your iPad you might want to check out a little file called &amp;ldquo;master.passwd&amp;rdquo;. In it, there is another user called &amp;lsquo;mobile&amp;rsquo; which has been pointed out since 2008 (here) on the iPhone as another account to change the password of.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get off my lawn! iPhone Geo Blocking</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2010/2010-06-25-get-off-my-lawn-iphone-geo-blocking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jun 2010 11:31:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2010/2010-06-25-get-off-my-lawn-iphone-geo-blocking/</guid>
      <description>I was recently approached by savant, who told me that a bunch of my Twitpics had geo location in them. Larry Pesce from PaulDotCom has been doing research in this field for a while and each time he brings it up I casually checked a couple of my twitpics and came up empty handed.
But, he gave me exact references, so I went to Twitpic to check them out for myself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My iPhone runs Windows</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-02-23-my-iphone-runs-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 22:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-02-23-my-iphone-runs-windows/</guid>
      <description>(This is the 3rd time I am writing this post, FF Fail, then Word crashed, so please excuse the lack of passion)
The moment that PDANet published that they released an updated version that allows USB tethering, I ran home and “QuickPWNd” my phone (which took all 5 minutes). Loaded the app and now I had the coveted TETHERING. I was free of my bind to Comcast or Free Public Wifi.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>