<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Payloads on Malicious Link</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/categories/payloads/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Payloads on Malicious Link</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2011 07:49:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://malicious.link/categories/payloads/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Metasploit Payloads Explained - Part 1b</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-07-17-metasploit-payloads-explained-part-1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2011 07:49:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-07-17-metasploit-payloads-explained-part-1b/</guid>
      <description>This series was interrupted a bit by the new Metasploit HTTP/HTTPS payloads (more info). Definitely not complaining though as the new features *(as will be discussed in part 2) are some epic new additions to the payloads list. However an important change happened while the craziness over the new payloads was going on. ScriptJunkie snuck in an awesome change to msfvenom (a.k.a. msffsm).
Here is the link to the ticket about the change (link) and the revision (r13057)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metasploit Payloads Explained - Part 1a</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-06-26-metasploit-payloads-explained-part-1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 17:47:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-06-26-metasploit-payloads-explained-part-1a/</guid>
      <description>In Part 1 I gave an example I used at CCDC with the single &amp;lsquo;windows/download_exec&amp;rsquo;. One of the down sides of that payload is you need to host the binary, giving up an IP/host that can be blocked. Well, Google recently (a couple months ago) allowed people to upload &amp;lsquo;anything&amp;rsquo; to Google docs. And you can then share these files publicly. Probably already see where I&amp;rsquo;m going with this, but here are some steps to get it going, first upload your malicious binary (not the dropper &amp;lsquo;windows/download_exec&amp;rsquo;, but the file it needs to execute).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metasploit Payloads Explained - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-06-26-metasploit-payloads-explained-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jun 2011 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-06-26-metasploit-payloads-explained-part-1/</guid>
      <description>Payload selection is something that rarely gets talked about in detail. Most PoCs just use calc.exe, netcat, or some kind of socket. The vast majority of Metasploit tutorials, videos and documentation use the _windows/meterpreter/reverse_tcp_ payload which is only one of 224 possible payloads. Here is a little disclaimer: While the payloads in Metasploit don&amp;rsquo;t get updated as much as other parts of Metasploit, this is a point in time documentation of them (June 23, 2011) and the payloads available in Metasploit are constantly changing.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>