<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wishlist on Room362</title>
    <link>https://room362.com/categories/wishlist/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wishlist on Room362</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2009 17:00:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://room362.com/categories/wishlist/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2009 Geek Christmas List</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2009/2009-12-03-2009-geek-christmas-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2009 17:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2009/2009-12-03-2009-geek-christmas-list/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s on your list? Here is mine (in no particular order):
Number 1: iPhone compatible alarm clock with good sound
Number 2: iPhone car mount that charges and is compatible with aux cables
 32GB E-flash (esata, USB2.0) Drobo 4 bay backup solution The Tauntaun Sleeping Bag Griffin PowerMate Kindle DX or Barnes and Noble Nook Nokia N900 Roku HD-XR This Tesla or this one Canon EOS Rebel T1i Popcorn Hour Device (trumps the Roku) Logitech MX Revolution Logitech Harmony One The Art of Software Security Assessment by Mark Dowd Windows Internals 5 by Mark Russinovich and David Solomon Wi-Spy 2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Tools I&#39;m Looking For Part I</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2009/2009-06-17-security-tools-im-looking-for-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2009 15:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2009/2009-06-17-security-tools-im-looking-for-part-i/</guid>
      <description>There are a lot of tools that I find in my endeavors would be really helpful, but can’t find on the net for whatever reason.
 A portable version of of tshark that has ARP spoofing capabilities. I want to be able to drop the file, issue the arguments and pull the pcap back.
 A application that can sniff traffic from a specific process. Metasploit’s keylogger is sort of there as it only pulls keys from the process of which it is attached (DLL is to ‘fault’ for this).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthday Wishes</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2006/2006-07-17-birthday-wishes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2006 15:20:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2006/2006-07-17-birthday-wishes/</guid>
      <description>I have decided this year, for my birthday, to create a list of so-called “WANTS”. I prefer to see them as “NEEDS”. I have intentionally created this list large, as to give the most choices when selecting a gift. I have also tried to provide links to where these items can be bought online for the least amount of money. I have intentionally left prices out of this, and the list is unordered.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>