<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Traning on malicious.link</title>
    <link>/categories/traning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Traning on malicious.link</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 15:18:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/categories/traning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Offensive Security Live Courses for 2009</title>
      <link>/post/2009/2009-04-29-offensive-security-live-courses-for-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2009 15:18:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009/2009-04-29-offensive-security-live-courses-for-2009/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I highly recommend both of these courses, and the chance to get in front of the instructors and ask questions live is worth it IMHO. So bang on those manager doors and work it out, because seats fill quickly and they are limited. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Check out the &lt;strong&gt;[&lt;/strong&gt;Offensive Security - Instructor Lead Training&lt;strong&gt;](&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.offensive-security.com/ilt.php&#34;&gt;http://www.offensive-security.com/ilt.php&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt; page for updated information.**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;We are excited to announce our next Offsec Live Classes.  
  
Since you asked to be notified of our next dates you will be happy to be among the first to have your teams invited to one of our next classes.  
  
Our last classes sold out about 2 months early and this class there are literally hundreds in the queue so please contact me as early as you can.  

------------------------------------------------------
Pentesting With BackTrack Live  
October 26-30, 2009  
Columbia, MD  
  
Costs:  
$3500 now till July 15th  
$3799 July 15th – September 1st  
$3999 September 1st till class  
  
Your class will include the following:  
·         5 days of intense training from Mati Aharoni and Chris Hadnagy  
·         30 days of labs in our special Pentesting with BackTrack Labs  
·         Your chance to take the highly regarded OSCP Certification  
·         We also cover your lunch during the week  
·         We host a special after hours session for those who want to join in  
  
This class is designed to take you from A to Z in real life pentesting skills.  We cover from Information Gathering to writing your own overflow.  
  
We ask each student to have a clear understanding of TCP/IP, basic linux skills and familiarity with the concepts of pentesting.  

------------------------------------------------------
Offensive Security Cracking the Perimeter Live  
November 9-13, 2009
Columbia, MD  
  
Costs:  
$5000 now till July 30th  
$5299 July 30th – October 1st  
$5499 October 1st till class  
  
Your class will include the following:  
·         5 days of intense training from Mati Aharoni and Chris Hadnagy  
·         30 days of labs in our special Cracking the Perimeter Labs  
·         Your chance to take the prestigious OSCE Certification  
·         We also cover your lunch during the week  
  
This class is designed for the seasoned security professional - A pentester or sec pro that has taken their skills to the edge and now need a little push over – to learn insane ways to crack the perimeter.  
  
This class relies heavily on the student knowing and using Olly Debugger, the Metasploit framework and understanding if not having written an full blown exploit before attempting this class.  If you have taken the “Pentesting With BT” class and mastered all aspects of this class you might be ready to take Cracking the Perimeter.  
  
All attendees are eligible for 40 CPE credits if you are CISSP.  
  
We are limiting these classes to a maximum of 20 for Pentesting with BackTrack and 15-17 for Cracking the Perimeter -  so if you are interested please contact us early and register completely to ensure your seat is saved.  
  
Thanks and I look forward to seeing you in class.  
  
Sincerely,  
  
Chris Hadnagy  
Operations Manager  
[www.offensive-security.com](http://www.offensive-security.com)  
[www.remote-exploit.org](http://www.remote-exploit.org)  
“back|track4 – So good it should be commercial”
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
