<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hak.5 on Room362</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/hak/index.5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hak.5 on Room362</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2009 22:30:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/hak.5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>OzymanDNS - Tunneling SSH over DNS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009310ozymandns-tunneling-ssh-over-dns-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2009 22:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009310ozymandns-tunneling-ssh-over-dns-html/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;hak5-episode-504-shownotes-http-www-hak5-org-episodes-episode-504:00c71f585c0a5a8e6a10fd11b10f754f&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hak5.org/episodes/episode-504&#34;&gt;Hak5 Episode 504 Shownotes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(In the episode I say that it&amp;rsquo;s cross platform, use the release links for the Windows binaries to get it working on windows or use cygwin)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;disclaimer-i-in-no-way-endorse-illegal-activities-use-the-following-guide-in-a-test-environment-or-at-your-own-legal-risk:00c71f585c0a5a8e6a10fd11b10f754f&#34;&gt;DISCLAIMER - I IN NO WAY ENDORSE ILLEGAL ACTIVITIES - USE THE FOLLOWING GUIDE IN A TEST ENVIRONMENT OR AT YOUR OWN LEGAL RISK.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;update-thanks-to-chris-gates-http-carnal0wnage-blogspot-com-and-robin-wood-http-www-digininja-org-index-php-for-pointing-me-towards-a-fixed-up-version-of-ozymandns-and-a-great-tutorial-here-http-www-splitbrain-org-blog-2008-11-02-dns-tunneling-made-simple:00c71f585c0a5a8e6a10fd11b10f754f&#34;&gt;UPDATE:Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://carnal0wnage.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Chris Gates&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digininja.org/index.php&#34;&gt;Robin Wood&lt;/a&gt; for pointing me towards a fixed up version of OzymanDNS and a great tutorial: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.splitbrain.org/blog/2008-11/02-dns_tunneling_made_simple&#34;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;update2-since-ozyman-is-no-longer-hosted-on-dan-s-site-i-have-posted-it-here:00c71f585c0a5a8e6a10fd11b10f754f&#34;&gt;UPDATE2: Since Ozyman is no longer hosted on Dan&amp;rsquo;s site, I have posted it here:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/scripts-and-programs/stolen/ozymandns_src_0.1.tgz&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;http://www.room362.com/scripts-and-programs/stolen/ozymandns_src_0.1.tgz&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;(Until of course/if he asks me to take it down)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DNS Tunneling isn&amp;rsquo;t new. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.doxpara.com/&#34;&gt;Dan Kaminsky&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s post for &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.doxpara.com/?p=51&#34;&gt;OzymanDNS&amp;rsquo; release&lt;/a&gt; was July 29th 2004 (There was DNS Tunneling linux packages dating back to the late 90s even). I will however comment that it&amp;rsquo;s still in it&amp;rsquo;s release version, but very functional. Also, DNS Tunnel isn&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;Big News&amp;rdquo; so it really hasn&amp;rsquo;t been &amp;lsquo;mitigated&amp;rsquo; anywhere yet. Everywhere I have tested it, it has worked, even behind a certain switch that rhymes with &amp;lsquo;Panera&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does OzymanDNS do? It has two parts, server, and client. The server is a set and forget. It sits there waiting for a connection (caveat: from anywhere) But we are getting ahead of ourselves, lets setup up DNS first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I&amp;rsquo;m going to assume that you have a SSH server somewhere that you have already setup)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-1-dns-setup:00c71f585c0a5a8e6a10fd11b10f754f&#34;&gt;Step 1 - DNS Setup:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each &amp;ldquo;Domain Manager&amp;rdquo; or DNS Server has a different set up,  So I&amp;rsquo;m not going to go into the details. The jist of the change you need to make is either make a domain or a subdomain that points it&amp;rsquo;s nameserver records towards the host that you are running your server on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ihaztunnel.room362.com IN NS mubixpwnsyour.homedns.org&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this example we have setup a subdomain called &amp;ldquo;ihaztunnel&amp;rdquo; and set it&amp;rsquo;s Name Server Record pointing to a dynamic dns host that points at the location of my OzymanDNS server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-2-server-setup:00c71f585c0a5a8e6a10fd11b10f754f&#34;&gt;Step 2 - Server Setup:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You need &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.perl.org/&#34;&gt;Perl&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.cpan.org/~danpeder/MIME-Base32-1.01/Base32.pm&#34;&gt;MIME::Base32&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://search.cpan.org/~olaf/Net-DNS-0.65/lib/Net/DNS.pm&#34;&gt;Net::DNS&lt;/a&gt; modules. After that you just run nomde.pl from whatever directory that you extracted the OzymanDNS scripts with the following context:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;./nomed.pl -i 0.0.0.0 ihaztunnel.room362.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tells it to listen on any IP the host has (you can specifiy one if you wish), and tells it the DNS name that it&amp;rsquo;s supporting. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget to do port forwarding on your router or whatever may be in the way of port 53 UDP and TCP coming inbound. Also keep in mind that your ISP may be blocking, so field test the connection before you try to use it in the wild.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;step-3-client-connection:00c71f585c0a5a8e6a10fd11b10f754f&#34;&gt;Step 3 - Client Connection:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the client, the setup is the same, get perl, the modules and OzymanDNS. Then you run the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ssh -D 8080 -C -o ProxyCommand=&amp;ldquo;/home/mubix/ozymandns/droute.pl whatever.ihaztunnel.room362.com&amp;rdquo; room362.com&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Breaking this command down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;-D 8080&amp;rdquo; starts SSH tunneling (Socks Proxy) on port 8080 once a connection is made.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;-C&amp;rdquo; requests compression so that we can get the best speeds possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;rdquo;-o ProxyCommand&amp;rdquo; sets the SSH option to the location of the droute.pl script and&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;whatever.ihaztunnel.room362.com&amp;rdquo; the &amp;lsquo;whatever&amp;rsquo; portion of this is the important part. It can be whatever you want it to be but the &amp;ldquo;magic&amp;rdquo; happens by adding this subdomain of the one you already set up.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;room362.com&amp;rdquo; the hostname or IP of the SSH server that you will be tunneling through.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If all worked out, you will get prompted to enter your password. That&amp;rsquo;s it folks. Now you can use FoxyProxy or just your standard proxy settings to use the tunnel. Or, you can use product that, IMHO, is well worth the 30 bucks for the PORTABLE EDITION: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.proxifier.com/&#34;&gt;Proxifier&lt;/a&gt;. It hooks the OS and makes every connection go through the proxy (games, IM, Java, Flash).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before you go the DNS route&lt;/strong&gt;, it might pay off to try the ?.jpg trick first. Check out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://debuggable.com/posts/hacking-a-commercial-airport-wlan:480f4dd5-50a0-40c6-aa60-4afccbdd56cb&#34;&gt;debuggable.com post&lt;/a&gt; for more details. - Thanks Xanfantasy for the memory jog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dnstunnel.de/&#34;&gt;http://www.dnstunnel.de/&lt;/a&gt; - A site that has an in-depth walk-through of setting up OzymanDNS if I didn&amp;rsquo;t answer all of your questions. They even have a script that will make OzymanDNS a service on Linux boxes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://thomer.com/howtos/nstx.html&#34;&gt;http://thomer.com/howtos/nstx.html&lt;/a&gt; - A write up on NSTX which doesn&amp;rsquo;t require SSH but doesn&amp;rsquo;t look like it&amp;rsquo;s still  in production. It is however in the Ubuntu and Gentoo repositories so feel free to mess with it there, and since &lt;a href=&#34;http://backtrack4.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Back|Track 4&lt;/a&gt; is now Ubuntu based you may be able to get it set up on BT4 as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iodine:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://code.kryo.se/iodine/&#34;&gt;http://code.kryo.se/iodine/&lt;/a&gt; - Another DNS Tunneling project that looks to be the most up to date. I haven&amp;rsquo;t tested it out to make sure it functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dns2tcp:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hsc.fr/ressources/outils/dns2tcp/index.html.en&#34;&gt;http://www.hsc.fr/ressources/outils/dns2tcp/index.html.en&lt;/a&gt; - Another DNS Tunneling Project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if DNS isn&amp;rsquo;t your thing and you want to tunnel over HTTP, check out Corkscrew:  &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.agroman.net/corkscrew/&#34;&gt;http://www.agroman.net/corkscrew/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maltego 2 and beyond - Part 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/200898maltego-2-and-beyond-part-1-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2008 05:09:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/200898maltego-2-and-beyond-part-1-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First lets outline whats to come:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Table of Contents:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Part 1 - Introduction&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/archives/229-Maltego-2-and-beyond-Part-2.html&#34;&gt;Part 2 - Entities and Transforms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313/archives/266-Maltego-2-and-beyond-Part-3.html&#34;&gt;Part 3 - The Human Factor&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Part 4 - Server Time (CTAS, PTTAS, MALTAS, SQLTAS, SNTAS)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Part 5 - Hacks, Tips, and Tricks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;**EDIT: This and the following posts are also show notes for the **&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hak5.org/episodes/episode-401-wi-fi-pineapples&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Season 4 premiere&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;** of **&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hak5.org/&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hak5&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So Maltego 2 has been released and all I have to show for it are these images stolen from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paterva.com/maltego/screenshots/&#34;&gt;paterva.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://s3.media.squarespace.com/production/438411/4879756/uploads/maltego_ss1.serendipityThumb.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://s3.media.squarespace.com/production/438411/4879756/uploads/maltego_ss1.serendipityThumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;a href=&#34;http://s3.media.squarespace.com/production/438411/4879756/uploads/maltego_ss2.serendipityThumb.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://s3.media.squarespace.com/production/438411/4879756/uploads/maltego_ss2.serendipityThumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and a bit of an explination also stolen from their site:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://s3.media.squarespace.com/production/438411/4879756/uploads/maltego_whatis.serendipityThumb.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://s3.media.squarespace.com/production/438411/4879756/uploads/maltego_whatis.serendipityThumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But you aren’t here for what you can find on their site. You are here to find out why Maltego is fun, useful, and something you might want to recommend your boss/secretary/parents to buy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maltego is hard define because of it’s open nature. It is designed to be whatever that information gatherer wants it to be. But before we go into Maltego’s super powers, lets define the differences between it’s two versions, Full and Community editions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Full is just as it implies. Unfettered. You can make it fly. But it’s 400 bucks a year per client. (Or your organization can talk straight to Paterva about their server/client platform)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Community Edition is free, but you are locked down quite a bit. Community Edition is bundled with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.remote-exploit.org/backtrack.html&#34;&gt;Back|Track 3&lt;/a&gt; which is don’t by the awesome guys over at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.offensive-security.com/&#34;&gt;Offensive Security&lt;/a&gt;. Here are the nags:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt; A 15second nag screen&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Save and Export has been disabled&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Limited zoom levels&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Can only run transforms on a single entity at a time&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cannot copy and paste text from detailed view&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Transforms limited to 75 per day&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Throttled client to TAS communication&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you do have one full version client, you can open saved investigations (mtg files) with it and manipulate it all you want. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that is just one of my tricks and now that we have a baseline down (kinda like getting done with all of your base classes in college), in the following segments of this post I will be showing of some of the electrolyte driven goodness of Maltego and some of the hacks/tricks that will make you look wonder just what you can’t do with Maltego.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hak.5 Radio goes legit</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2006/2006913hak5-radio-goes-legit-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2006 10:09:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2006/2006913hak5-radio-goes-legit-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, Hak.5 Radio is really taking off! We are now certified free and clear, you can check it out below. Just wanted to make a quick quip, more later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;http://nowplaying.loudcity.net/?stationid=864&#34; scrolling=&#34;no&#34; width=&#34;375&#34; height=&#34;225&#34;&lt;/iframe&gt;  
  

&lt;p&gt;psst - however, as you can plainly see, this is far from LIVE data&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jd&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VPN Hacking Game</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2005/20051214vpn-hacking-game-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2005 23:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2005/20051214vpn-hacking-game-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have created this post to invite all who read this (all 5 of ya, yes, I know your IPs by heart) to a game that was initiated out of a forum thread on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hak5.tv/forums/viewtopic.php?t=433&#34;&gt; the Hak.5 Forums&lt;/a&gt;. If you would like to join the game, by you commenting on this post you are accepting an agreement that ANYTHING that happens across this VPN is not my or any of the participants fault. You are also authorizing yourself to be a target. HOWEVER, the rules of this game are that of the WHITE HAT. You are not allowed to destroy ANYTHING on ANY computer on the VPN unless explicitly announced. Also, if there is a complaint, a valid complaint against you for not adhering to these rules, you certificate will be revoked and you will no longer be able to participate. I will be the final judge on wither or not a complaint is valid or not. I will be recording ALL traffic across the VPN. Yes, I do have enough space. If you agree to these rules, please add the comment of “I AGREE” , your handle, and include your email address in a human legible way. When the game begins I will email out each individual certificate. Further rules will be set once an initial panel of judges is formed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to be a judge. There will be 2 spots. Email me for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>