<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>beautifulbasics - Tag - Malicious Link - Blog by mubix - Rob Fuller</title>
        <link>https://malicious.link/tags/beautifulbasics/</link>
        <description>beautifulbasics - Tag - Malicious Link - Blog by mubix - Rob Fuller</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>mubix@hak5.org (Rob Fuller)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>mubix@hak5.org (Rob Fuller)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 04:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://malicious.link/tags/beautifulbasics/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Beautiful Basics: Lesson 4</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-04/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 04:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Rob Fuller</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-04/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Lesson 4 - User Blaming Security is NOT everyone&rsquo;s job in the company. Stop trying to force the issue. It&rsquo;s security&rsquo;s job to enable, incentivize and protect.
In the Marine Corps, I was taught that every Marine is a &ldquo;Rifleman&rdquo;, meaning that any Marine, no matter their MOS (Military Occupational Specialty) - aka their job, could be called upon to engage with the enemy using a rifle or other weapon.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Beautiful Basics: Lesson 3</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-03/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 03:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Rob Fuller</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-03/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Lesson 3 - Detection Reality People and Honey tokens are THE BEST detective tool you have.
Go buy a Thinkst Canary, they detect me more than any multi-million dollar EDR. Period.
Let me clarify something quickly before I get roasted. I am not saying that EDR (Endpoint Detection and Response) agents don&rsquo;t have a place, it&rsquo;s just that they have taken over for Anti-Virus for being mostly preventative and response oriented.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Beautiful Basics: Lesson 2</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-02/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Rob Fuller</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-02/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Lesson 2 - Least Privilege No one should have administrative access. All elevated access should be checked out when you need it and checked back in (automatically if possible). Just like UAC. MFA should be required, proximity or push based. And every use of a break glass account should be highly monitored
I think &ldquo;Least Privilege&rdquo; has been harped on at least &hellip; you know what, let me wager that you can&rsquo;t find a single infosec or hacking conference from 2000 until now (2022) that doesn&rsquo;t have 4 talks with the words &ldquo;least privilege&rdquo; in the talk.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Beautiful Basics: Lesson 1</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-01/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Rob Fuller</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-01/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Lesson 1 - YOU could be &ldquo;Legacy&rdquo; Stop thinking that just because it did or didn’t work X way when you learned it, it still does or doesn&rsquo;t. That could be 20 years ago. Technology changes faster than you do.
I guess that&rsquo;s a bit mean for a title but here&rsquo;s the thing:
One of the greatest yet most challenging things about doing any job in technology is staying current.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Beautiful Basics - Series</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2022/beautiful-basics/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Rob Fuller</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2022/beautiful-basics/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Today I keynoted @BSidesVancouver. It was an honor to be asked and I had a great time.
Conference Link: https://hopin.com/events/bsides-vancouver-2022/
I talked about 11 lessons learned over my career that contradict some of the edicts that are well known in the Cyber Security space.
Before we get into the lessons though, let me attack the things I know many of you reading this already have queued up in your head.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
