<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>beautifulbasics on malicious.link</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/tags/beautifulbasics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in beautifulbasics on malicious.link</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 04:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://malicious.link/tags/beautifulbasics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful Basics: Lesson 4</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 04:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-04/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lessons-learned&#34;&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-01&#34;&gt;Lesson 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-02&#34;&gt;Lesson 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-03&#34;&gt;Lesson 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-04&#34;&gt;Lesson 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-05&#34;&gt;Lesson 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-06&#34;&gt;Lesson 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-07&#34;&gt;Lesson 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-08&#34;&gt;Lesson 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-09&#34;&gt;Lesson 9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-10&#34;&gt;Lesson 10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-11&#34;&gt;Lesson 11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;lesson-4---user-blaming&#34;&gt;Lesson 4 - User Blaming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security &lt;strong&gt;is NOT&lt;/strong&gt; everyone&amp;rsquo;s job in the company. Stop trying to force the issue. It&amp;rsquo;s security&amp;rsquo;s job to enable, incentivize and protect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/2022/beautifulbasics_lesson4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the Marine Corps, I was taught that every Marine is a &amp;ldquo;Rifleman&amp;rdquo;, meaning that any Marine, no matter their MOS (Military Occupational Specialty) - aka their job, could be called upon to engage with the enemy using a rifle or other weapon. This meant that every Marine must be trained, and regularly re-trained/tested, to ensure their proficiency with a rifle. Other branches have similar stances or sayings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe the mindset that every person in a company has a stake in it&amp;rsquo;s cyber security came from veterans. That or it came from the realm of safety, which I 100% support. Safety is everyone&amp;rsquo;s responsibility. Now is where some of you are equating cyber security with safety, and yes, they do sometimes overlap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, in most cases, cyber security has nothing to do with the safety of a corporations personnel, customers, or it&amp;rsquo;s community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what am I saying? 3 things:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stop blaming users for clicking on links, or opening macro enabled documents, or inserting USB sticks with viruses on them. We need to get to a place in security where it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if they do those things. We need to do better and stop making excuses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security awareness training is usually overly complicated, outdated, or has very little other use. I think those teams are better served by running a security incentivize program. What does this look like? Basically a gamification of security asks.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start a points program at your company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give points away for reporting phishing emails or security infractions like tailgaiting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give points monthly for use of a password manager&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take away points based on security infractions (infected laptop, clicking a phishing email)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give points monthly of good password use.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Give points for early adoption / beta testing of security programs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow points to be spent on gift cards, dinners with the CISO / CEO / CTO, or live events like tickets to concerts or plays.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change how the security organization talks within and outside the organization about partners in IT, developers and users in general. Managers need to crack down on this type of negative talk because it can be easily felt on calls with those groups.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Number 3 is super important. If you allow people to talk negatively about another group in your company it will quickly become the law of the land, and will decrease motivation to find equitable solutions or even have equitable conversations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, we, the security community and vendors have to do a better job at solving problems and rejecting solutions that just perpetuate the status quo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;slides&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vQWsIcPGnJ60ROVu3K32uI7Gtg7zciUle7hfZnN5HPrJ1mD38LZWT5x5DQOyd5CpLXt0hL125fKqOQL/embed?start=false&amp;loop=true&amp;delayms=15000&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; width=&#34;960&#34; height=&#34;569&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;video&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9yv6SdDtU-Q&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful Basics: Lesson 3</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 May 2022 03:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-03/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lessons-learned&#34;&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-01&#34;&gt;Lesson 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-02&#34;&gt;Lesson 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-03&#34;&gt;Lesson 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-04&#34;&gt;Lesson 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-05&#34;&gt;Lesson 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-06&#34;&gt;Lesson 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-07&#34;&gt;Lesson 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-08&#34;&gt;Lesson 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-09&#34;&gt;Lesson 9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-10&#34;&gt;Lesson 10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-11&#34;&gt;Lesson 11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;lesson-3---detection-reality&#34;&gt;Lesson 3 - Detection Reality&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People and Honey tokens are THE BEST detective tool you have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Go buy a &lt;a href=&#34;https://thinkst.com/&#34;&gt;Thinkst Canary&lt;/a&gt;, they detect me more than any multi-million dollar EDR. Period.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/2022/beautifulbasics_lesson3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let me clarify something quickly before I get roasted. I am not saying that EDR (Endpoint Detection and Response) agents don&amp;rsquo;t have a place, it&amp;rsquo;s just that they have taken over for Anti-Virus for being mostly preventative and response oriented. Do EDRs detect things? Sure, but in my pentesting and red teaming experience they rarely catch any of the actions I do outside of touching LSASS. Which to be fair, is what a lot of malware and APT actors do. But it won&amp;rsquo;t stay that way, and Sysmon is free :P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One more clarifying statement. I have no affiliation to &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ThinkstCanary&#34;&gt;Thinkst&lt;/a&gt; other than knowing &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/haroonmeer&#34;&gt;Haroon Meer&lt;/a&gt; through Twitter and meeting him once or twice in person, super amazing dude, I think the world of him. I truly think the Canary as a concept is one of the best detective tools we have. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have fake accounts, computers, and configurations that look vulnerable mixed in with your population of systems you are missing out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally lets get to the meat of this lesson. Back in 2018 I made this statement:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;Dear %Companies%, A single security minded Sys Admin is worth more than a handful of pentesters. Please start investing in the admins you already have. I say this as a pentester who has seen the impact that an empowered admin can have.&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Rob Fuller (@mubix) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mubix/status/1007296914742759424?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&#34;&gt;June 14, 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;System administrators usually know their systems very well. With the move to DevOps, I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if that is decreasing because systems are more transitory or the monitoring systems have kept pace or improved because of it. But, as a pentester / red teamer I have been caught more times by system administrators than any tool security operations has put in place. I did a talk back in 2014 called &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VqcDjPUXPIw&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Attacker Ghost Stories&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; [&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.slideshare.net/hashdays/attacker-ghost-stories-v8&#34;&gt;slides&lt;/a&gt;] about exactly this and all of the ways system administrators put tricks and traps in place to catch attackers like me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What are these tricks? Just to name a few:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trap&lt;/strong&gt;: Create a domain administrator that has logon hours all turned off with alerting on any attempt to logon with that user not just sent to an alert or a log server but to PagerDuty. This user had the current, real password in the description. No one should EVER use this account.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefit&lt;/strong&gt;: It&amp;rsquo;s too hard to pass up and logon hours aren&amp;rsquo;t commonly looked at by attackers in the attributes for a user, so not only will the attack fail, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a near instant, high fidelity alert of malicious actions on your network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alternatives&lt;/strong&gt;: Have an account that is Kerberoastable with a very weak password that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have permission to logon anywhere (you can do this by assigning the user to a computer account that no longer exists). Less risk an attacker will find a way to use the account and still a high fidelity alert (just not as juicy of bait)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trap&lt;/strong&gt;: A fake login portal that looks like it is a corporate VPN or OWA server, this is a very easy way to identify credentials that had already been stolen some other way from your organization.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Benefit&lt;/strong&gt;: An attacker will attempt to validate credentials they have stolen other ways.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is just two ideas. Go look at the slides for more, or check out OpenCanary - &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/thinkst/opencanary&#34;&gt;https://github.com/thinkst/opencanary&lt;/a&gt; - it&amp;rsquo;s an open source version that you can start to play with along with Canary Tokens if you want even less setup - &lt;a href=&#34;https://canarytokens.org/generate&#34;&gt;https://canarytokens.org/generate&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t have to use any of the Thinkst tools, for that matter you don&amp;rsquo;t need any of the new &amp;ldquo;Deception&amp;rdquo; vendors (** **barf** **) out there. Just sprinkle your network with bait of all kinds (ask your pentester, or look at what your last pentest report &amp;ldquo;found&amp;rdquo; as their steps) and make fake things. It&amp;rsquo;s set-it-and-forget-it. Way easier than implementing 500 security vendors to catch bad in every way possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;slides&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vQWsIcPGnJ60ROVu3K32uI7Gtg7zciUle7hfZnN5HPrJ1mD38LZWT5x5DQOyd5CpLXt0hL125fKqOQL/embed?start=false&amp;loop=true&amp;delayms=15000&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; width=&#34;960&#34; height=&#34;569&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;video&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9yv6SdDtU-Q&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful Basics: Lesson 2</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-02/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-02/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lessons-learned&#34;&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-01&#34;&gt;Lesson 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-02&#34;&gt;Lesson 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-03&#34;&gt;Lesson 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-04&#34;&gt;Lesson 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-05&#34;&gt;Lesson 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-06&#34;&gt;Lesson 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-07&#34;&gt;Lesson 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-08&#34;&gt;Lesson 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-09&#34;&gt;Lesson 9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-10&#34;&gt;Lesson 10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-11&#34;&gt;Lesson 11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;lesson-2---least-privilege&#34;&gt;Lesson 2 - Least Privilege&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No one&lt;/strong&gt; should have administrative access. All elevated access should be &lt;strong&gt;checked out&lt;/strong&gt; when you need it and checked back in (automatically if possible). Just like UAC. MFA should be required, proximity or push based. And every use of a break glass account should be highly monitored&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/2022/beautifulbasics_lesson2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think &amp;ldquo;Least Privilege&amp;rdquo; has been harped on at least &amp;hellip; you know what, let me wager that you can&amp;rsquo;t find a single infosec or hacking conference from 2000 until now (2022) that doesn&amp;rsquo;t have 4 talks with the words &amp;ldquo;least privilege&amp;rdquo; in the talk. But maybe a handful out of all of those talks tell you how to accomplish such a feat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-goal&#34;&gt;The Goal&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lets talk about the goal first though, just-in-time administration. Identity and Access Management (IAM) has tried very hard to steal the &amp;ldquo;Just-In-Time&amp;rdquo; (JIT) terminology from the software development and reverse engineering world but I don&amp;rsquo;t think it has ever stuck. I do however completely agree with it&amp;rsquo;s concepts. JIT Privilege Access Management (JIT PAM, try to say that acronym in a meeting, probably won&amp;rsquo;t end well), is the concept where you get rid of all of the administrative accounts across your entire organization, replacing them with temporary (you only have access to the account for a short amount of time) and even sometimes transitory (the admin account gets deleted after use) administrative accounts. That&amp;rsquo;s the goal, where if you business closes down at 8 PM on a Friday, by 9 PM (for example), there isn&amp;rsquo;t a single administrative account left on your company network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-is-this-needed&#34;&gt;Why is this needed?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right now, in the organization that you work in, can an IT admin use their own administrative account to make a change to your systems or network? Of course, that&amp;rsquo;s their job. We definitely don&amp;rsquo;t want to hinder them from doing their job right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are the problems that this scenario faces:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The password for administrative accounts should be much more secure but many times it&amp;rsquo;s not, since it&amp;rsquo;s up to a human to select. They also have to type it in a large number of times a day so we don&amp;rsquo;t want to make it difficult to do so.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The time an administrative user&amp;rsquo;s password is valid for can be weeks, months, years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An administrative user can forget or simply not know the correct way to log out of sessions with administrative access (this is super common both on web applications and RDP)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Very rarely have I seen a network completely devoid of &amp;ldquo;old&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;forgotten&amp;rdquo; administrative users. This could be a lack of off-boarding process or just laziness but it&amp;rsquo;s pretty universal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where does the administrator write down which systems they are going to access or which actions they are going to perform?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Admins leave all kinds of scripts and saved passwords lying around on systems they only access for short periods of time. We all do this, if we didn&amp;rsquo;t then kiosks in hotels wouldn&amp;rsquo;t need to be wiped between use&amp;hellip; oh yea, they aren&amp;rsquo;t&amp;hellip; you get the point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I can use a vaulting product to take care of #1, #2, and possibly help with #4. I can use Active Directory GPOs to work on #2 and #3 possibly. But there is still no accountability around what actions are being performed or on what systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-do-we-get-there&#34;&gt;How do we get there?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start with pairing down and auditing the list of administrators. Starting with Domain Admins is easy. Narrow it down to just the people who actually truly need that much access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now make a generic Domain Admin accounts instead of the personalized ones and vault them. It&amp;rsquo;s ok if the admins each still use just one of those accounts. This is getting them used to the idea that these aren&amp;rsquo;t &amp;ldquo;their&amp;rdquo; accounts and they can&amp;rsquo;t just leave stuff on the desktop or saved passwords.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make MFA required to check out these generic accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable &amp;ldquo;reason&amp;rdquo; fields in your vaulting software (like Hashicorp Vault, CyberArk or Thycotic) and push those logs to your SEIM / logging platform (or better yet, into and admins chat channel that the IR team has access to as well)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make all profile customization (files on desktops, custom terminal sessions, etc) get deleted once the account is checked back in. (this will require roaming profiles or a way to manage it remotely)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now start doing that for each and every administrative group / accounts, cloud, network infrastructure, virtualization platforms, databases, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eventually you&amp;rsquo;ll get to a place where it&amp;rsquo;s normal for people to check out accounts and have it log why they are doing so, then &lt;strong&gt;everything access privilege that account has is revoked&lt;/strong&gt; and the password is automatically rotated and randomized. You can even get to the point where they have to specify the servers they need to access and it only gives them access to just those servers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;slides&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vQWsIcPGnJ60ROVu3K32uI7Gtg7zciUle7hfZnN5HPrJ1mD38LZWT5x5DQOyd5CpLXt0hL125fKqOQL/embed?start=false&amp;loop=true&amp;delayms=15000&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; width=&#34;960&#34; height=&#34;569&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;video&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9yv6SdDtU-Q&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful Basics: Lesson 1</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 01:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-01/</guid>
      <description>
&lt;h3 id=&#34;lessons-learned&#34;&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-01&#34;&gt;Lesson 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-02&#34;&gt;Lesson 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-03&#34;&gt;Lesson 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-04&#34;&gt;Lesson 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-05&#34;&gt;Lesson 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-06&#34;&gt;Lesson 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-07&#34;&gt;Lesson 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-08&#34;&gt;Lesson 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-09&#34;&gt;Lesson 9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-10&#34;&gt;Lesson 10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-11&#34;&gt;Lesson 11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;lesson-1---you-could-be-legacy&#34;&gt;Lesson 1 - YOU could be &amp;ldquo;Legacy&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop thinking that just because it did or didn’t work X way when you learned it, it still does or doesn&amp;rsquo;t. That could be 20 years ago. Technology changes faster than you do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/2022/beautifulbasics_lesson1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess that&amp;rsquo;s a bit mean for a title but here&amp;rsquo;s the thing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the greatest yet most challenging things about doing any job in technology is staying current. Everyone struggles to stay up to date with as much of what is going on around you. Many people specialize, which makes it easier to stay up to date with a specific thing. Yet that can lead to tunnel vision as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I&amp;rsquo;m trying to say here is that sometimes, the person with the least amount of &amp;ldquo;experience&amp;rdquo; in a given technology field is going to have the most open mind to what is possible. &lt;strong&gt;No matter how long you have been in cyber security or technology in general, you should consider your knowledge on a specific topic a point in time piece of information&lt;/strong&gt;. At that exact moment in your life, that fact was true. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that it stays that way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take passwords for example. Everyone said &amp;ldquo;8 character passwords are secure&amp;rdquo; for decades. I&amp;rsquo;m still hearing that. Or &amp;ldquo;never write your passwords down&amp;rdquo;. This is just one example. &amp;ldquo;Never use X software, it&amp;rsquo;s insecure&amp;rdquo;, is it still?. One of the ways I stay &amp;ldquo;current&amp;rdquo; is by always challenging my knowledge of how I think things should work vs how they do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is why during my keynote I noted when and where I leaned these lessons, there is every possibility I am complete off base with all of them. This is also why it&amp;rsquo;s my beautiful basics lesson #1. Something to always keep top of mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;slides&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vQWsIcPGnJ60ROVu3K32uI7Gtg7zciUle7hfZnN5HPrJ1mD38LZWT5x5DQOyd5CpLXt0hL125fKqOQL/embed?start=false&amp;loop=true&amp;delayms=15000&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; width=&#34;960&#34; height=&#34;569&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;video&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9yv6SdDtU-Q&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beautiful Basics - Series</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2022 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I keynoted &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/BSidesVancouver&#34;&gt;@BSidesVancouver&lt;/a&gt;. It was an honor to be asked and I had a great time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conference Link: &lt;a href=&#34;https://hopin.com/events/bsides-vancouver-2022/&#34;&gt;https://hopin.com/events/bsides-vancouver-2022/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I talked about 11 lessons learned over my career that contradict some of the edicts that are well known in the Cyber Security space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get into the lessons though, let me attack the things I know many of you reading this already have queued up in your head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/2022/beautifulbasics_excuses.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;counter-point-1&#34;&gt;Counter Point 1&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All of that is well and good, but it&amp;rsquo;ll never work where I work.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why not?&lt;/strong&gt; Every single one of these lessons learned are things that I was told wasn&amp;rsquo;t possible. For the most part they were things I didn&amp;rsquo;t even do, they were things either already in place when I joined the company or put into place while I worked there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw first hand that something I was told was &amp;ldquo;impossible&amp;rdquo; was not only possible but accomplished much more than I could have imagined. Until you see something for yourself, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to go against what you are taught, but as Security Professionals isn&amp;rsquo;t that what we are supposed to do? Look beyond the scope of what is seen as &amp;ldquo;possible&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;counter-point-2&#34;&gt;Counter Point 2&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not as easy as you are making it sound.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are right, none of this is easy. Good work hardly ever is. If you are looking for the easy solution, something that can be done in a day or a week this is not the blog series for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;counter-point-3&#34;&gt;Counter Point 3&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;We already known all of this&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Awesome! I wish I would have known these things earlier in my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;lessons-learned&#34;&gt;Lessons Learned&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-01&#34;&gt;Lesson 1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-02&#34;&gt;Lesson 2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-03&#34;&gt;Lesson 3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-04&#34;&gt;Lesson 4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-05&#34;&gt;Lesson 5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-06&#34;&gt;Lesson 6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-07&#34;&gt;Lesson 7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-08&#34;&gt;Lesson 8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-09&#34;&gt;Lesson 9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-10&#34;&gt;Lesson 10&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/post/2022/beautiful-basics-lesson-11&#34;&gt;Lesson 11&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;h4 id=&#34;slides&#34;&gt;Slides&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vQWsIcPGnJ60ROVu3K32uI7Gtg7zciUle7hfZnN5HPrJ1mD38LZWT5x5DQOyd5CpLXt0hL125fKqOQL/embed?start=false&amp;loop=true&amp;delayms=15000&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; width=&#34;960&#34; height=&#34;569&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;video&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/9yv6SdDtU-Q&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; allowfullscreen title=&#34;YouTube Video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;



</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
