<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Podcasts on Room362</title>
    <link>//room362.com/categories/podcasts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Podcasts on Room362</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2010 18:49:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//room362.com/categories/podcasts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>grmn00bs podcast</title>
      <link>//room362.com/post/2010/2010-01-08-grmn00bs-podcast/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2010 18:49:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//room362.com/post/2010/2010-01-08-grmn00bs-podcast/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently on the grmn00bs podcast, I had a great time, and I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see who they pick up next on their series:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.grmn00bs.com/2009/12/16/podcast-episode-9-when-they-were-n00bs-with-rob-fullermubix&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;grmn00bs podcast: episode 9&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20091227070701/http://www.grmn00bs.com/2009/12/16/podcast-episode-9-when-they-were-n00bs-with-rob-fullermubix&#34;&gt;Archive.org Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;When they were n00bs Series&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Show Notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hak5.org/&#34;&gt;hak5&lt;/a&gt; is one of the original security shows. Rob has been featured on several segments.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twit.tv/&#34;&gt;Twit Netcast Network with Leo Laporte&lt;/a&gt; is another show that&amp;rsquo;s been around for a while.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.securitytube.net/&#34;&gt;Security Tube&lt;/a&gt; is the Youtube of security videos. This is where I&amp;rsquo;m at when I should be working. You might even find some GRM n00bs stuff rattling around there.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theacademypro.com/&#34;&gt;The Academy Pro&lt;/a&gt; is another excellent place to go for security training.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.milw0rm.com&#34;&gt;milw0rm&lt;/a&gt; has lots of exploits. It&amp;rsquo;s a good place to check out some old papers to brush up on security history.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://neworder.box.sk/&#34;&gt;NewOrder&lt;/a&gt; is another resource to get abreast of lessons learned in the past.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.digininja.org/jasager/&#34;&gt;Jasager&lt;/a&gt; is the &amp;ldquo;Yes Man&amp;rdquo; Rob talks about in the show.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://astore.amazon.com/carnal0wnage-20/&#34;&gt;Chris Gates&amp;rsquo;s book list&lt;/a&gt; has some good ideas for security reading.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.syngress.com/&#34;&gt;Syngress&lt;/a&gt; is a publisher of security texts. They have all my money.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donate to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hackersforcharity.org/&#34;&gt;Johnny Long&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time, Fedora, and other things 42 related.</title>
      <link>//room362.com/post/2006/2006-05-08-time-fedora-and-other-things-42-related-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2006 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//room362.com/post/2006/2006-05-08-time-fedora-and-other-things-42-related-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I haven’t posted in a while. Which is due to supreme work related stresses&amp;hellip;. no, actually just lazyness, but atleast I am a bit better than say, oh &lt;a href=&#34;http://darrenkitchen.net&#34;&gt;Darren Kitchen&lt;/a&gt;, (April 17th) or &lt;a href=&#34;http://dankiswess.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Wess Tobler&lt;/a&gt; (December 11th). Ok, ya, my last post was on the 6th of April and TECHNICALLY I don’t beat Darren’s but, I actually post something, he posts videos&amp;hellip; pfffft. That isn’t a blog. ;-) You know I love you D. Anyways, in other news, I believe I will be hitting the 500+ pictures mark of my son soon. It’s crazy. Oh, and I installed &lt;a href=&#34;http://fedora.redhat.com/&#34;&gt;Fedora Core 5&lt;/a&gt; on my laptop to test it out. I’ll tell you guys how it’s going.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am hooked on 3 TV shows. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fox.com/24/&#34;&gt;24&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://abc.go.com/primetime/lost/&#34;&gt;Lost&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.the4400.com&#34;&gt;The 4400&lt;/a&gt;. Lost supposedly had their best episode all season last Wednesday and 24 is winding down after a great season, The 4400 will be starting up again for Season 3 on June 11th at 9 EST on the USA Network .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also watched the first episode of a exciting new IPTV show done by Foxx, Mustang, and special guest LuckyPhil called &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.bsodtv.org&#34;&gt;BSOD&lt;/a&gt; (Bastard Sons of Dial-up) a.k.a Blue Screen of Death boys ;-)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, during the last month I was accepted to DJ at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yarradio.com&#34;&gt;Yarradio.com&lt;/a&gt; which I had to turn down half way through acceptance due to some real life conflicts of schedule but they were great people to work with, and I’d like to put a shout out to DJ Snowball who hooked me up with the gig, and Loathed and Degrifter for all the help and understanding during my training phase for all my scheduling delemas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and I will be going to Japan in the next few months so, I might disappear for an extended period of time again. I am real excited about the trip and it will be a nice break from everything. If you want me to pick you up a certain manga/anime or other gift shout me an IM or email and I’ll see what I can hook up. All requests for 1st Class tickets or Sumo tickets will be accepted on a case by case basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it for now. I’ll be back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hak.5 Episode 9</title>
      <link>//room362.com/post/2006/2006-04-06-hak5-episode-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2006 06:24:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//room362.com/post/2006/2006-04-06-hak5-episode-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, so I am a little late on posting. Been kinda busy with my new son, work, and everything in between (mainly IRC). The reason I am posting about this episode is because I was welcomed onto the show as a Guest. If you have already seen it. Yes, I was nervous and Yes, I am ugly. Get it? Got it? Good. Ok, well I did a segment on applications that conviently fit onto a USB flash drive. Now, I only showed 4 on the show, my favorites. However there are about 32 applications that I would like to share. Which brings me to my second shout out to all the viewers: Yes, I have the complete list, Yes, it is publicly available, and NO I will not send, email, or IM you the link until the 10th. The reason for this is I was welcomed on the show as a guest as I said before and I respect their way of doing things, so I will retain the knowledge of the link until the rest of the show notes are released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh by the way, if you don’t know about Hak.5, go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hak5.org&#34;&gt;http://www.hak5.org/&lt;/a&gt; and click on Episodes, you will see multiple links to many different ways to download the episodes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can find the list of USB applications that I previewed on the show at &lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20060614073745/http://www.room362.com/pages/usbgoodies.html&#34;&gt;/pages/usbgoodies.html&lt;/a&gt; or by clicking on the link under static pages.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SploitCast, a Feburary baby, ShmooCon and Tax season</title>
      <link>//room362.com/post/2006/2006-01-29-sploitcast-a-feburary-baby-shmoocon-and-tax-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2006 02:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//room362.com/post/2006/2006-01-29-sploitcast-a-feburary-baby-shmoocon-and-tax-season/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Geez. I never have time anymore to put something on this darn thing. I think I am going to stop apologizing for how long it takes me to post, because it is quite quickly becoming the norm. So anyways, since my last post, I have been to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shmoocon.org&#34;&gt;ShmooCon &amp;lsquo;06&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//room362.com/images/postimages/shmoocon2006.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I met some great people to include but not limited to, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mal-aware.org/&#34;&gt;Lance James&lt;/a&gt;, Kevin Mitnick, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.insecure.org/&#34;&gt;Fyodor&lt;/a&gt; - A.K.A the creator of NMAP, Skydog, DC-Mike, and Simple Nomad. And those are just some of the highlights of what happened. Bruce Potter, who is sort of a Bruce Banner / Harry Potter mix, in the closing ceremonies decided to start throwing electronics out into the crowd, one of such attacks hitting me. But I got a 1gb USB drive out of the deal so it&amp;rsquo;s all good. Oh, and a little birdy told me that they may be releasing the videos too all confrences via torrent some time in mid Feb. So if you missed the fun, atleast check out the talks. That way, next year, you&amp;rsquo;ll beat yourself up even more to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next topic: Feburary Baby. It&amp;rsquo;s about that time. Words can&amp;rsquo;t express how excited I am for the first addition to my family. I am the middle child and my older sister was supposed the be the first. I think she just wanted to test the waters with a nephew first before she picked out one of her own ;-).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//room362.com/images/postimages/sploitcast.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next topic: SploitCast. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sploitcast.com&#34;&gt;SploitCast&lt;/a&gt; is REALLY taking off. I don&amp;rsquo;t know what or why it happened. But we are getting some pretty big names to speak on our tiny little podcast. Check us out at SploitCast.com or on iTunes. I&amp;rsquo;ll add a link in the navigation bar so it&amp;rsquo;s easier for ya&amp;rsquo;ll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next topic: Tax Season for all you Northern Americans under Canada. For the first time in my life, I have my taxes submitted before the deadline. Do you have yours done?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now a question for the crowd: What is your favorite tool? Any tool, it could be software, a hammer or jolt cola. What is that one thing you couldn&amp;rsquo;t survive without?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SploitCast hits the shelves!</title>
      <link>//room362.com/post/2006/2006-01-10-sploitcast-hits-the-shelves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 05:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//room362.com/post/2006/2006-01-10-sploitcast-hits-the-shelves/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;.-.. .. ... - . -. / - --- / ... .--. .-.. --- .. - -.-. .- ... - / .-- .-- .-- .-.-.- ... .--. .-.. --- .. - -.-. .- ... - .-.-.- -.-. --- --&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The above is Morse code. But anyways, we release the first episode of SploitCast yesterday night and we already have 1164 diggs. Which is pretty exciting. A lot of people have said quite a few good things about what we are doing. One thing that we do have to work on is the volume equalizing, which is just time and experiance. I am very glad that so many people viewed our first episode as a hit. Thanks for all your support. You can subscribe to SploitCast on iTunes by clicking &lt;a href=&#34;http://phobos.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewPodcast?id=116603876&amp;amp;amp;s=143441&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or by going to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sploitcast.com&#34;&gt;SploitCast.com&lt;/a&gt;. Check it out and tell us what you think. You can also help us out by digging the the story at digg.com :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20090222085828/http://digg.com/security/SploitCast_-_a_new_podcast_for_hackers&#34;&gt;SploitCast - a new podcast for hackers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jd&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;archive-org-copy-of-sploitcast-com-https-web-archive-org-web-20090307174402-http-sploitcast-com:40778a4ce70dbb0b9832aa6e76395d6b&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20090307174402/http://sploitcast.com/&#34;&gt;Archive.org copy of Sploitcast.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VPN Hacking Game</title>
      <link>//room362.com/post/2005/2005-12-14-vpn-hacking-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2005 23:34:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//room362.com/post/2005/2005-12-14-vpn-hacking-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have created this post to invite all who read this (all 5 of ya, yes, I know your IPs by heart) to a game that was initiated out of a forum thread on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hak5.tv/forums/viewtopic.php?t=433&#34;&gt;the Hak.5 Forums&lt;/a&gt;. If you would like to join the game, by you commenting on this post you are accepting an agreement that ANYTHING that happens across this VPN is not my or any of the participants fault. You are also authorizing yourself to be a target. HOWEVER, the rules of this game are that of the WHITE HAT. You are not allowed to destroy ANYTHING on ANY computer on the VPN unless explicitly announced. Also, if there is a complaint, a valid complaint against you for not adhering to these rules, you certificate will be revoked and you will no longer be able to participate. I will be the final judge on wither or not a complaint is valid or not. I will be recording ALL traffic across the VPN. Yes, I do have enough space. If you agree to these rules, please add the comment of “I AGREE” , your handle, and include your email address in a human legible way. When the game begins I will email out each individual certificate. Further rules will be set once an initial panel of judges is formed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to be a judge. There will be 2 spots. Email me for more information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New IPTV Links</title>
      <link>//room362.com/post/2005/2005-12-06-new-iptv-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2005 18:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//room362.com/post/2005/2005-12-06-new-iptv-links/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just a real quick FYI. Since I have been getting more and more into the IPTV scene, I figured that I would add links to my favorite shows. I will most indubitably be adding more, but this is a good start. Check it out over&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash; There..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;opps.. now  there &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hak.5 and techPhile merge for a day.</title>
      <link>//room362.com/post/2005/2005-12-04-hak5-and-techphile-merge-for-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2005 17:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//room362.com/post/2005/2005-12-04-hak5-and-techphile-merge-for-a-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hak5.org&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//room362.com/images/postimages/hak5_logo_small.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;December 2nd, I drove down to Williamsburg VA to meet up with the guys from Hak.5 and Frank Linhares. For those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t know. Hak.5 is an IPTV (Vidcast) show, which basically boils down to a TV show on the internet. Anyways, I got to meet up with these fellas and a couple other interesting people. While I was there, I had the privilege of helping out not only in the live &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techphile.ca&#34;&gt;techPhile&lt;/a&gt; podcast by Frank Linhares, but also the &amp;lsquo;glue&amp;rsquo; segments of Ep 5 of Hak.5. I must say, if and of the Hak.5 crew or Frank are reading this; it was a great pleasure to hang out with you guys. I would also like to make some personal shout outs to each one, and because this is my site. I get to. Muhahaha.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frank&lt;/strong&gt;: It was awesome to meet and get to know you. You still owe me dinner! ;-) But seriously, it was an honor to help out with the show.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Darren&lt;/strong&gt;: You have Hak.5 on lock, keep up the awesome work, and it was cool meeting you. Thanks for the invite. Inviting someone you have never met into your home is a big deal to me, thanks for the trust and respect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wess&lt;/strong&gt;: I love you man. We need to tell Alli about us before this gets ugly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harrison&lt;/strong&gt;: It was sweet meeting you man. We became fast friends; you and I think a lot alike. (&amp;lsquo;cept for cars: Ferrari Sucks) and I think &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shmoocon.org&#34;&gt;ShmooCon 2006&lt;/a&gt; is gonna rock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon&lt;/strong&gt;: Man, we will get Gentoo done. If you need any further help you guys got my number - Mubix – Tech Support &lt;sup&gt;24&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt; 365. Keep it real man.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alli, Paul, Harrison&amp;rsquo;s Mom, and Jui-Chia&lt;/strong&gt;: It was cool hanging out with you guys. I had a blast down there. 1 &lt;sup&gt;1&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;2&lt;/sub&gt; hour commute is worth it to hang out w/ you guys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One last thanks goes out to all the people in the IRC channel &lt;a href=&#34;irc://irc.techphile.ca&#34;&gt;techPhile IRC server&lt;/a&gt; #hak5 and #techphile for making my moderation a cake walk. Except for a certain individual, all the questions were perfect and I only had to fix/deny a few of them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What happened!?</title>
      <link>//room362.com/post/2005/2005-11-30-what-happened/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2005 04:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//room362.com/post/2005/2005-11-30-what-happened/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well if you were wondering about me, I didn&amp;rsquo;t die. I am working on a super secret project for Frank Linhares of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techphile.ca&#34;&gt;techPhile.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//room362.com/images/postimages/techphile_logo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don&amp;rsquo;t tell anyone! That is secret squrrell news. I have also submitted some logo ideas for the new Auditor Security Collection. You can vote for me: &lt;a href=&#34;http://forum.remote-exploit.org/viewtopic.php?t=1408&amp;amp;amp;start=15&amp;amp;amp;sid=8fa9089f2224df115d1f605cbcf704f8&#34;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got a HP dv1420us which, so far, I really like. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t like linux too much, but it is challenging me to learn more about the kernel and other aspects of linux to fix the problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways,&lt;br /&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ll start posting more&amp;hellip;. promise&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;j.d.mubix&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TechTV back from the dead?</title>
      <link>//room362.com/post/2005/2005-09-17-techtv-back-from-the-dead/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2005 18:46:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//room362.com/post/2005/2005-09-17-techtv-back-from-the-dead/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,&lt;br /&gt;
I am proud to announce that TechTV, the cable television channel that we know and USED to love might just be making a comeback. In an ‘Aliens’ sort of revival, a year and a half after they were pwnd ‘merged’, might be popping out on top of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.g4tv.com&#34;&gt;G4&lt;/a&gt;. For starters they are bringing back “&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.callforhelptv.com&#34;&gt;Call for Help&lt;/a&gt;” with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.leoville.tv&#34;&gt;Leo Leporte&lt;/a&gt;. First seen on KevinRose.com which is a blog written by, yup you guessed it Kevin Rose, the next move is that the G4 Founder and CEO who engineered the dumbass move ‘merger’ has been FIRED! released. There are so many blogs and IRC channels that are DEDICATED to bringing back TechTV that it surprises me that the suits over at G4 took this long to get the message.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hollywood.com/celebs/detail/celeb/190259&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to vote for how much you like Charles Hirschhorn&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the FORMER TechTV killer click &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.g4tv.com/html/about.asp?area=about&amp;amp;subarea=chirschhorn&#34;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt; for his Bio at G4’s about page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tell me what you think about the issue. Post a comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come back to us&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//room362.com/images/postimages/200509_techtv_1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//room362.com/images/postimages/200509_techtv_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jd&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>