<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Room362</title>
    <link>http://room362.com/categories/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Room362</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:43:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://room362.com/categories/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Problems with blogging software</title>
      <link>http://room362.com/post/2013/2013-08-10-problems-with-blogging-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://room362.com/post/2013/2013-08-10-problems-with-blogging-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Problems are that everyone does this whole blogging thing in so many different ways. Me, personally? I like to have a client that I can save drafts it, work on things a little bit here and there and then finalize stuff when I&amp;rsquo;m ready to post. I have a couple dozen of these posts ready and set with final tweaks needed but my blogging software Squarespace up and moved on to &amp;ldquo;Squarespace 6&amp;rdquo;. The the current stage you don&amp;rsquo;t have to move to 6 but at some point the owners of Squarespace are going to force everyone over. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to wait for that to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Octopress and Postach.io are my favorite options right now. Both blog in markdown language which is ok. Converting 8 years of blog posts to markdown is going to be a lot of work but a one time deal. Plus it would give me a chance to go through and fix the things that were broken over the years of modified blogging clients and services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postach.io has one major downside, they don&amp;rsquo;t have good &amp;ldquo;code&amp;rdquo; block support, whereas Octopress/Jekyll have excellent support as well code hilighting. The major upside? It&amp;rsquo;s based on Evernote. Which means I can blog from whereever I have Evernote. They also used to have an EXCELLENT feature that seems to have disappeared where if you updated a post it would automatically throw the blog post up to the top of your page, meaning your update would get back in your RSS feed and the update wouldn&amp;rsquo;t go unnoticed as most updates to blog posts do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Done</title>
      <link>http://room362.com/post/2005/2005-07-31-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2005 09:58:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://room362.com/post/2005/2005-07-31-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, I finally got a working CMS type deal going on for a blog. I was going to write one but decided not to. Call it lazy or standing on the shoulders of
programming gods, you choose.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>