<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ashleypark on Room362</title>
    <link>https://room362.com/categories/ashleypark/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ashleypark on Room362</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2005 21:55:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://room362.com/categories/ashleypark/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ASHEE has moved - Updated</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2005/2005-08-31-ashee-has-moved-updated/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2005 21:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2005/2005-08-31-ashee-has-moved-updated/</guid>
      <description>(Updated because people were having a hard time finding where I had put the site)
I am no longer going to post everything she writes to the main page. It is taking up too much space. From now on I will post when there is an update, and you can find it in the navigation bar. Hopefully I didn’t make it too hard to find.
jd.mubix
For those of you featured in the picture below, look at the left side of the page, find “Stupid People”, click that, then when “Ashley Park” shows up, click on her.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angry Reader? And the response...</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2005/2005-08-29-angry-reader-and-the-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Aug 2005 17:23:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2005/2005-08-29-angry-reader-and-the-response/</guid>
      <description>And here is what she sent me back:
 WHAT THE FUCK EVER. I KNOW THAT I LOVE MY COUNTRY AND MY TROOPS. I KNOW THAT BUSH IS SENDING MORE OVER THERE TO BE KILLED. I HATE IT BUT I GUESS THAT IS WERE PEOPLE MESSED UP FOR VOTING FOR HIM. I WASNT TALKING ABOUT THE HIJACKERS THEMSELVES, BUT THEIR “BOSS” DUH. BUT YOU KNOW WHAT I AM SO TIRED OF HEARING YOUR SHIT BECAUSE THAT IS ALL IT IS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angry Reader? Could this get better?</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2005/2005-08-27-angry-reader-could-this-get-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Aug 2005 22:21:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2005/2005-08-27-angry-reader-could-this-get-better/</guid>
      <description>I sent her this today:
 Ashley,
I think you watch the news too much. First : The reason why we can’t find the airplane hijackers of 9-11 is because they went up in a cloud of smoke just like all our loved ones did. Second: ‘They’ aren’t smarter than us. We are just a lot bigger target. What is easier to catch? A pillow or the piece of lint falling from it?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angry Reader? Keep it going?</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2005/2005-08-26-angry-reader-keep-it-going-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2005 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2005/2005-08-26-angry-reader-keep-it-going-html/</guid>
      <description>Should I respond and keep it going? Give me your comments.. or should I create a poll? If you want me to keep it going, should I:
 Tell her to check out the site again, cause you know she hasn’t Tell her off Be nice &amp;hellip;. again  You decide.
One of my readers was trying to post this in the comments. So here it is. </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angry Reader? The Saga Continues</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2005/2005-08-25-angry-reader-the-saga-continues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2005 18:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2005/2005-08-25-angry-reader-the-saga-continues/</guid>
      <description>If this is your first time reading this, then you need to read this first: (Angry Reader?)
I got this today:
 Well you now what, I have always had a problem believing people but I grew out of it. And now I realize why I never trusted people before because they cant be trusted. You post a lie on the internet and dont even let anyone know it is a lie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angry Reader?</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2005/2005-08-25-angry-reader/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2005 04:11:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2005/2005-08-25-angry-reader/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: I just looked at your ‘referal’ page http://search.yahoo.com/search?p=www.usmc.com&amp;amp;fr=ieas-dns
&amp;hellip; you did a search for www.usmc.com&amp;hellip;
This speaks for itself:
Ashley: (A Comment on USMC: Crack down on Tats)
 I can’t believe that they are doing this. Everyone in my boyfriends Platoon has a tat.They are over seas dieing and they are worried about tattooes?!!!?!? Shouldnt they be more worried about their safe &amp;hellip;
 I sent her this email:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USMC: Crack down on Tats</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2005/2005-08-05-usmc-crack-down-on-tats/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2005 14:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2005/2005-08-05-usmc-crack-down-on-tats/</guid>
      <description>(This is a joke) IN BREAKING NEWS: The Marine Corps has adopted the no Tat policy. In this bold move, it is Dishonorably discharging 80% of it&amp;rsquo;s current personnel due to this new &amp;ldquo;Clean or Out&amp;rdquo; program. </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>