<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>guestpost on malicious.link</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/tags/guestpost/</link>
    <description>Recent content in guestpost on malicious.link</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 09:30:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://malicious.link/tags/guestpost/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>No Tech Hacking - Tip of the Hat</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2008/no-tech-hacking-tip-of-the-hat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2008 09:30:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2008/no-tech-hacking-tip-of-the-hat/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to do my part and tip my hat to Johnny Long from &lt;a href=&#34;http://johnny.ihackstuff.com&#34;&gt;ihackstuff.com&lt;/a&gt;. He really is doing great work. Also, check out &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hackersforcharity.org/&#34;&gt;hackersforcharity.org&lt;/a&gt; to do your part. Without further ado, HERE’S JOHNNY!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Tech Hacking Released!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m proud to announce the release of No Tech Hacking from Syngress Publishing! I’m even more happy to announce that 100% of the proceeds will be going to charity. In fact, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/gp/product/1597492159?&amp;amp;camp=212361&amp;amp;creative=380729&amp;amp;linkCode=wey&amp;amp;tag=ihackstuff-20&#34;&gt;each purchase through this Amazon like will feed an African child for one month!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What’s the story with the proceeds?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s simple, really. My proceeds from this book are going to AOET (aoet.org), an organization that provides food, education and medical care to children left in the wake of Africa’s HIV/AIDS epidemic. More than an aid organization, AOET aims to disrupt the cycle of poverty and hopelessness in sub-Saharan Africa through empowerment programs and job training, enabling children and adults to be self-sustaining, restoring not only their health but their pride and hope for a brighter future. A single book purchase made through my Amazon associates account (linked from any of my websites, or though &lt;a href=&#34;http://tiniuri.com/f/Xpc&#34;&gt;http://tiniuri.com/f/Xpc&lt;/a&gt;) will generate enough income for AOET to feed a child for an entire month. Other retail purchases (which generate half as much income) will provide either medical services or educational supplies and funding for a single child through a donation pool set aside for those purposes. Why bother? Because I am called to “look after orphans and widows in their distress” (James 1:27), and I know from personal experience how mutually transformative it can be to take that calling seriously. Hamlet was onto something when he wondered, &amp;ldquo;Whether &amp;rsquo;tis nobler in the mind to suffer the slings and arrows of outrageous fortune or to take arms against a sea of troubles, and by opposing, end them.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Johnny Long&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you can’t do anything else, buy a book using the link above and help support a child in need. Again, the link is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No Tech Hacking on Amazon.com -  &lt;a href=&#34;http://tinyurl.com/3bt9or&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;http://tinyurl.com/3bt9or&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
