<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>certifications on malicious.link</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/categories/certifications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in certifications on malicious.link</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 18:53:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://malicious.link/categories/certifications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Offensive Security Certified Professional</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-02-01-offensive-security-certified-professional/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 18:53:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-02-01-offensive-security-certified-professional/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently obtained the status &lt;strong&gt;Offensive Security Certified Professional&lt;/strong&gt;. It is one of the best courses I have ever taken. It challenged me to think and learn new skills on the fly. You start the course with a bunch of video files, a huge pdf and an lzm file to get your VPN setup. It is self paced and intense. The topics cover everything from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.remote-exploit.org/&#34;&gt;Back|Track&lt;/a&gt; basics to the HXDEF rootkit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the problem, you can&amp;rsquo;t get a job with it. I know that seems shallow, but let me explain. As I see it there are basically 3 types of certifications or for that matter education in general that you can go through. The first gets you a job. The second teaches you something. The third is good for you or fun.This course is fun but more so falls in the &amp;lsquo;teaches you something&amp;rsquo; category. The CISSP on the other hand help you get a job, but I&amp;rsquo;ll hold that topic for another post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, the &lt;a href=&#34;http://offensive-security.com/offsec101.php&#34;&gt;Offensive Security 101&lt;/a&gt; course (leads to the OSCP test), is not quite on the radars of any recruiters or for that matter companies yet. Which is truly a shame. Unlike the CISSP and almost every other certification that I know of or heard of via 3rd party, this cert makes you &amp;ldquo;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;try harder&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;. And all of the pain ends in a 24 hour marathon of hacking, where you will be an idiot not to use every second of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been a huge supporter of Back|Track for ages and they have really shifted my thinking of certifications by providing the Offsec 101 course. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to take their other courses, Wi-Fu and Back|Track to the Max (which I am told that my mind will melt during the course of study). They also have some &lt;a href=&#34;http://offensive-security.com/ilt.php&#34;&gt;instructor led training&lt;/a&gt; so you can get one on one with Muts or one of the other crazy brains behind &lt;a href=&#34;http://offensive-security.com&#34;&gt;OFFENSIVE SECURITY&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can sign up for classes via their website: &lt;a href=&#34;http://offensive-security.com/training.php&#34;&gt;http://offensive-security.com/training.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also check out some of their videos here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://offensive-security.com/videos.php&#34;&gt;http://offensive-security.com/videos.php&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**Update: **Back|Track to the Max is now named:&lt;a href=&#34;http://offensive-security.com/ctp.php&#34;&gt; Cracking the Perimeter&lt;/a&gt; which ends in your OSCE (Offensive Security Certified Expert) exam.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
