<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Breaking News on malicious.link</title>
    <link>/tags/breaking-news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Breaking News on malicious.link</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2008 03:13:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/breaking-news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasters Meetup @ DEFCON 16</title>
      <link>/post/2008/200879podcasters-meetup-defcon-16-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2008 03:13:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2008/200879podcasters-meetup-defcon-16-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;To All,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, this year marks the first annual &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.defcon.org/&#34;&gt;DEFCON&lt;/a&gt; Podcaster’s Meetup, and we will be doing it in STYLE. For those of you who made it out to the second annual Podcaster’s Meetup at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shmoocon.org/&#34;&gt;ShmooCon&lt;/a&gt;, we ran into some hitches (like sound), but as we grow, so do the problems. Let me start off by telling you some sweet news. We are nailing down time in a SkyBox! So we will have plenty of room, piece and quite for recording, and a nice view over the con, plus NO WALKING TO THE PARTY. We will have it right there in the box!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Podcasters,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I need to know as soon as possible how many already are set to go, those intending on getting set up and those who can’t make it. Also, if the idea of getting in free pushes you over the ‘going’ edge, we may be able to work that as well. Also, on that note, please forward this, like a Microshaft chain letter to any other podcasters that may be going, give them my email address so we can start a dialog and work out any kinks in their plans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Potential Sponsors,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have included you in this email because I want you to understand the possibilities of this event. It will be at DEFCON 16. The most well known security / hacker conference. If you want to send fliers, stickers, drinks, money, or prizes, we can work out the details. We will be recording and broadcasting a live show from DEFCON which usually brings in 100 local and up to 500 remote viewers. It is then rebroadcast on which ever podcasters or vidcasters distribution that wants to and that could range from 10,000 to 1 million potential viewers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As information is updated and confirmations come in, I will be updating the collaboration site: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.podcastersmeetup.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.podcastersmeetup.com/&lt;/a&gt; . Feel free to post or forward this information on to who every you like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like an account in order to broadcast your presence at the event, please signup and I will upgrade your user level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those who may not know: DEFCON 16: August 8-10, 2008&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your time, and I look forward to hearing from you,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rob Fuller, a.k.a. &lt;a href=&#34;../../../../&#34;&gt;Mubix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacker steals Quake</title>
      <link>/post/2008/2008629hacker-steals-quake-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jun 2008 17:04:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2008/2008629hacker-steals-quake-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a Dutch news site there was a story about a hacker that stole 50,000 credit cards (well, the information at least) and also stole a prerelease version of Quake Wars. What do you think made the title line? Quake Wars. That puts things in perspective on what is impotant. Big companies like the one that made Quake Wars have the liquid budget to chase this guy down, but the 50,000 individuals don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Is it bad that my sole thought after reading this article is wondering how he got into the Id Software servers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dutchnews.nl/news/archives/2008/06/hacker_arrested_for_stealing_q.php&#34;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other hacker news,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.news.com.au/couriermail/story/0,23739,23933178-952,00.html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hacker reveals flaws in school website security&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;“&lt;a href=&#34;http://news.cnet.com/8301-10789_3-9978151-57.html&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Woman accused of hacking Houston organ bank indicted&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
