<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>internet - Category - Malicious Link - Blog by mubix - Rob Fuller</title>
        <link>https://malicious.link/categories/internet/</link>
        <description>internet - Category - Malicious Link - Blog by mubix - Rob Fuller</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>mubix@hak5.org (Rob Fuller)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>mubix@hak5.org (Rob Fuller)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 21:02:22 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://malicious.link/categories/internet/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Suggestions on what to do when a service you use gets compromised</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2013/2013-03-02-suggestions-on-what-to-do-when-a-service-you-use-gets-compro/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2013 21:02:22 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2013/2013-03-02-suggestions-on-what-to-do-when-a-service-you-use-gets-compro/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[It seems like every week there is a new compromise of some service or another. But as a user what are you supposed to do with this knowledge? Here are some suggestions on things to do or think about when reacting:
Do you use the password you use there anywhere else? Think about starting to use a password manager like LastPass, 1Password, KeePass, or a product like Yubico. This way you can very easily use different passwords for different sites.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Companies that give back with free tools</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2012/2012-06-20-companies-that-give-back-with-free-tools/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jun 2012 18:34:57 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2012/2012-06-20-companies-that-give-back-with-free-tools/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Penetration Testing / Red Teaming requires the use of a lot of tools. I don&rsquo;t mind getting called a &ldquo;script kiddie&rdquo; because I can accomplish more and faster when I don&rsquo;t have to code every single task I need to do. This post is to point out companies that make this possible and give a small bit of thanks.
(If you&rsquo;ve ever tried to convince a company to give something away for free, you can understand how big this really is) Some give a lot, some only one tool, but even one is more than some.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Shared Links</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2011/2011-12-23-shared-links/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2011 03:45:27 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2011/2011-12-23-shared-links/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[When Google Reader decided to remove everything it was good for, we all scrambled to find new homes for things we wanted to share. Tumblr became a place that most of us flocked. I&rsquo;ve found Tumblr to be not a very good substitue for Google Reader&rsquo;s functionality (IMHO).
The other day, carnal0wnage told me about a service called &lsquo;Buffer&rsquo;, and all this thing does is do scheduled tweets, but it has one distinct feature, not only is it focused around the sharing of links, it works (if you install the browser plugin/extension) INSIDE OF GOOGLE READER ;-) So you can be reading a feed item, push a button and not have to open a page or another app, it&rsquo;s pretty much all right there.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>First day of a No Starch Christmas - Winner</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2011/2011-12-01-first-day-of-a-no-starch-christmas-winner/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2011 14:11:49 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2011/2011-12-01-first-day-of-a-no-starch-christmas-winner/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Our first day of No Starch winner is Russ with Room 362 right next to the Fire Hose ;-)
1st Day of @NoStarch Winner]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Wim Remes (@wimremes) for (ISC)2 Board of Directors</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2011/2011-08-30-wim-remes-wimremes-for-isc2-board-of-directors/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2011 15:25:52 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2011/2011-08-30-wim-remes-wimremes-for-isc2-board-of-directors/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I am way late to the game on this, but if you have a blog, a twitter handle, or even better (in this specific case) a CISSP, please support Wim Remes (@wimremes), as he has submitted to become a member of the (ISC)2 Board of Directors.
On twitter use the hashtag: #wim4board
Lets help the certifications, especially the one with so much corporate/gov acceptance, get better.
His petition: http://blog.remes-it.be/petition.html]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Exploitable Mobile App Challenge</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2011/2011-04-12-exploitable-mobile-app-challenge/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2011 17:12:36 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2011/2011-04-12-exploitable-mobile-app-challenge/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Original Post: http://blog.nvisiumsecurity.com/2011/04/exploitable-mobile-app-challenge-now.html
You can read the details on the above link, but it boils down to you make an application for iPhone or Android. You make it vulnerable to X,Y,Z types of flaws, you win a 32gb iPad or a Motorola Xoom.
Added bonus, all the apps get submitted to OWASP for people to learn Mobile security.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Patch Adams</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2011/2011-02-11-patch-adams/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2011 06:03:23 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2011/2011-02-11-patch-adams/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Thought I would share this video, if it isn&rsquo;t a swift kick in the pants to do better with your life I don&rsquo;t what is:]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Acceptable Questions Checklist</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2010/2010-10-01-acceptable-questions-checklist/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2010 18:00:51 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2010/2010-10-01-acceptable-questions-checklist/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[&ldquo;There is no stupid question&rdquo; but, if it doesn&rsquo;t meet this checklist, it&rsquo;s officially a time wasting one.
Acceptable questions checklist:
Have I tried it Have I checked the manual, wiki, or forum Have I googled and searched for an answer All marks must be achieved before a question is asked unless the target of the question is getting paid to answer the source&rsquo;s inquires &ldquo;Have I tried it&rdquo; mark can only be skipped in the case of life threatening actions PDF version is available upon request.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>A very important link...</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2010/2010-06-01-a-very-important-link/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2010 01:11:18 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2010/2010-06-01-a-very-important-link/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Normally I save links for my &ldquo;Mubix Links&rdquo; blog to keep the clutter down on this one, but I think this is one that I would like to highlight as important. The NFO, credits and summary to this copyrighted video is what I wish to highlight.
http://thepiratebay.org/torrent/5573874/Hackers_Wanted_%282008%29
I am against the misuse of copyrighted material, and it is a violation of laws in many countries, including my own.
I really wish this video would have been published, I&rsquo;m sure it would have been a very interesting video, that I definitely would have purchased.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Practical Exploitation</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2010/2010-02-23-practical-exploitation/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 17:00:02 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2010/2010-02-23-practical-exploitation/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Practical Exploitation is going to be me, explaining things in the way that I see the world on the best medium for what I&rsquo;m explaining, be it a short blog blurb, a video of me, a video of a desktop, or just audio. There is no schedule that I&rsquo;ll be sticking to, but I will guarantee you 3 things though:
If you want it explained and it has to do with infosec or hacking (I&rsquo;ll do my best on the hardware side), it will be on the show.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>2009 Geek Christmas List</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-12-03-2009-geek-christmas-list/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2009 17:00:06 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-12-03-2009-geek-christmas-list/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[What&rsquo;s on your list? Here is mine (in no particular order):
Number 1: iPhone compatible alarm clock with good sound
Number 2: iPhone car mount that charges and is compatible with aux cables
32GB E-flash (esata, USB2.0) Drobo 4 bay backup solution The Tauntaun Sleeping Bag Griffin PowerMate Kindle DX or Barnes and Noble Nook Nokia N900 Roku HD-XR This Tesla or this one Canon EOS Rebel T1i Popcorn Hour Device (trumps the Roku) Logitech MX Revolution Logitech Harmony One The Art of Software Security Assessment by Mark Dowd Windows Internals 5 by Mark Russinovich and David Solomon Wi-Spy 2.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>SHODAN The Computer Search</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-11-24-shodan-the-computer-search/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 24 Nov 2009 14:21:41 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-11-24-shodan-the-computer-search/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[If you haven&rsquo;t seen it all over twitter yet, achillean released the &ldquo;beta&rdquo; of SHODAN yesterday. It&rsquo;s a search engine of basically a nmap of the internet (ports 21, 22, 23 or 80 so far).
http://shodan.surtri.com/
You can search by keyword, and/or using any of the advanced search options.
country: 2-letter country code hostname: full or partial host name net: IP range using CIDR notation (ex: 18.7.7.0/24 ) port: 21, 22, 23 or 80 Here is just a taste of the power this bring to the game:]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Why Room362?</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-11-12-why-room362/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2009 04:46:37 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-11-12-why-room362/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[(This post got lost in the intertubes and it took a bit to get back, Archive.org nor Google cache had it)
I get this question all the time: “Why room362.com?” I have answered that question in a lot of ways, depending on the perceived amount of time I had to tell the story. But, on a blog you have tons of time, right? Not if you are studying the Twitter boom.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Getting your n00b fill of security</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-10-26-getting-your-n00b-fill-of-security/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2009 23:02:31 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-10-26-getting-your-n00b-fill-of-security/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Continuing my “Getting your fill of” series
Dave Shackleford recently posted an excellent blog entry titled “One for the n00bs”: http://daveshackleford.com/?p=277
It relates the security community to a high school cafeteria. It’s a good read and pretty dead on. I want to echo his sentiments, “I got my OWN lunch table. And you’re invited.”, I”m just an email away. I also wanted to let you know there are a lot of places where you can learn on your own, at your own pace, and without any chance of ridicule.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>APPLE: A Modern Day Willy Wonka Story</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-10-12-apple-a-modern-day-willy-wonka-story/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 15:42:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-10-12-apple-a-modern-day-willy-wonka-story/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Yes, I just called everyone who works at Apple an Oompa Loompa, but I digress:
I was reading Brooke Crothers&rsquo; story on the Apple &lsquo;gag&rsquo; order [1] and couldn&rsquo;t help but think of how Apple has created an almost similar situation. Everyone wants to know what Apple is up to, can&rsquo;t stop talking about it. Buzz Out Loud [2] even had people call and email asking them to see if they could do a show without mentioning Apple or the iPhone.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>SquareSpace, New Design and Call for Contributors</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-10-01-squarespace-new-design-and-call-for-contributors/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2009 18:50:24 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-10-01-squarespace-new-design-and-call-for-contributors/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The site has been down for a while, there were a lot of factors that played into that, but mostly it was focus on some family, as I had some in town. I also came to the conclusion that it&rsquo;s time to move to &ldquo;the cloud&rdquo; so I moved over to SquareSpace (using the coupon code: DEFCON &lt;/end shameless plug&gt;). I have an actual web designer looking at hooking this thing up right.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Getting your fill of Security</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-05-29-getting-your-fill-of-security/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2009 19:35:22 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-05-29-getting-your-fill-of-security/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I recently posted a blog post to Exotic Liability&rsquo;s website with the same title, and I realized that it would make a great thing to post to here, and update regularly, or just put it on the wiki I keep saying that I get going here. Enough rambling, here is how you can get your fill of security:
Podcasting: GetMon - http://www.getmon.com/ - This is a great site because you can download or listen to any of the security podcasts right from their site if you want to.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The History of the Internet - VIDEO</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-02-13-the-history-of-the-internet-video/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2009 20:04:39 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-02-13-the-history-of-the-internet-video/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I got this off of a post by Jason Appelbaum and I thought it important to repost. We all need to remember where we came from once in a while.
History of the Internet from Melih Bilgil on Vimeo.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Metasploit Across the Net</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-02-04-metasploit-across-the-net/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2009 18:13:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-02-04-metasploit-across-the-net/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Metasploit is awesome, but some don’t know that their are updates all the time via SVN, and even fewer know of places to get good non-svn modules / scripts. Here are a few of my favorites:
https://www.securinfos.info/metasploit/msfxdc.php http://metasploit.com/users/mc/ http://darkoperator.blogspot.com &ndash; newly added, check out the CookieMonster script and a host of others:
http://pentest.cryptocity.net And of course: http://carnal0wnage.blogspot.com/]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Bob Stories - Airport Boredom</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-02-02-bob-stories-airport-boredom/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2009 17:48:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-02-02-bob-stories-airport-boredom/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I registered Bobstories.com after listening to PaulDotCom for a while. I have always told stories of this manor, but never quite put a name to “my friend”. Now that he has a name, it is only fitting that he has a domain and a blog. Please, come, register under the name bob_#### with a mailinator address to match, or your own name and email address if you wish. I’ll moderate all posts simply for spam purposes and have them up post haste.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
