<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>ldapsearch - Tag - Malicious Link - Blog by mubix - Rob Fuller</title>
        <link>https://malicious.link/tags/ldapsearch/</link>
        <description>ldapsearch - Tag - Malicious Link - Blog by mubix - Rob Fuller</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>mubix@hak5.org (Rob Fuller)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>mubix@hak5.org (Rob Fuller)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 11:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://malicious.link/tags/ldapsearch/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>LDAPSearch Reference</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2022/ldapsearch-reference/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 11:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Rob Fuller</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2022/ldapsearch-reference/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ldapsearch is a extremely powerful tool, especially for Windows Active Directory enumeration. It&rsquo;s one of my primary tools when performing pentesting or red teaming against an environment with Active Directory, but also comes in quiet handy to know as many times it can come default installed or part of a base image, so its a bit Living-Off-The-Land-esq. Another point towards ldapsearch is that it&rsquo;s easy to forget that Active Directory isn&rsquo;t the only LDAP server in most environments and the ability to utilize a tool like this can come in extremely handy.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Dump LAPS passwords with ldapsearch</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2017/dump-laps-passwords-with-ldapsearch/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2017 07:35:28 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Rob Fuller</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2017/dump-laps-passwords-with-ldapsearch/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[If you&rsquo;ve ever been pentesting an organization that had LAPS, you know that it is the best solution for randomizing local administrator passwords on the planet. (You should just be leaving them disabled).
LAPS stores it&rsquo;s information in Active Directory:
The expiration time: ms-Mcs-AdmPwdExpirationTime: 131461867015760024
And the actual password in clear text: ms-Mcs-AdmPwd: %v!e#7S#{s})+y2yS#(
When LAPS first came it, any user in Active Directory could read it. Microsoft fixed that, you now have to have the All extended rights permission to the object or Full Control of it.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
