<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sploitcast on malicious.link</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/categories/sploitcast/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sploitcast on malicious.link</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2006 02:11:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://malicious.link/categories/sploitcast/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SploitCast, a Feburary baby, ShmooCon and Tax season</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2006/2006-01-29-sploitcast-a-feburary-baby-shmoocon-and-tax-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2006 02:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2006/2006-01-29-sploitcast-a-feburary-baby-shmoocon-and-tax-season/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Geez. I never have time anymore to put something on this darn thing. I think I am going to stop apologizing for how long it takes me to post, because it is quite quickly becoming the norm. So anyways, since my last post, I have been to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shmoocon.org&#34;&gt;ShmooCon &amp;lsquo;06&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/postimages/shmoocon2006.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I met some great people to include but not limited to, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mal-aware.org/&#34;&gt;Lance James&lt;/a&gt;, Kevin Mitnick, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.insecure.org/&#34;&gt;Fyodor&lt;/a&gt; - A.K.A the creator of NMAP, Skydog, DC-Mike, and Simple Nomad. And those are just some of the highlights of what happened. Bruce Potter, who is sort of a Bruce Banner / Harry Potter mix, in the closing ceremonies decided to start throwing electronics out into the crowd, one of such attacks hitting me. But I got a 1gb USB drive out of the deal so it&#39;s all good. Oh, and a little birdy told me that they may be releasing the videos too all confrences via torrent some time in mid Feb. So if you missed the fun, atleast check out the talks. That way, next year, you&#39;ll beat yourself up even more to go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next topic: Feburary Baby. It&#39;s about that time. Words can&#39;t express how excited I am for the first addition to my family. I am the middle child and my older sister was supposed the be the first. I think she just wanted to test the waters with a nephew first before she picked out one of her own ;-).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/postimages/sploitcast.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next topic: SploitCast. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sploitcast.com&#34;&gt;SploitCast&lt;/a&gt; is REALLY taking off. I don&#39;t know what or why it happened. But we are getting some pretty big names to speak on our tiny little podcast. Check us out at SploitCast.com or on iTunes. I&#39;ll add a link in the navigation bar so it&#39;s easier for ya&#39;ll.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next topic: Tax Season for all you Northern Americans under Canada. For the first time in my life, I have my taxes submitted before the deadline. Do you have yours done?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now a question for the crowd: What is your favorite tool? Any tool, it could be software, a hammer or jolt cola. What is that one thing you couldn&#39;t survive without?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SploitCast hits the shelves!</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2006/2006-01-10-sploitcast-hits-the-shelves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 05:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2006/2006-01-10-sploitcast-hits-the-shelves/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;.-.. .. ... - . -. / - --- / ... .--. .-.. --- .. - -.-. .- ... - / .-- .-- .-- .-.-.- ... .--. .-.. --- .. - -.-. .- ... - .-.-.- -.-. --- --&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The above is Morse code. But anyways, we release the first episode of SploitCast yesterday night and we already have 1164 diggs. Which is pretty exciting. A lot of people have said quite a few good things about what we are doing. One thing that we do have to work on is the volume equalizing, which is just time and experiance. I am very glad that so many people viewed our first episode as a hit. Thanks for all your support. You can subscribe to SploitCast on iTunes by clicking &lt;a href=&#34;http://phobos.apple.com/WebObjects/MZStore.woa/wa/viewPodcast?id=116603876&amp;amp;s=143441&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; or by going to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sploitcast.com&#34;&gt;SploitCast.com&lt;/a&gt;. Check it out and tell us what you think. You can also help us out by digging the the story at digg.com :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20090222085828/http://digg.com/security/SploitCast_-_a_new_podcast_for_hackers&#34;&gt;SploitCast - a new podcast for hackers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;jd&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;archiveorg-copy-of-sploitcastcomhttpswebarchiveorgweb20090307174402httpsploitcastcom&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20090307174402/http://sploitcast.com/&#34;&gt;Archive.org copy of Sploitcast.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
