<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Proxy on </title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/categories/proxy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Proxy on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 13:16:39 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://malicious.link/categories/proxy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing proxychains hardcoded DNS server</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2013/2013-09-10-changing-proxychains-hardcoded-dns-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 13:16:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2013/2013-09-10-changing-proxychains-hardcoded-dns-server/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever used proxychains to push things through Meterpreter, one of the most annoying things is its &amp;ldquo;hardcoded&amp;rdquo; DNS setting for 4.2.2.2, if the org that you are going after doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow this out of their network, or if you are trying to resolve an internal asset, you&amp;rsquo;re SOL. After a ton of googling and annoyed head slams into walls every time I forget where this is I&amp;rsquo;ve finally decided to make a note of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting SYSTEM&#39;s proxy settings with Metasploit</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2012/2012-10-21-setting-systems-proxy-settings-with-metasploit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Oct 2012 07:40:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2012/2012-10-21-setting-systems-proxy-settings-with-metasploit/</guid>
      <description>One of the great things about the reverse_http(s) payloads is that it is proxy aware. However one of the pitfalls to this is that SYSTEM doesn&amp;rsquo;t have proxy settings, nor do users who have never logged into a system (unless profile loading is triggered). The problem here arrises when you are trying to do anything as SYSTEM, also the PSEXEC only has the option of getting you a SYSTEM shell (so you&amp;rsquo;re done for right out of the door)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lab Setup - Windows Proxy and Egress Filtering</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2012/2012-10-06-lab-setup-windows-proxy-and-egress-filtering/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 03:02:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2012/2012-10-06-lab-setup-windows-proxy-and-egress-filtering/</guid>
      <description>pfSense is an excellent free way of including a firewall / ids / proxy in your lab or VMs. It runs small and fast, but even as simple as pfsense is sometimes you need a bit less complexity and speed of configuration.
Enter Peerblock and AnalogX&amp;rsquo;s proxy. Two free tools, one usually used to stop people who torrent from getting caught by the RIAA/MPAA and the other a drop dead simple windows based proxy utility.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>