<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>antivirus - Category - Malicious Link - Blog by mubix - Rob Fuller</title>
        <link>https://malicious.link/categories/antivirus/</link>
        <description>antivirus - Category - Malicious Link - Blog by mubix - Rob Fuller</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>mubix@hak5.org (Rob Fuller)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>mubix@hak5.org (Rob Fuller)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 16:00:38 &#43;0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://malicious.link/categories/antivirus/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>AV Tracker</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2010/2010-08-03-av-tracker/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 03 Aug 2010 16:00:38 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2010/2010-08-03-av-tracker/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Ever set up a multi/handler and get an odd IP hitting it? Probably forgot about it as internet chatter? Think again, you might have just been caught
AV Tracker - http://avtracker.info/ is a site that tracks the different IP addresses, hostnames, computer names and user agents that AV and other &ldquo;Submit-your-malware-here&rdquo; drop boxes use.
Peter Kleissner and his team provide
ranges that the hosts use a dynamic text file with the IP addresses listed if you want to add it to some auto updating block list a line by line IPTABLES block config and even C code to add into your binary to make sure it doesn&rsquo;t talk out from one of those addresses (I could be reading it wrong, still a beginner in C) The team has been criticized a lot by AV vendors, enough so the took down the site in January of this year.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>AV bypass made stupid</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2010/2010-06-03-av-bypass-made-stupid/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 03 Jun 2010 03:41:13 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2010/2010-06-03-av-bypass-made-stupid/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[WARNING if you use fgdump like I did, it extracts pwdump to %TEMP% at run time, which is detected by AV.
First of all, I was floored when this worked. Really AV? It&rsquo;s that easy? Really?
So here is the break down, go get &ldquo;Resource Hacker&quot;… You&rsquo;re almost done. Only 3 steps left. (1 of which is optional)
I started with fgdump, a well known hashdumping/pwdump tool. It&rsquo;s detected by 80% of all AVs and by all the top 10.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
