<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Room362</title>
    <link>https://room362.com/tags/rant/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Room362</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://room362.com/tags/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Time</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2015/10-25-time</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 12:02:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2015/10-25-time</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Time is a one-time non-renewable precious resource you are given. It is ok to be greedy, selective, and even snobbish about how, and with whom you spend it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it helps, think of your time as a vault, money is withdrawn at a constant rate by people as you spend it, but you are not allowed to look inside to see how much you have left. It could be a billion dollars, it could be .25 cents. If it were money, who would you spend it on if that were the case? Most likely you would be more cautious on who and what you spent any amount on.  (This is not to say you live a hermit, but pushing you to actively choose what you want instead of letting life happen and spending your resource)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, respect other&amp;rsquo;s choice to spend their time with you. I know we don&amp;rsquo;t always acknowledge it, but we should be a bit more cognizant of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We actually dismiss it nonchalantly, in English, with simple phrasing changes like &amp;ldquo;Thank you for spending THE time&amp;rdquo;. When we should probably say &amp;ldquo;Thank you for spending YOUR time&amp;rdquo;. I have heard it both ways and much more the latter, but it just struck me as I was writing the close to this blog post that I was about to do what I had just warned against.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, in closing, thank you for spending your precious moments reading my blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rob&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R5 Industries</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2015/10-14-r5-industries</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 12:02:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2015/10-14-r5-industries</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently took the plunge and joined a startup called R5 Industries. I wanted to say thanks for all the well wishes that I received on social media. It has certainly calmed my nerves about the choice ;-).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve had a number of people ask what R5 Industries does. Our primary selling point is AntigenC2, which is a really Command and Control detection product (no agents). But we also do Red Team assessments and some other fun toys if you are interested, contact@r5industries.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More info here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://r5industries.com/&#34;&gt;http://r5industries.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And thats the end and last sales pitch you&amp;rsquo;ll get from me on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did I make the move?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;While, I loved life as an internal Red Team member (highly recommended, if you need reasons why make sure you watch Chris Gates&amp;rsquo; talk at RuxCon: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ruxcon.org.au/speakers/#Chris&#34;&gt;https://ruxcon.org.au/speakers/#Chris&lt;/a&gt; Gates ) where I got to help steer the boat of a Fortune 10 company, I had a number of opportunities that I had to turn down because of it, even though my higher ups went above and beyond to give me as much latitude as possible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had a bunch of crazy project ideas that I wanted to see come to life over the years, I don&amp;rsquo;t think I would have ever had the time to see them become anything more than mythical ideas without this opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, wish me luck, send me work (as I can finally accept it ;-) [through R5 of course]) and look out for some pretty wacky ideas and products that I&amp;rsquo;ve been talking about for years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks again, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be here without you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rob&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking Advice For @Krystropolis</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2015/09-24-hacking-advice-for-krystropolis</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 07:35:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2015/09-24-hacking-advice-for-krystropolis</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I was asked by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/krystropolis&#34;&gt;@Krystropolis&lt;/a&gt; for a &amp;ldquo;Hello&amp;rdquo; and maybe some hacking advice, see tweet:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&#34;twitter-tweet&#34;&gt;&lt;p lang=&#34;en&#34; dir=&#34;ltr&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mubix&#34;&gt;@mubix&lt;/a&gt; I have my class in 4 hours.  Would you be willing to post a &amp;#39;hello&amp;#39; and maybe some hacking advice for my class demo? &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/PSUBehrend?src=hash&#34;&gt;#PSUBehrend&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hashtag/CTF?src=hash&#34;&gt;#CTF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; Krystal Elliott (@krystropolis) &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/krystropolis/status/647070576528502785&#34;&gt;September 24, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async src=&#34;//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&#34; charset=&#34;utf-8&#34;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought about it on my entire 1 hour drive home from just turning in my badge and laptop from a big corporation to go work at a start up. I thought about talking about ethics and data handling, to Geo-politics. I mean, what kind of hacking are we talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally ended up thinking about what would have been the best advice for me, growing up, for &amp;ldquo;how to learn hacking&amp;rdquo;, and I boiled it down right before I pulled into my drive way to two words: &amp;ldquo;Build It&amp;rdquo;. For me personally, I didn&amp;rsquo;t start to really understand attackers, attacks, or even simple defense strategies until I started to try to build it myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many hackers (and mechanics, my father included) they started by taking things a part first, then putting them back together (usually with a few extra screws or parts that &amp;ldquo;didn&amp;rsquo;t matter&amp;rdquo; on the side). But for me, I learned best, by building from scratch. This went from stealing RAM for the &amp;ldquo;old junk&amp;rdquo; computer locker from my high school to upgrade my Mom&amp;rsquo;s 95 Mhz Pentium (OH YA!) - in my defense, the computer science teacher told me that I could take anything I needed to build a computer and he didn&amp;rsquo;t specify the physical location that computer had to be in - all the way to working on the sensor grid for the Marine Corps networks when I helped at the MARCERT as a level 1 tech. I even convinced a few of the Hak5 crew at the time to let me build Gentoo (Stage 3 baby!) on their laptops because it was tons faster (once everything compiled 10 years later).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Man do I ramble. Point is. If you want to learn hacking, or how to hack, you need to know a system inside and out first. &lt;a href=&#34;http://dictionary.reference.com/browse/system&#34;&gt;System (noun)&lt;/a&gt; in it&amp;rsquo;s most basic sense. The best penetration testers / hackers I have ever known are the ones that have rebuilt their labs/phone/widget for the 500th time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE: I have had a few comments, about the post already. But what I forgot to point out is that by building a system or network you not only get to know the ins and outs of how it works, and what shortcuts you had to take to get it to actually work, but also the appreciation of what it took for you to build it, the hours/research that went into it, how it connects to other systems and clients, and finally what kind of business impact it could or does have on actual corporations. These are core skills to be an effective communicator of risk and need, while keeping compassion for the requirements and business impact. Highly sought after skills in the job market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this helps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rob&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Internets Own Boy</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2014/2014-07-10-the-internets-own-boy</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 11:26:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2014/2014-07-10-the-internets-own-boy</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Anyone who knows me knows that I live in a tiny world of offensive security, so much so that I miss large world events entirely. (Like elections and hurricanes)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t know Aaron Swartz, or even 1% of what he was doing in the world to make it a better place and for that I am ashamed. I will do better, to look around, see what needs to be changed in this world and make it a reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is a Documentary about the life of Aaron Swartz. If you live under a similar rock as I, you can start here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aaron_Swartz&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Aaron_Swartz&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch, learn, share, and help continue a legacy that Aaron started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&#34;https://archive.org/embed/TheInternetsOwnBoyTheStoryOfAaronSwartz&#34; width=&#34;640&#34; height=&#34;480&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; webkitallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; mozallowfullscreen=&#34;true&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go home InfoSec, you&#39;re drunk</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2014/2014-05-26-go-home-infosec-youre-drunk</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 11:26:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2014/2014-05-26-go-home-infosec-youre-drunk</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let me start off by saying this post is easy for me to write in one facet as I&amp;rsquo;ve never been a heavy drinker or much enjoyed the taste of alcohol. So if you need a reason to disregard what I say next, I leave the door open.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am still pretty much a runt in the infosec community as I didn&amp;rsquo;t even begin learning computers (outside of playing games on them) until 2005. However, one thing that has nagged at me for a long time is the intertwined nature of hacking/infosec and drinking. Its almost a right of passage in the common fraternity style. The problem lies in the fact that you don&amp;rsquo;t really &amp;ldquo;graduate&amp;rdquo; and leave those parties behind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I have certainly partaken in my share of parties and consumption, even with that nagging feeling in the back of my head. It didn&amp;rsquo;t really take root until just recently. I was at a conference where a student (who was not 21) that looked very much like an older version of my oldest child said that he was going to skip dinner to go get wasted with XYZ &amp;ldquo;Infosec Rockstar&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That scared me into thinking that if my son goes into Infosec he will be basically expected to drink like an alcoholic. How can I want my kid to be expected (not forced) to drink a shot on stage if he gets accepted to speak at DEF CON.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We (the infosec community) are few, and we loose too many to idiotic things like drug overdose, drinking and driving, and other stupidly preventable crap&lt;/strong&gt;. For that reason I actually don&amp;rsquo;t want to share the thing I feel so passionate about with my own kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My call to action is this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are a conference goer&lt;/strong&gt;, try going one con completely dry, and if you already do, maybe ask friend to join you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are speaker&lt;/strong&gt;, enough of the drinks on stage and drinking games. Do you really want the next generation, those you are trying to teach, to remember that part of your talk instead of the rest?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are a conference organizer&lt;/strong&gt;, maybe a completely dry day at the con? or an AA meeting space?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are a podcaster&lt;/strong&gt;, if you drink during the cast, make it about the taste and selection, instead of how wasted and totally useless the next hour of your listeners life will be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ShmooCon runs an AA meeting at the con&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets stop losing our friends and family because we are too weak to say &amp;lsquo;no thank you&amp;rsquo; when someone approaches the dais with a shot.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brass Tax on Chrome</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-09-03-200893brass-tax-on-chrome-html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 15:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-09-03-200893brass-tax-on-chrome-html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So there is already an exploit: &lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.zdnet.com/security/?p=1843&#34;&gt;http://blogs.zdnet.com/security/?p=1843&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are naysayers: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tgdaily.com/content/view/39154/108/&#34;&gt;http://www.tgdaily.com/content/view/39154/108/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there is the truth: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.stillsecureafteralltheseyears.com/ashimmy/2008/09/sucking-the-chr.html&#34;&gt;http://www.stillsecureafteralltheseyears.com/ashimmy/2008/09/sucking-the-chr.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like the design of the tabs and address bar, but I can do that with a theme in firefox. I want my add-ons, even with the memory problems. Chrome is great for Mom and Pap, but for “Internet Power Users” it falls lightyears short on features. So where is the brass tax?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;IMHO:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firefox &amp;gt; (INSERT CHROME HERE) &amp;gt; Opera &amp;gt; Safari &amp;gt; IE7 &amp;gt; IE8 &amp;gt; IE6&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other news: Yousif Yalda has made it to the coveted “Stupid People” link category, where until now was solely held by Ashley Park.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the hits just keep rolling in:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.milw0rm.com/exploits/6353&#34;&gt;http://www.milw0rm.com/exploits/6353&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ndash; DoS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://evilfingers.com/advisory/google_chrome_poc.php&#34;&gt;http://evilfingers.com/advisory/google_chrome_poc.php&lt;/a&gt; - Original PoC for DoS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blogs.zdnet.com/security/?p=1847&#34;&gt;http://blogs.zdnet.com/security/?p=1847&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://erratasec.blogspot.com/2008/09/lookingglass-vendor-of-week-google.html&#34;&gt;http://erratasec.blogspot.com/2008/09/lookingglass-vendor-of-week-google.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sunbeltblog.blogspot.com/2008/09/chrome-rocks-i-dont-care-what-others.html&#34;&gt;http://sunbeltblog.blogspot.com/2008/09/chrome-rocks-i-dont-care-what-others.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AUTOMATIC DOWNLOADS? What?!&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.milw0rm.com/exploits/6355&#34;&gt;http://www.milw0rm.com/exploits/6355&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where do people find the time?</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-08-06-200886where-do-people-find-the-time-html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2008 06:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-08-06-200886where-do-people-find-the-time-html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently was Stumbling and happened across the following video. Now, when people use StumbleUpon they are usually bored and aren’t really contributing to the world as we know it. It strikes me as ironic that I found and watched a video like this, via StumbleUpon. I promise, it is well worth the fraction of a wikipedia project cycle you will utilize on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite quote out of the whole deal: “Media that is made for you, but does not include you, is not worth sitting still for”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Original Link: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.clusterflock.org/2008/04/where-do-people-find-the-time.html&#34;&gt;http://www.clusterflock.org/2008/04/where-do-people-find-the-time.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part 1:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[youtube=&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AyoNHIl-QLQ&amp;amp;w;=425&amp;amp;h;=344&#34;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=AyoNHIl-QLQ&amp;amp;w;=425&amp;amp;h;=344&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part 2:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[youtube=&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jNCblGv0zjU&amp;amp;w;=425&amp;amp;h;=344&#34;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jNCblGv0zjU&amp;amp;w;=425&amp;amp;h;=344&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comcast Cares?</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-07-22-2008722comcast-cares-html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 17:28:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-07-22-2008722comcast-cares-html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So after my last post, which autotwittered, I got a reply from a guy by the name of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.google.com/search?hl=en&amp;amp;q=Frank+Eliason&amp;amp;btnG=Google+Search&#34;&gt;Frank Eliason&lt;/a&gt;, who goes by the handle “&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/comcastcares&#34;&gt;ComcastCares&lt;/a&gt;” on Twitter. And this is how the converation went:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mubix: Blogged Comcast: The start of a new series &lt;a href=&#34;http://tinyurl.com/6jrvhe&#34;&gt;http://tinyurl.com/6jrvhe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5 days ago&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;comcastcares: @mubix I would like to help. Email me *********[snipped]@cable.comcast.com (new email: &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:We_Can_Help@cable.comcast.com?subject=I%20have%20a%20problem%20with%20comcast%20%20can%20you%20help%3F%20-%20Referred%20by%20Room362.com&#34;&gt;We_Can_Help@cable.comcast.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5 days ago&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mubix: @comcastcares it shouldn’t come to the point where you need to help. I expect a certain level of service for the golf time I am paying for&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;about 3 hours later&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;comcastcares: @mubix The golf time?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 minutes later&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mubix: @comcastcares the premium that I pay monthly helps pay for Comcast execs trips to the golf course&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;about 1 hour later&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;comcastcares: @mubix Oh! I have not been golfing in a long time. Actually I do not know any golfers here. I guess I should make more friends&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So after I’m done insulting the guy, he still goes out of his way to help me out. The very next day after this twitter conversation happens, a “gumbling” as my wife put it, contractor came to my house and put the cable in the ground. So I would like to give notice to Comcast: Frank Eliason is the best employee you have, if he every leaves or gets fired, I’m switching providers. To those who have problems with Comcast and their customer support, click the email link above and Frank will fix any problem you have, or at the very least he will know who to contact and with get things actually moving.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you Frank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mubix&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone Apps vs iPhone Web Apps</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-07-21-2008721iphone-apps-vs-iphone-web-apps-html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2008 03:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-07-21-2008721iphone-apps-vs-iphone-web-apps-html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am truely getting tired of iPhone &amp;ldquo;Web Apps&amp;rdquo;. I created the title like I was going to give them a fair chance, but they truely have ZERO integration into the actual phone. They do have a pretty interface and I have to give props to some of the design developers, but does this seem more of a copout to anyone else?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll give an example. I LOVE Remember the Milk. It is probably the best task system out there in my opinion. I have for the longest time tried to get tasks on my phone and have it integrate into my calendar. So I was very excited about the new iPhone and the possibility that there would be a killer app for calendar / todo syncing with the service I already love, RTM. To my shock I found they had a Web App. What does this do for me? I now can add tasks to my to do and RTM can email or text me when something comes up. I find this pointless, because I can simply add tasks with a full qwerty keyboard at the nearest computer with a internet connection. PLUS to add to it, RTM wants me to &amp;ldquo;Go Pro&amp;rdquo; in order to&amp;hellip; use their WEBSITE? Hmm, pay 25 dollars and use their iPhone friendly web site, or just use their normal site from my iPhone&amp;hellip;. I am not against paying for a product, and I am especially not against supporting a developer, but don&amp;rsquo;t make me pay for VISITING YOUR WEB SITE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel that a lot of these &amp;ldquo;Web Apps&amp;rdquo; are a complete waste of developers time, instead give me an ACTUAL iPhone App! Now, if Apple is charging all kinds of money to be published to the App Store than I retract all I have said. If not, you are missing the boat people, charge 9.99 a pop and make an iPhone app that is worth downloading. I promise that I won&amp;rsquo;t be the only one pushing that &amp;ldquo;Purchase&amp;rdquo; button.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comcast: The start of a new series</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-07-17-2008717comcast-the-start-of-a-new-series-html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2008 02:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-07-17-2008717comcast-the-start-of-a-new-series-html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now, I don’t like to publicly bad mouth companies, but at some point, Comcast’s lack of “service” has got to stop. Well, let me rephrase that: Comcast needs to be held accountable for their utter lack of due diligence. I have been a Comcast customer by default ever since they swallowed the portion of Adelphia that held my area. I say this because only recently, have I actually had a choice in the matter. So, without further ado, here is my latest Tales from Comcast Customer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having recently moved, I decided that even though I have a choice, incurring additional “setup” fees for switching services was not something I wanted. So they guy was there 5 days after I moved in, ran the line, and we were hot with both digital cable, and speedy internet service. I came home from work, ran some speed tests and was delighted to see that I had just almost tripled my speeds from my previous residence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weeks go by, and this line that the Comcast installer ran from the box to my house is still strung across my lawn. I call and they say they will send someone out to put it down as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 months later, I call again; they cannot see in their system that a request to put a line in the ground was ever submitted. After 20 minutes of trying to ensure that the “Customer Service Representative” fully understood that there was actually, physically, an orange coaxial line, above ground, strung across my front lawn, that was Comcast’s responsibility, she submitted a new request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1 week after the new request, I come home to a Comcast truck in the driveway. YIPEE!, nope, he was there to fill out the request for a contractor to come and put the line in the ground. So basically he had no purpose in life or in my driveway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2 weeks after the new request, no contractor, but someone at some point came by my house and spray painted lines on my lawn where my line should be in the ground. (And no, I didn’t miss a call or the contractor coming)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3 weeks after the new request, the wife is fed up and she has me call Comcast after our TV goes out for no apparent reason. Guess what I got when I called? A busy signal. That just doesn’t compute in my head. How is Comcast going to present me with a busy signal for a 24 hour service line? Anyways, the next day I call and actually get through. Now guess what they told me? Nope, they had the request, but it was for September!? The “Customer Service Representative” was nice enough to move it up to this Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To Be Continued&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this event has run its course, it will be filed under “Stupid People” in the links menu, under “Tales of a Comcast Customer: EP1”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am Jack&#39;s unpropitious excitement</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-06-11-2008611i-am-jacks-unpropitious-excitement-html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 18:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-06-11-2008611i-am-jacks-unpropitious-excitement-html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I have to apologize to the whole Security community for my idiocy. Yesterday I was made aware of a post about Backtrack 3 Final coming out. The link I received was a link to Mut’s blog. While reading the post it mentioned something about an early IRC release. Proceeding to IRC I found a direct link to the ISO in the topic. Excited about the release I failed to read the rest of the topic in IRC mentioning that they wanted it to stay within the IRC community. I then started sending out a link to Mut’s post, and the link to the ISO out to my friends and the Wifi Sec mailing list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today at some point the ISO was pulled offline, according to an email I received, due to my Wifi Sec posting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am sorry to everyone in the Remote Exploit community, and especially Mutts, Max, and MjM. So, if you read this and see me at one of the conferences. Mention this post’s title and I owe you a beer.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft making secret power plays?</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-06-08-200868microsoft-making-secret-power-plays-html</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2008 04:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-06-08-200868microsoft-making-secret-power-plays-html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I have been hearing a lot of innovators posting to their blogs that they are pursuing new employment with Microsoft, and I wonder if they are making sneaky power plays into the Open Source market. Taking it’s best projects and plucking their leads. For example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;KnoppMyth Creator:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mysettopbox.tv/index.html#News&#34;&gt;http://mysettopbox.tv/index.html#News&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT&lt;/strong&gt;: The above article seems to be an April Fools joke that I was late to the party on. Thanks to Mark for calling me out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Castle Cops - Owner/Operator - Paul Laudanski&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.castlecops.com/t223152-Must_Read_Important_Announcement.html&#34;&gt;http://www.castlecops.com/t223152-Must_Read_Important_Announcement.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, don’t get me wrong, everyone needs their family and Open Source is a thankless job sometimes. I am not trying to dog on them for going Microsoft. I am just wondering if they are doing this to give these gents a job and make their product better, or just get rid of supporting competition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just my rant on what I am seeing. Sounds a bit like dvorak.org/blog eh?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; mubix&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creators of New</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-06-06-200866creators-of-new-html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 03:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-06-06-200866creators-of-new-html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;What happens when the lights go out. Power is gone and all you have left is your thoughts and a laptop that’s battery is quickly dieing? You write. Movies will take up too much power and it’s too dark to read so you write. What do you write about, does it really matter? You write.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a part of a great many projects but I can’t say that I have contributed to them very much. But I would like to in this post, since I have the time all of a sudden, take the time to acknowledge the real people who are making things happen:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of we have Roelof Temmingh. His hard work and dedication to his project Maltego has created something as revolutionary as the search engine. Now, you may say that that is one hell of a statement and shouldn’t be tossed around like an Emmy. I am here to assure you I am not. Just as ArcSight, if implemented correctly and cared for is one of the greatest tools a Information System Incident Responder can have, Maltego is the information gatherer’s most valuable asset. From Intel bubbas to Social Engineers to Private Investigators. This tool is not something you can live without any longer. Why? Because your opponent is already using it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paterva.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.paterva.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next project I would like to talk about is the WiFi Security mailing list. Dninja and Joshua Wright as some of the brightest minds in the field of 802.11. Joshua Wright is well recognized, but I think Dninja is less so. Both Josh and Dninja are working on incorporating Karma into embedded devices, mainly the Fon Router. The Fon is a extremely small form factor router that still has enough embedded memory to be useful for modding. Their continued research, by all of those in the WiFi Security mailing list, directly impact the 802.11 field. That impact is seen in the increased security we are seeing in WiFi devices and software every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.securityfocus.com/archive/137/description&#34;&gt;http://www.securityfocus.com/archive/137/description&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Mal-Aware team. Lance James and the gents over at Castle Cops are the main players in this team but collaboration from around the world is done on these mailing lists. Closely working with the FBI and other federal and foreign agencies. The brain power that make up the list of email addresses joined together in this list could swell any room. Like mythological super heroes, they dedicate their free time to making the internet a safer place each and every day. [&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mal-aware.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.mal-aware.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;](&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mal-aware.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.mal-aware.org/&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last but not least is the crew over at Hak.5. Darren, Wess, Ally, Paul, and the latest addition Matt. I probably wouldn’t be as ingrained in the “Hacker” world as I am now without these guys. The videos they produce on such a limited budget are entertaining and, in my opinion, rival the professionalism of Hollywood. What they produce is always innovative and informative. Even if they mod the Guitar Hero guitar every other episode. Even though they criticism from all angles, they continue to produce and put out a video podcast that is as of yet unmatched in it’s market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hak5.org&#34;&gt;http://www.hak5.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The reason I am writing this post, other than boredom, is to sort of tip my hat in humility to these innovators. Some of the readers of my blog think highly of me. I wish only to transfer that respect to those who deserve it. I am humbled to be apart of such amazing projects and be witness to their impact on the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Rob Fuller (a.k.a. Mubix)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. So basically, buy Maltego (or get your company/school to), join the WiFi Sec and Mal-Aware mailing lists, and watch Hak.5. Support these projects in any way you can, because they have already supported you in one way or another.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oregon Offers Tuition Waiver</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-05-06-200856oregon-offers-tuition-waiver-html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2008 06:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-05-06-200856oregon-offers-tuition-waiver-html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Oregon’s State Legislature passed a law that provides a full-tuition waiver for a bachelor’s or master’s degree at an Oregon University System institution for children or spouses of service members who died on active duty, became 100 percent disabled in connection with military service, or died as a result of a disability sustained on active duty&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My home state rocks.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.military.com/veterans-report/oregon-offers-tuition-waiver?ESRC=vr.nl&#34;&gt;Military.com’s Writeup&lt;/a&gt; | &lt;a href=&#34;http://digg.com/world_news/Oregon_Offers_Tuition_Waiver&#34;&gt;digg this story&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook chat - All that and a bag of cheesy poofs</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-04-23-2008423facebook-chat-all-that-and-a-bag-of-cheesy-poofs-html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 21:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-04-23-2008423facebook-chat-all-that-and-a-bag-of-cheesy-poofs-html</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wow. I have to admit, they did the Facebook chat right. I like how it looks and how it works. I would only change one this and allow chats to disembark from the status bar, but other than that, congrats. It is actually keeping me on Facebook longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://s3.media.squarespace.com/production/438411/4879756/uploads/logo_facebook-rgb-7inch.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enough brown nosing, here are the pros and cons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRO&lt;/strong&gt;: very well done layout - clean, crisp and not in the way&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CON&lt;/strong&gt;: I have no idea when one of my friends sign on or off, it would be nice to have to show something simple as - Bob signed on, and have it as an option to turn off for those who have reached their 5000 friend limit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PRO&lt;/strong&gt;: I now have access to all of those old friends and people that I have lost touch with over the years and didn’t know their email or IM address. This was already the case, but IMs are much more inviting to use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;CON&lt;/strong&gt;: Like I said above, it would be nice if I could dock and undock the IM windows. being stuck to the bottom kinda gets annoying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still think that Facebook is littered with a lot of useless apps and spam, but the IM ability is helping to ween me back into trying and cleaning up my profile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT&lt;/strong&gt;:Alright, either the Facebook code really fast, or I just didn’t know where to click, but I have been corrected. You can undock the IM interfcae by clicking on the shiloutte and clicking “Pop Out Chat”. This will create a new window and put all of your chatting in the new window. After you are done being pop’ed out, just click Pop-In on the upper right and you are back to normal. While this isn’t the 100% solution I was looking for (Ajax floating chat boxes that could be together or seperate or tabbed)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>