<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rant on </title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/tags/rant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rant on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 11:30:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://malicious.link/tags/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Few Changes</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2018/a-few-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jul 2018 11:30:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2018/a-few-changes/</guid>
      <description>For nearly a year I left a CoinHive miner up on the blog so that people that didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like or couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford a way to support the blog could do so via a bit of CPU power. Unfortunately during that time lots of malware started to use services like coinhive and I quickly started recieving warning that my site had been &amp;ldquo;hacked&amp;rdquo; or was showing up as malicious (har har).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2015/time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 12:02:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2015/time/</guid>
      <description>Time is a one-time non-renewable precious resource you are given. It is ok to be greedy, selective, and even snobbish about how, and with whom you spend it.
If it helps, think of your time as a vault, money is withdrawn at a constant rate by people as you spend it, but you are not allowed to look inside to see how much you have left. It could be a billion dollars, it could be .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R5 Industries</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2015/r5-industries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 12:02:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2015/r5-industries/</guid>
      <description>I recently took the plunge and joined a startup called R5 Industries. I wanted to say thanks for all the well wishes that I received on social media. It has certainly calmed my nerves about the choice ;-).
I&amp;rsquo;ve had a number of people ask what R5 Industries does. Our primary selling point is AntigenC2, which is a really Command and Control detection product (no agents). But we also do Red Team assessments and some other fun toys if you are interested, contact@r5industries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hacking Advice For @Krystropolis</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2015/hacking-advice-for-krystropolis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2015 07:35:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2015/hacking-advice-for-krystropolis/</guid>
      <description>Today I was asked by @Krystropolis for a &amp;ldquo;Hello&amp;rdquo; and maybe some hacking advice, see tweet:
@mubix I have my class in 4 hours. Would you be willing to post a &amp;#39;hello&amp;#39; and maybe some hacking advice for my class demo? #PSUBehrend #CTF
&amp;mdash; Krystal Elliott (@krystropolis) September 24, 2015  I thought about it on my entire 1 hour drive home from just turning in my badge and laptop from a big corporation to go work at a start up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Internets Own Boy</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2014/the-internets-own-boy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 11:26:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2014/the-internets-own-boy/</guid>
      <description>Anyone who knows me knows that I live in a tiny world of offensive security, so much so that I miss large world events entirely. (Like elections and hurricanes)
I didn&amp;rsquo;t know Aaron Swartz, or even 1% of what he was doing in the world to make it a better place and for that I am ashamed. I will do better, to look around, see what needs to be changed in this world and make it a reality.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go home InfoSec, you&#39;re drunk</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2014/go-home-infosec-youre-drunk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 May 2014 11:26:38 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2014/go-home-infosec-youre-drunk/</guid>
      <description>Let me start off by saying this post is easy for me to write in one facet as I&amp;rsquo;ve never been a heavy drinker or much enjoyed the taste of alcohol. So if you need a reason to disregard what I say next, I leave the door open.
I am still pretty much a runt in the infosec community as I didn&amp;rsquo;t even begin learning computers (outside of playing games on them) until 2005.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brass Tax on Chrome</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2008/200893brass-tax-on-chrome-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2008 15:58:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2008/200893brass-tax-on-chrome-html/</guid>
      <description>So there is already an exploit: http://blogs.zdnet.com/security/?p=1843
There are naysayers: http://www.tgdaily.com/content/view/39154/108/
And then there is the truth: http://www.stillsecureafteralltheseyears.com/ashimmy/2008/09/sucking-the-chr.html
I like the design of the tabs and address bar, but I can do that with a theme in firefox. I want my add-ons, even with the memory problems. Chrome is great for Mom and Pap, but for “Internet Power Users” it falls lightyears short on features. So where is the brass tax?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where do people find the time?</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2008/200886where-do-people-find-the-time-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2008 06:34:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2008/200886where-do-people-find-the-time-html/</guid>
      <description>I recently was Stumbling and happened across the following video. Now, when people use StumbleUpon they are usually bored and aren’t really contributing to the world as we know it. It strikes me as ironic that I found and watched a video like this, via StumbleUpon. I promise, it is well worth the fraction of a wikipedia project cycle you will utilize on it.
My favorite quote out of the whole deal: “Media that is made for you, but does not include you, is not worth sitting still for”</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comcast Cares?</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2008/2008722comcast-cares-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 17:28:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2008/2008722comcast-cares-html/</guid>
      <description>So after my last post, which autotwittered, I got a reply from a guy by the name of Frank Eliason, who goes by the handle “ComcastCares” on Twitter. And this is how the converation went:
mubix: Blogged Comcast: The start of a new series http://tinyurl.com/6jrvhe
5 days ago
comcastcares: @mubix I would like to help. Email me *********[snipped]@cable.comcast.com (new email: We_Can_Help@cable.comcast.com)
5 days ago
mubix: @comcastcares it shouldn’t come to the point where you need to help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone Apps vs iPhone Web Apps</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2008/2008721iphone-apps-vs-iphone-web-apps-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2008 03:42:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2008/2008721iphone-apps-vs-iphone-web-apps-html/</guid>
      <description>I am truely getting tired of iPhone &amp;ldquo;Web Apps&amp;rdquo;. I created the title like I was going to give them a fair chance, but they truely have ZERO integration into the actual phone. They do have a pretty interface and I have to give props to some of the design developers, but does this seem more of a copout to anyone else?
I&amp;rsquo;ll give an example. I LOVE Remember the Milk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comcast: The start of a new series</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2008/2008717comcast-the-start-of-a-new-series-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jul 2008 02:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2008/2008717comcast-the-start-of-a-new-series-html/</guid>
      <description>Now, I don’t like to publicly bad mouth companies, but at some point, Comcast’s lack of “service” has got to stop. Well, let me rephrase that: Comcast needs to be held accountable for their utter lack of due diligence. I have been a Comcast customer by default ever since they swallowed the portion of Adelphia that held my area. I say this because only recently, have I actually had a choice in the matter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I am Jack&#39;s unpropitious excitement</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2008/2008611i-am-jacks-unpropitious-excitement-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2008 18:07:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2008/2008611i-am-jacks-unpropitious-excitement-html/</guid>
      <description>So, I have to apologize to the whole Security community for my idiocy. Yesterday I was made aware of a post about Backtrack 3 Final coming out. The link I received was a link to Mut’s blog. While reading the post it mentioned something about an early IRC release. Proceeding to IRC I found a direct link to the ISO in the topic. Excited about the release I failed to read the rest of the topic in IRC mentioning that they wanted it to stay within the IRC community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft making secret power plays?</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2008/200868microsoft-making-secret-power-plays-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2008 04:04:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2008/200868microsoft-making-secret-power-plays-html/</guid>
      <description>Recently I have been hearing a lot of innovators posting to their blogs that they are pursuing new employment with Microsoft, and I wonder if they are making sneaky power plays into the Open Source market. Taking it’s best projects and plucking their leads. For example:
KnoppMyth Creator:
http://mysettopbox.tv/index.html#News
EDIT: The above article seems to be an April Fools joke that I was late to the party on. Thanks to Mark for calling me out.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creators of New</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2008/200866creators-of-new-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2008 03:47:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2008/200866creators-of-new-html/</guid>
      <description>What happens when the lights go out. Power is gone and all you have left is your thoughts and a laptop that’s battery is quickly dieing? You write. Movies will take up too much power and it’s too dark to read so you write. What do you write about, does it really matter? You write.
I am a part of a great many projects but I can’t say that I have contributed to them very much.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oregon Offers Tuition Waiver</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2008/200856oregon-offers-tuition-waiver-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2008 06:42:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2008/200856oregon-offers-tuition-waiver-html/</guid>
      <description>Oregon’s State Legislature passed a law that provides a full-tuition waiver for a bachelor’s or master’s degree at an Oregon University System institution for children or spouses of service members who died on active duty, became 100 percent disabled in connection with military service, or died as a result of a disability sustained on active duty
My home state rocks.
Military.com’s Writeup | digg this story</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook chat - All that and a bag of cheesy poofs</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2008/2008423facebook-chat-all-that-and-a-bag-of-cheesy-poofs-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2008 21:35:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2008/2008423facebook-chat-all-that-and-a-bag-of-cheesy-poofs-html/</guid>
      <description>Wow. I have to admit, they did the Facebook chat right. I like how it looks and how it works. I would only change one this and allow chats to disembark from the status bar, but other than that, congrats. It is actually keeping me on Facebook longer.
Enough brown nosing, here are the pros and cons:
PRO: very well done layout - clean, crisp and not in the way</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KVM MITM</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2008/200826kvm-mitm-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Feb 2008 21:27:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2008/200826kvm-mitm-html/</guid>
      <description>I’ve had an idea and I have been hashing it out the last couple days. I want a smal piece of hardware that runs basically a MITM, but a physical one. Something like those old keyloggers that you plug between a PS/2 keyboard and a computer. If it already exsists, please link me, but this is what I want it to do:
Features of the KVM-MITM:
 Ports: (2) DVI or VGA; (2) Ethernet NICs; (4) USB or/and (4) PS/2 Ports &amp;lt;&amp;ndash; Half male, Half female</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Too busy to breath</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2008/2008123too-busy-to-breath-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2008 18:02:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2008/2008123too-busy-to-breath-html/</guid>
      <description>This is me complaining that I have too much on my plate. And, it is all my fault that I accepted so much. Here are the projects I currently am working on:
 Hak.5 Radio - This project has taken on a life of it’s own, the community member run it and are currently working on a site design and back end. I really have to applaud the effort and free time that everyone on the H5rDev team has put into making the only community radio station on the net so sucessful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This is only a Test</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2007/20071116this-is-only-a-test-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2007 03:50:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2007/20071116this-is-only-a-test-html/</guid>
      <description>This is a test of the EMERGENCY SBN, This is only a test. If this was a real security emergency, the FBI would contact you.
 Thank you for your patience.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>They let me in. Muhaha</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2007/20071030they-let-me-in-muhaha-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2007 01:35:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2007/20071030they-let-me-in-muhaha-html/</guid>
      <description>Proud member of Security Bloggers Network, a FeedBurner Network.
The fools&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Time to shape up.</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2007/20071029time-to-shape-up-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 21:01:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2007/20071029time-to-shape-up-html/</guid>
      <description>A while ago I said that I was going to start putting more security related articles up. Well, it&amp;rsquo;s now on the wire. I have applied to join the Security Blogger&amp;rsquo;s Network. So a lot more people than just the Hak.5 crew are going to possibly be reading this blog. I may or may not be chosen to join the network, but if I do, it should be an wild ride.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History is MAD</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2007/20071029history-is-mad-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Oct 2007 18:03:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2007/20071029history-is-mad-html/</guid>
      <description>It is not often, especially this day in age, that shakes one to the core. This is one of those times. Original Source: http://www.eightcitiesmap.com/transcript_bc.htm
DR BILL COSBY SPEAKS at the 50th Anniversary commemoration of the Brown vs Topeka Board of Education Supreme Court Decision Ladies and gentlemen, I really have to ask you to seriously consider what you&amp;rsquo;ve heard, and now this is the end of the evening so to speak.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>because I learned linux</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2007/20071010because-i-learned-linux-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Oct 2007 21:06:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2007/20071010because-i-learned-linux-html/</guid>
      <description>I am in training right now and the instructor made a funny, which I will probably be making into a shirt.
 &amp;ldquo;I no longer have to work out to impress women. I learned Linux&amp;rdquo;
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>George Carlin does Religion</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2007/2007109george-carlin-does-religion-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2007 11:08:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2007/2007109george-carlin-does-religion-html/</guid>
      <description>George Carlin is funny. Offensive to most everyone, but I think the whole &amp;ldquo;I hate everyone, so it&amp;rsquo;s not an &amp;lsquo;ism&amp;rsquo; thing&amp;rdquo; works here. Here he is on the topic of Religion: [youtube http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MeSSwKffj9o]</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Questions that need answering.</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2007/2007108questions-that-need-answering-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Oct 2007 04:51:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2007/2007108questions-that-need-answering-html/</guid>
      <description>QUESTIONS ********* Why do you need a driver&amp;rsquo;s license to buy liquor in America when you can&amp;rsquo;t drink and drive? Why isn&amp;rsquo;t phonetic spelled the way it sounds? Why are there interstate highways in Hawaii? Why are there flotation devices under plane seats instead of parachutes? Why are cigarettes sold in gas stations when smoking is prohibited there? Do you need a silencer if you are going to shoot a mime?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multicast and some random thoughts</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2007/200761multicast-and-some-random-thoughts-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2007 12:56:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2007/200761multicast-and-some-random-thoughts-html/</guid>
      <description>So I am a complete noob when it comes to multicast and recently I have been hearing about it more and more. I know it&amp;rsquo;s been out there since the dawn of time but I simply thought it was a way of broadcasting video across the network. WRONG. So for those who don&amp;rsquo;t know, and correct me if I am wrong, a computer or device sends out a multicast packet headed for a 244.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NAC in use</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2007/2007418nac-in-use-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2007 16:32:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2007/2007418nac-in-use-html/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was listening to Episode 66 of PaulDotCom Security Weekly and they briefly touched on Packetfence. Packet Fence is a Open Source NAC. This is the first time that I have really gotten hand on a NAC. I have heard of NAC and at ShmooCon Labs, I was part of Simple Nomad&amp;rsquo;s team and Vernier&amp;rsquo;s IPS/NAC. However, I didn&amp;rsquo;t get a chance to get hands on during the con. So that puts me in the &amp;ldquo;noob&amp;rdquo; category.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On a RANT</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2007/2007221on-a-rant-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2007 15:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2007/2007221on-a-rant-html/</guid>
      <description>First of all, every blog entry on every blog, is in fact a RANT. So, stating that one is, is kind of pointless. That being said. Here is my rant:
Now that I have changed this part of my blogisphere, I have been getting guff about not covering certain exploits and 0-days. So here it is:
Microsoft Excel 0-day
The easiest way to make a unix based system (Mac) insecure:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas, New Years and a Keychain</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2006/20061228christmas-new-years-and-a-keychain-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2006 15:59:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2006/20061228christmas-new-years-and-a-keychain-html/</guid>
      <description>Boss! I can&#39;t come in today. I woke up this morning and found 20 inches of snow in front of my drive way. Don&#39;t we all wish it was this simple. Anyways, I went home for Christmas, back to Oregon. Had a good time, got some good presents, yup... everything was good. New Years is coming up. 2007... yeah, the whole millennium thing is wearing off. As for the key chain, I got a cool skeleton key chain for Christmas that is almost impossible to fit in my pocket, but oh so worth it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>12 Hour Shifts</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2005/12-hour-shifts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2005 12:34:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2005/12-hour-shifts/</guid>
      <description>I have officially determined 12 hour shifts suck. Whoever invented this crazy idea needs to be shot! Oh! I’ve got an idea! Instead of 3 people per day, which allowed all three to have proper recoup time, lets make it just 2 on a 12 on, 12 off schedule! We can use that employee somewhere else! Sound like an issue of Dilbert? Yeah, I thought so too.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New &#34;Advanced&#34; Error system for Windows Vista</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2005/new-advanced-error-system-for-windows-vista/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2005 11:46:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2005/new-advanced-error-system-for-windows-vista/</guid>
      <description>This and more Atom Smasher&amp;rsquo;s Error Message Gallery</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gentoo enters the 21st Century</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2005/gentoo-enters-the-21st-century/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2005 01:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2005/gentoo-enters-the-21st-century/</guid>
      <description>Let me be the first to welcome Gentoo into the 21st Century. Creating an Installer instead of a 40 page &amp;lsquo;Handbook&amp;rsquo; was a bold and innovative move. In this bold move they have enticed new blood to this awesome distro such as the renowned Silent_Bob who now goes under the alias thesb to avoid FBI and CIA warrants, but that is another story altogether. (Which I will follow-up on if you, the reader, comment and tell me to) But back to Gentoo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to the Basics</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2005/back-to-the-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2005 04:11:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2005/back-to-the-basics/</guid>
      <description>Age of Empires II - Age of Kings. That is a great game. It has something that not a lot of games have these days, which is replay value. Once you beat a game, that is it. No more fun. You know all the secrets.
That is where MMORPG came into the picture. But still most of them are still lacking. You can get to Level 60 or Level 70 and you have reached the top.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>