<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rant on Room362</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/rant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rant on Room362</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 15:30:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplicity is Security</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009813simplicity-is-security-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 15:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009813simplicity-is-security-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Per the best of the best in presenting, what breeds a good presentation slide deck? Simplicity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to pose a statement. &amp;ldquo;Simplicity is Security&amp;rdquo;. The reason I say this is that this day in age, at least in the US, &amp;lsquo;convenience&amp;rsquo; is king. And we try to protect those conveniences with &amp;lsquo;security&amp;rsquo;. Let me start over a bit, this train of thought all started when I started to explain the insecurities in WiMAX to my wife. We saw a WiMAX device that plugged straight into your computer. I told her this was bad because by connecting to this you have no barrier between you and the &amp;lsquo;bad guys&amp;rsquo; other than possibly the Windows Firewall. Her answer surprised me. &amp;lsquo;So?&amp;rsquo; is all she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Japan doesn&amp;rsquo;t use &amp;lsquo;Check Cards&amp;rsquo; or even really credit cards for that matter. To get such a card you need to go through a book worth of paper work, so it&amp;rsquo;s just not &amp;lsquo;convenient&amp;rsquo; for most people, so they don&amp;rsquo;t get them. So guess what? They don&amp;rsquo;t bank online, and they don&amp;rsquo;t buy stuff online. I racked my brain to figure out what possibly could be on her computer that a &amp;lsquo;bad guy&amp;rsquo; would want. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of anything (maybe you can). The government relies on paper backups of anything electronic (so they hardly make electronic versions). Signatures are based on stamps that are difficult to copy. The worst a hacker could do on her computer is use it as a zombie, and even then, their ISPs detect and disconnect excessive use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where did we as &amp;ldquo;Security Professionals&amp;rdquo; go wrong? Was it the fat paychecks we wanted? Was it the fear of the &amp;lsquo;underground&amp;rsquo;? Reality seems to dictate that we will continue on this path from the analog to the digital, from paper and clerks to networks and AI. The question I want to ask you though is; Should we continue down the path of &amp;ldquo;MORE SECURITY&amp;rdquo; or should we deviate a bit for simpler, possibly non-technical practices?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In these last two posts you may assume that I favor the Japanese culture and way of life over a US one. You would be mistaken, I simply learn, take the best parts of what I learn, and try to apply them where I can. Learning from others triumphs and defeats, strengths and weaknesses is a basic human function that we a humanoids should embrace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applied Network Security Density</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009812applied-network-security-density-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 15:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009812applied-network-security-density-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently visited Tokyo, Japan. Just as always, my curiosity got the best of me and I started to calculate the population density of the buildings where I was staying. Giving fudge factor of non-populated apartments, I estimated 8,500 families in twelve 15 story buildings, living in a 1.5 mile square piece of land.That&amp;rsquo;s CRAZY. Mass transit and unrestricted modes of transit are not a whim, they are a requirement. I bet you&amp;rsquo;re asking how this applies to security, or for that matter computers at all. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t. But one of it&amp;rsquo;s effects does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an effect of this density, the Mom &amp;amp; Pap stores businesses flourish. In it&amp;rsquo;s density, the &amp;ldquo;big iron&amp;rdquo; is just too inconvenient, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. I used the reference for a reason. It was my own mental bridge between the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; and security world (anyone who denies the difference is confused, and/or just left DefCon).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the &amp;ldquo;Big Iron&amp;rdquo; in the security world? Central management, Correlation, and other ways of supposedly spending &amp;ldquo;less&amp;rdquo; on security by having less points of failure. So this is where I stray from the path. I think that networks need to mimic their worldly equivalent. Large organizations need to take an page from Tokyo and decentralize. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s hard getting &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; people, and trust is not something we easily come by in this industry, but from an offensive point of view, centralization just means a bigger payoff. Higher walls, maybe, but an &amp;lsquo;easier&amp;rsquo; target to zero in on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does this mean? I eluded to it a bit in my previous paragraph, but what it means is more hands on. We need to train the &amp;lsquo;security guards&amp;rsquo; of our network and put them at every location we have a grouping of nodes. The smaller the grouping of nodes the better. VLANs are not enough. I&amp;rsquo;m going to use the the dreaded &amp;ldquo;Defense in Depth&amp;rdquo; phrase: We need to make our defense in depth smaller, more compact. Make it to the point where you don&amp;rsquo;t NEED &amp;ldquo;Big Iron&amp;rdquo; because you have such small perimeters that open source stuff on an old *nix box would work just fine. Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an exaggeration but you get the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every city is different and unique, as is any network, and I am by no means saying that decentralization is for everyone. What I do think is that big organizations are getting too hung up on devices and one stop shops where they can set up a NOC and expect a number, however many, of people to be able to watch everything going on. Exactly the way that corporations lose touch with their employees because of their size, they are loosing touch with their network and how it works. How many places have you worked that they have a good diagram of nodes (not just subnets) on their network? Much less documentation on those nodes. How exactly are you supposed to centrally monitor something you have very little knowledge of? Will it take as many years as it did with personnel to reconnect with the life of the network? Probably, but I hope not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, I am open to debate and hearing about flaws in my logic, so please leave a comment and tell me what you think.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sexism and the religion of hackers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009713sexism-and-the-religion-of-hackers-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 19:36:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009713sexism-and-the-religion-of-hackers-html/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Let me preempt this post with the following facts: I am a white male veteran with amazing parents. I went to a good school, and was never under-valued by the people I cared about. I fit no minority profiles in other words. I tell you this so that you can latch on to it as why I don&amp;rsquo;t understand anything in your rebuttal. But I think this gives me a unique view on the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;People are stupid. They will believe a lie because they want to believe it&amp;rsquo;s true, or because they are afraid it might be true.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;-Wizard&amp;rsquo;s First Rule - By Terry Goodkind&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post was a long time coming. I feel pretty passionate about &amp;ldquo;my community&amp;rdquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t say that in a lead-follower sense, but more of a Kum Ba Ya one. The feather that pushed this post over the edge into existence is @&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/shazzzam&#34;&gt;shazzzam&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s post &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://demosthenes.tumblr.com/post/140922392/female-stereotyping-in-security-research&#34;&gt;Female stereotyping in security research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; which was in response to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://hackerschool.org/DefconCTF/17/B300.html&#34;&gt;Saphead&amp;rsquo;s Binary 300 solution cartoon&lt;/a&gt;. But please keep in mind, this only set the cogs in motion for this post that I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about way before this cartoon came into existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sexism, and for that matter, any &amp;ldquo;-ism&amp;rdquo; is flawed on both sides. Now, Shazzzam went no where near the extreme that most of the &amp;ldquo;-ists&amp;rdquo; do for their &amp;ldquo;-isms&amp;rdquo;, she actually had some great points however, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t excuse the presumptions she made. Pusscat, Hypatia, and Shazzzam (+ the many other women in IT) have made enormous contributions, just as males have. Hackers are hackers. The only thing we measure by is the brain in your noggin, but I&amp;rsquo;ll go into that later. Where Shazzzam went wrong is that she assumed that this cartoon was depicting the female falsely, which may or may have not been the case. She then used it as a soap box to express her hate for people who make presumptions about her mental abilities because of her sex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Damn men, &amp;ldquo;they&amp;rdquo; are always assuming I&amp;rsquo;m an idiot)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the difference between a WM (woman-Marine) and a hooker? Hooker gets paid in the morning and the WM gets paid on the 1st and 15th.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;-old Marine joke, origin unknown&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this is a crude joke, it illustrates a point. During my time in the Marine Corps I witnessed female Marines that were useless, ones that slept around, and those that outshined their peers, male and female alike. But guess what, those that did well were sadly the minority in my experiences. Now you might hinge your argument on that it&amp;rsquo;s my biased opinion that &amp;lsquo;saw&amp;rsquo; what I wanted to see, and you very well could be right. I hardly consider myself perfect, but lets just say for the sake of argument that what I say is true. We all make assumptions, you are not perfect either, is it so wrong to bet on odds or experience when making assumptions? It&amp;rsquo;s human nature, but keeping an open mind is the key to this. How many Mark Dowds, HDs, Shazzzams and Pusscats are there in this world? How many times have you complained about an idiot boss or co-worker? How many times have you complained about script kiddies? or whatever you complain about on an assumption or amassed experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Stupid woman, &amp;ldquo;they&amp;rdquo; never do anything right, can&amp;rsquo;t even drive straight)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings us to my favorite part, and why I love our community. Hackers are hackers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;snip&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phrack.org/issues.html?issue=7&amp;amp;id=3&amp;amp;mode=txt&#34;&gt;original - phrak&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We exist without skin color, without nationality, without religious &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;(or sexual)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; bias&amp;hellip; and you call us criminals. You build atomic bombs, you wage wars, you murder, cheat, and lie to us and try to make us believe it&amp;rsquo;s for our own good, yet we&amp;rsquo;re the criminals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I am a criminal. My crime is that of curiosity. My crime is that of judging people by what they say and think, not what they look like. My crime is that of outsmarting you, something that you will never forgive me for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a hacker, and this is my manifesto. You may stop this individual, but you can&amp;rsquo;t stop us all&amp;hellip; after all, we&amp;rsquo;re all alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+++The Mentor+++&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the liberty of adding &amp;ldquo;(or sexual)&amp;rdquo; to this famous manifesto. But I think it stays in the spirit of it&amp;rsquo;s writer&amp;rsquo;s intent. This is my religion. I think all &amp;ldquo;ists&amp;rdquo; have forgotten what they fight for and just fight to be right. My suggestion? Make a mental note of those who have forgotten how to truly be what they claim as a title. For they will out themselves time and time again, and be destined to fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Damn kids. They&amp;rsquo;re all alike.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;edit-nikita-has-done-an-excellent-job-of-expressing-what-i-so-obviously-failed-at-doing-http-attrition-org-news-content-09-07-14-001-html-http-attrition-org-news-content-09-07-14-001-html:8cc7e12017d3404c7193dfdbd380073e&#34;&gt;EDIT: Nikita has done an excellent job of expressing what I so obviously failed at doing: &lt;a href=&#34;http://attrition.org/news/content/09-07-14.001.html&#34;&gt;http://attrition.org/news/content/09-07-14.001.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rant Back – ValSmith</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009611rant-back-valsmith-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 02:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009611rant-back-valsmith-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Val Smith recently wrote a post on the new &lt;a href=&#34;http://carnal0wnage.attackresearch.com&#34;&gt;Attack Research / carnal0wnage blog&lt;/a&gt; titled:&lt;br /&gt;
”&lt;a href=&#34;http://carnal0wnage.attackresearch.com/node/361&#34;&gt;Security Conferences, pen tests and incident response&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my thoughts on what he wrote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In paragraphs 2-6 he talks about two points. The first being that Hacker Conferences have become sort of commercialized with most speakers going for their day in the lime light or to pimp some product/0day. And the second being a lot of the talks are things that most can’t go home / back to work and test out or implement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree with him on both points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first point I think that one detail was left out of this evaluation. Size. Back when DEFCON was &amp;lt;500 people, almost everyone knew each other. 90% of those attending had the passion, had the fire for that what makes our line of work such an art. Now that our community has become “popular”, that percentage is around 20-30%. These numbers aren’t based on any stats, just something that I have been observing as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the second point, my first security conference was ShmooCon ‘06. I was glued to might seat in each talk I attended, and in just 3 short years I have seen EXACTLY what he’s talking about. I used to have to decide between awesome talks in the same hour. Now I actually find times where I’m not interested in anything being presented for that hour. But, rooms still get packed so I guess that’s just my own pickiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Penetration Testing and Incident is the second portion of his post and I really think he’s hit the nail on the head, Pen Testing and Incident Response should work closely together. I want to throw Vulnerability Assessment and Forensics into the mix as well, feeding each other, sharing data, and assisting. The segmentation of duties / teams is killing collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets get back to the basics, and really show what this community is capable of.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AnonymASS - Hiding Behind The Tubes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/anonymass-hiding-behind-the-tubes-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/anonymass-hiding-behind-the-tubes-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First I wanted to say, sorry for this and the last installment of Room362 being non-technical. They are topics that I feel strongly about and so felt impelled to share.One of the biggest problems in the world, IMHO, are people who have unfounded hate. This is compounded by the anonymity of the Internet. Allowing that hate to have no reprocussion or identity. Let me also say I have a deep respect for Free Speech, the depths of which I fear, few truly know. What I don&amp;rsquo;t have a respect for is people who abuse that right. It&amp;rsquo;s ultimately a respect of your fellow man/woman/it, that transends any nationality, race, creed, or color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you know where I stand, let me step down to a slightly lower soap box. On my last post about ethics, I received a comment from an individual who posted under the guise of not only a false email and name, but also from a proxied address. They were on my side of the argument and were digusted with Dave&amp;rsquo;s. His/her/it&amp;rsquo;s post was pointed, rude, and had no constructive criticism or facts. It was deleted. It does not deserve a direct response. So I am issuing a response to all who tred here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These types of posts are allowed to flow on other forums, blogs, and mediums of the Internet. &lt;strong&gt;They WILL NOT be allowed here. Period. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may think of me what you will, pompous, self righteous. I don&amp;rsquo;t care. I will keep my bit of the Internet clean how I see fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I hope I demonstrated this fact already, but I want to reiterate it here. I will never delete comments on any side of any discussion I have here, even if I disagree with the comment. I enjoy debat and discussion. I am religous in my faith fight for free speech and it&amp;rsquo;s application on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have something to say fine. You better do it with respect or you can take your posts to slashdot, digg, or some other place. They won&amp;rsquo;t see the light of day here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 Kindle or Not(ebook) 2 Kindle</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009352-kindle-or-notebook-2-kindle-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2009 20:19:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009352-kindle-or-notebook-2-kindle-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently I have been debating on whether to get a Netbook or the Kindle 2. (I am only in this debate because my lovely wife decided to buy a table and chairs, for the house. There is no winning when they buy things for &amp;lsquo;the house&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;the kids&amp;rsquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyways, I tweeted up my dilemma and got a huge amount of responses. They came from both sides of the fence. Some said Kindle and some said Netbook, and they all had good arguments. But, being the gadget nerd that I am and having owned a netbook before I started to lean towards the Kindle. Until I looked at the Kindle store..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you hear about the Kindle you hear about the cheap books (no argument there), the free EVDO (still no argument), and the fact that you can read blogs and magazines. This is where the marketing people caught me. I am a huge blog reader. I currently have 2700+ blogs in my google reader OPML (I can usually hit them all in less than an hour with a process I&amp;rsquo;ve refined, so don&amp;rsquo;t think too lowly of me). So the fact that I could read my blogs and the occasional book, and even send pdfs to the Kindle got me excited about the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I put the Kindle 2 in my shopping cart at Amazon, added a leather case just for S&amp;amp;G, and looked back at TweetDeck for any last comments people had. &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/hmjgriffon&#34;&gt;@hmjgriffon&lt;/a&gt; was completely against buying the Kindle, so I decided to try out sending a PDF to the Kindle app Amazon has for the iPhone. I had installed it a couple nights ago and hadn&amp;rsquo;t tested it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the charges started rolling in. First I find out that it is 10 cents per PDF that I have converted for use on the Kindle/iPhone App. Then I looked into the blogs, you know, just to try at least SOMETHING out before I bought it. The few blogs that they support are either 99 cents or 1.99 a month. Wait.. so let me get this straight. I have to pay $1 or $2 to view a blog that is free? No thanks. I mean they could do something cool and special with the blog, but I don&amp;rsquo;t see the market. Magazines, maybe, I think I would probably subscribe to CPU or Linux Journal if it came via Kindle (definitely 2600..).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I stopped, and complained on twitter about it. Then a couple people started shouting solutions, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/wardspan&#34;&gt;@wardspan&lt;/a&gt; pointed me towards a Kindle book (and said it contained the secret to using Google Reader on the Kindle free):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Complete-Users-Amazing-Amazon-Kindle/dp/B001TOCCRK/ref=pd_bbs_sr_1?ie=UTF8&amp;amp;s=books&amp;amp;qid=1236280910&amp;amp;sr=8-1&#34;&gt;The Complete User&amp;rsquo;s Guide To the Amazing Amazon Kindle 2: A Kindle Owners Toolkit Of Over 500 Tips, Tricks, &amp;amp; Links (For Amazons Revolutionary e-Book Reader &amp;amp; Free Wireless Web Browser) (Kindle Edition)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to purchase it (0.99) and read it on my iPhone, for not only the contents of the book, but to kind of gauge the service for myself before I buy. I think that 99 cents is a minimal cost to find out if the Kindle truly is for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hope this helps those of you who are on the fence like me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twitter API Problem</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/200934twitter-api-problem-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2009 15:54:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/200934twitter-api-problem-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://s3.media.squarespace.com/production/438411/4879756/wp-content/uploads/2009/03/twitter_rate_exceeded.png&#34; alt=&#34;twitter_rate_exceeded&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of you Twitterholics have seen this beautiful status. You get a total of 100 API calls per Twitter account per hour. What happens if you use all of your afforded calls? You can just use &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.twitter.com/&lt;/a&gt; no problem right? Well you loose a lot of what makes Twitter clients so useful (search, grouping, instant updates.. etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, what if you leave you client up at home? TweetDeck by itself uses most of the API calls just by itself. So in this scenerio, you are destined (at least for that day) to spend it on the twitter site, which as we already discussed, leaves much to be desired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mom taught me never to point out a problem without suggeting a solution, so here is what I think would be an awesome addition to Twitter, that might have other advantages as well:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://s3.media.squarespace.com/production/438411/4879756/wp-content/uploads/2009/03/twitter_rate_exceeded2.png&#34; alt=&#34;twitter_rate_exceeded2&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is at the bottom of gmail. It allows you to see where else your account is being accessed from (IP). You can also click &amp;ldquo;Details&amp;rdquo;  and click to log out of all other sessions. This would be nice in twitter for a couple reasons. It would allow you to block/logout the client you left at home, but also check to make sure the IPs that are accessing the API on your behalf are your own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just a suggestion..&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My iPhone runs Windows</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009223my-iphone-runs-windows-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2009 22:50:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009223my-iphone-runs-windows-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;(This is the 3rd time I am writing this post, FF Fail, then Word crashed, so please excuse the lack of passion)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moment that PDANet published that they released an updated version that allows USB tethering, I ran home and “QuickPWNd” my phone (which took all 5 minutes). Loaded the app and now I had the coveted TETHERING. I was free of my bind to Comcast or Free Public Wifi. However, over the next few months, my iPhone started getting slower and slower to respond. Crashes happened on apps that never had a problem before (including Safari). It would even crash on incoming calls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5 minutes ago (now more like 20), I had it crash again and slow responsiveness down to unbearable speeds. (2 minutes from touch to fully started app). When I had an internal debate: Would I go home and de-PWN it, or deal with it? With that same thought I realized that at the core of most of the technologies we use today, Windows, Twitter, MySpace (now Facebook), is an underlying need, freedom, or other feature that they provide that makes them ‘bearable’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twitter’s FAIL WHALE is famous because Twitter crashes or is down A LOT. Why do you still use it? Windows is an utter mess of code and BSOD even had a hardware device made for it. Why do you still use it? &amp;hellip;you get the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not going to revert my iPhone back. You know why? Because the freedom that it provides me, (like typing a blog post for the 3rd time going 65 miles an hour in the back seat of a car) is worth it, to me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TiVo for the Economically Unstimulated</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009122tivo-for-the-economically-unstimulated-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2009 17:40:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/2009122tivo-for-the-economically-unstimulated-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;TiVo and DVRs in general have brought TV watching a long way. Some of the innovations that have come of it have made the TV experience better.  Commercial skipping is my own personal favorite. But some of the other features are pausing, rewinding, and fast forwarding (after you are behind a bit obviously) and finally recording. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, recording live TV is nothing new. People have done it since VCRs were invented, and I’m sure much before then. But the problem, from back in the day, all the way up to the most updated TiVo is that you, the user have to remember to set it up to record, and if you missed an episode, you’re SOL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In comes torrenting. Usually it’s a bad word on the Internet and on the news, so I will make my disclaimer here. I am not a lawyer, nor do I know the laws surrounding what I am about to describe. Use at your own discretion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using your favorite torrent search engine (mine is &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scrapetorrent.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.scrapetorrent.com/&lt;/a&gt;) you can find every episode of every show you could ever imagine, even some of the more obscure ones. However we run into the same problem, you the user have to know when a new episode is out, hunt it down, and download it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where TVRss (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tvrss.net/&#34;&gt;http://www.tvrss.net/&lt;/a&gt;) shines and makes your life easy. TVRss is a website that serves up RSS feeds for a huge list of shows. You might not find some of the more obscure shows, like you would doing a naked torrent search, but they have most of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where do all the pieces fit together? TVRss + uTorrent (or your favorite RSS supporting torrenting program) + your favorite media server/client of choice and you have a free TiVo killer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lifehacker has a tutorial on getting this running working with Democracy: &lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/204057/&#34;&gt;http://lifehacker.com/204057/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will post screen shot here later&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaking 102 - The Audience Perspective</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/200916speaking-102-the-audience-perspective-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 20:44:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2009/200916speaking-102-the-audience-perspective-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://s3.media.squarespace.com/production/438411/4879756/uploads/sloe_death_by_meeting.serendipityThumb.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt; Today I was in a brief / talk / meeting and I just wanted to share with you some of the things that I saw in this event that might better help you know what NOT to do while getting up in front of any size crowd.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Death by bullets (Yes this is bulleted to be ironic). But seriously, this was a reoccuring theme throughout the meeting. Try and keep it to 3 or 5.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simple = Better&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The slides should not be more important than the speaker. If your slides can be printed out and disbursed. Don’t waste the time of everyone attending by reading them or having us read them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the audience takes more than 5 seconds to read a slide = &lt;strong&gt;FAIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the speaker takes more than 2 seconds to read a slide = &lt;strong&gt;FAIL&lt;/strong&gt; (this is only tolerable at the 2 second limit during long and information intense talks)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If your text during slide creation is &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AUTOSIZING DOWN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, you are in the &lt;strong&gt;process of FAIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Visio is a hand out development tool. Using it as a slide development tool = &lt;strong&gt;FAIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Holding items in your hands without the items being on topic = &lt;strong&gt;FAIL&lt;/strong&gt; (do not figit with a book, or a pen or an award until it is time to use said object)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interrupting you co-speaker to enhance points = &lt;strong&gt;FAIL&lt;/strong&gt; (this is _**NEVER **_a good thing) You are demeaning your co-speakers presence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Making it obvious that you were not paying attention to your co-speaker by stating that you don’t know something that was actually just presented by your co-speaker = &lt;strong&gt;MAJOR FAIL&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just wanted to get these off my chest as the speakers were not interested in input. I hope these help you become a better speaker.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Guards without guns</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/2008126security-guards-without-guns-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2008 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/2008126security-guards-without-guns-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://s3.media.squarespace.com/production/438411/4879756/uploads/security_guard.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have had this rant on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.twitter.com/mubix&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; (if they had threading I would link to it). I have also had it in person a half dozen times at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.csiannual.com/&#34;&gt;CSI Annual&lt;/a&gt;. And a piece of it was touched on a piece of the puzzle by &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.uncommonsensesecurity.com/&#34;&gt;Jack Daniel on his blog&lt;/a&gt; posting “&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.uncommonsensesecurity.com/2008/12/fallacy-of-penetration-testing.html&#34;&gt;The Fallacy of Penetration Testing&lt;/a&gt;”. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We as “Security Professionals” have a big problem. We usually don’t have the power to make change. This has been a fight that every one of us has gone to bat for and usually lost. We are basically security guards without guns. We don’t have the ability to shoot that intruder if he trys to step up. Now, that is an over simplification, but you understand what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we all want the power, but are we ready for the consequences that such power brings? Are you ready to loose your job or go to jail if someone breaks into your network? Again, an over simplification, and I understand there are things outside the control of all of us, but if you implement security policyes, and products, and they fail, why do we just go ‘oh well, lets mitigate and try to catch them the next time’. I don’t think that the security community as a whole is ready for such power or the consequences it brings. I know this is going to be a very controversial issue, so fell free to post your comments. Tell me why you think we are ready for the guns.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Gmail Snooze Button</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/20081129gmail-snooze-button-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2008 06:41:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/20081129gmail-snooze-button-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://s3.media.squarespace.com/production/438411/4879756/uploads/snooze_koala1.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;I use gmail. Not really a big admission nor, very hard to find out. But the reason I use it is becasuse of it’s theading and archiving. For me those two abilities are unmatched anywhere else, both Outlook and Thunderbird fail horribly at this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More to the point, I have reached a certain level of ‘zen’ with my GTD methods on gmail. I am in a constant battle for “&lt;a href=&#34;http://video.google.com/videoplay?docid=973149761529535925&#34;&gt;Inbox Zero&lt;/a&gt;” and have “Starring” extremely useless for me. My problem lies in the fact that I have email threads that I am waiting on people to reply or I simply want to reply later. While keeping them in my Inbox is alright, it is a mental block in my quest for Inbox Zero to have to go to the next page of emails and work from there due to the first page being full of followups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I thunked on the problem and came up with the idea of a snooze button. I would like a snooze button in gmail where I can click a email thread, and it asks me for a date and time period and possibly a note to tag along with it. And then, on that date or elapsed period of time OR a new email enters the thread, the thread reappears in my Inbox. I realize that you can Star, then archive, and then check your stars, but that doesn’t work for me, it is simply like making a second inbox to manage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If anyone has any ideas on how to make this happen or a contact at google that would be willing to listen to the idea, please leave a comment or shoot me an email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Koala image used with permission from: &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/witchietaitai/2629766357/&#34;&gt;http://flickr.com/photos/witchietaitai/2629766357/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maltego Keygen Crack Torrent and Offensive Security Torrent</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/20081024maltego-keygen-crack-torrent-and-offensive-security-torrent-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 18:44:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/20081024maltego-keygen-crack-torrent-and-offensive-security-torrent-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi, and welcome to my trap. I see a ton of searches of just your type on my site on a daily basis. Lets get down to ranting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.paterva.com/maltego&#34;&gt;Maltego&lt;/a&gt; is an awesome tool, it’s also GIVEN AWAY for FREE.. As in beer, which they allow you to use their servers to do your stupid little ego searches on.** STOP TRYING TO STEAL IT.**&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.offensive-security.com/training.php&#34;&gt;Offensive Security 101&lt;/a&gt;. This is by far the best course / certification that I have attempted thus far in my career. It is informative and challenging. &lt;strong&gt;STOP TRYING TO STEAL IT.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to sum up a bit and not sound like a total ass. I fully support the use of torrents, for many of it’s uses. I do not however support the torrenting of projects such as this. The Offensive Security people contribute day and night with the development of BackTrack 3, which is again, free. Paterva also gives away the use of their Community Edition of Maltego for free. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of just taking from the community like the leech that you are, try contributing something. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/rant&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who frequent my blog, I am sorry, this rage is not intended for you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mubix&#39;s Links</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/2008929mubixs-links-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Sep 2008 20:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/2008929mubixs-links-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So there are all kinds of links that I find and queue up to look at but hate keeping them open in tabs, and they aren’t always in Google Reader and I don’t want to spam to twitter, so &lt;a href=&#34;http://mubix.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;Mubix’s Links&lt;/a&gt; was born. I setup &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scribefire.com/&#34;&gt;ScribeFire&lt;/a&gt; with a new blogspot account and now, no more tabs, it truely feels like an application of GTD. Plus it allows anyone who is interested to follow along via the blogspot feed. As &lt;a href=&#34;http://edsmiley.com/&#34;&gt;edsmiley&lt;/a&gt; commented in IRC something to the effect of that he doesn’t need all the security blog feeds he just lets me do all the work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Love what you do</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/2008923love-what-you-do-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2008 20:54:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/2008/2008923love-what-you-do-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Do what you love, love what you do is what I have been told since I was young, and Gary V takes that puts it in the mirror and makes you look at it with the following video:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[youtube=&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EhqZ0RU95d4&amp;amp;w;=425&amp;amp;h;=344&#34;&gt;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EhqZ0RU95d4&amp;amp;w;=425&amp;amp;h;=344&lt;/a&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>