<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cracking on Malicious Link</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/categories/cracking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cracking on Malicious Link</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 13:55:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://malicious.link/categories/cracking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume Shadow Copy NTDS.DIT Domain Hashes Remotely - Part 2</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2013/2013-06-11-volume-shadow-copy-ntdsdit-domain-hashes-remotely-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2013 13:55:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2013/2013-06-11-volume-shadow-copy-ntdsdit-domain-hashes-remotely-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Part 2, we have the NTDS.dit file and the SYSTEM.hive file. First we need a few tools:
From: http://www.ntdsxtract.com/
Download: http://www.ntdsxtract.com/downloads/ntdsxtract/ntdsxtract_v1_0.zip
wget http://www.ntdsxtract.com/downloads/ntdsxtract/ntdsxtract_v1_0.zip  From: http://code.google.com/p/libesedb/
Download: https://googledrive.com/host/0B3fBvzttpiiSN082cmxsbHB0anc/libesedb-alpha-20120102.tar.gz
wget https://googledrive.com/host/0B3fBvzttpiiSN082cmxsbHB0anc/libesedb-alpha-20120102.tar.gz  Extract the tools:
tar zxvf libesedb-alpha-20120102.tar.gz unzip ntdsxtract_v1_0.zip  Compile/make libesedb:
root@wpad:~/blog/# cd libesedb-20120102 root@wpad:~/blog/libesedb-20120102# ./configure root@wpad:~/blog/libesedb-20120102# make  Export the tables from NTDS.dit:
root@wpad:~/blog/libesedb-20120102# cd esedbtools/ root@wpad:~/blog/libesedb-20120102/esedbtools# ./esedbexport esedbexport 20120102 Missing source file. Use esedbexport to export items stored in an Extensible Storage Engine (ESE) Database (EDB) file Usage: esedbexport [ -c codepage ] [ -l logfile ] [ -m mode ] [ -t target ] [ -T table_name ] [ -hvV ] source source: the source file -c: codepage of ASCII strings, options: ascii, windows-874, windows-932, windows-936, windows-1250, windows-1251, windows-1252 (default), windows-1253, windows-1254 windows-1255, windows-1256, windows-1257 or windows-1258 -h: shows this help -l: logs information about the exported items -m: export mode, option: all, tables (default) &#39;all&#39; exports all the tables or a single specified table with indexes, &#39;tables&#39; exports all the tables or a single specified table -t: specify the basename of the target directory to export to (default is the source filename) esedbexport will add the suffix .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volume Shadow Copy NTDS.dit Domain Hashes Remotely - Part 1</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2013/2013-06-10-volume-shadow-copy-ntdsdit-domain-hashes-remotely-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 13:11:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2013/2013-06-10-volume-shadow-copy-ntdsdit-domain-hashes-remotely-part-1/</guid>
      <description>This and part 2 are mostly just an update to http://pauldotcom.com/2011/11/safely-dumping-hashes-from-liv.html but without the need for VSSOwn, that and we are doing it remotely without the need for shell on the DC.
 Ever run into a Domain Controller that wasn&amp;rsquo;t allowed to talk to the Internet, had insane AV and GPOs not allowing anyone to RDP in (Even Domain Admins) unless they provided some kind of voodo happy dance?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Length Sorting Wordlists</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2013/2013-03-18-length-sorting-wordlists/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2013 20:01:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2013/2013-03-18-length-sorting-wordlists/</guid>
      <description>This is one of those stupid simple things that are easy to forget so I&amp;rsquo;m posting it here. Wordlists and dictionaries are awesome for cracking password hashes, and although, thanks to things like Mimikatz and WCE I don&amp;rsquo;t have to, but there is times where it&amp;rsquo;s important.
Now, having John, Hashcat, or Cain go through a dictionary is a 1-for-1 hit, no time wasted no matter how it&amp;rsquo;s sorted and usually is best to sort them by most common first so you get earlier hits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to White Chapel</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2013/2013-01-19-intro-to-white-chapel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jan 2013 02:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2013/2013-01-19-intro-to-white-chapel/</guid>
      <description>I made a slide deck to kind of explain my latest project. Basically I got fed up with having dictionaries, passwords, and cracking tools but no way to really do better collaboration in a team format as well as just better management for myself. Please feel free to submit pull requests, issues if you think something is broken or want features, or whatever on the Github repo here:
https://github.com/mubix/WhiteChapel/
Here is the slide deck:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>lm2ntlm with John the Ripper</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2012/2012-10-24-lm2ntlm-with-john-the-ripper/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2012 15:03:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2012/2012-10-24-lm2ntlm-with-john-the-ripper/</guid>
      <description>Since I didn&amp;rsquo;t see any documentation bringing how to take an LM hash that you&amp;rsquo;ve cracked and convert it to the NTLM equivalent all in one place. And I google how to do it almost every time. I wanted to put all these links in one place and remember how to do it for john. Go-go-gadget blog-notes.
So there is this: https://github.com/snarez/rcracki/blob/master/lm2ntlm.cpp
And this: https://github.com/rapid7/metasploit-framework/blob/master/tools/lm2ntcrack.rb
And this: http://www.securityfocus.com/tools/6696
And the edited version of the above: http://atenlabs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Dictionaries or Wordlists Using John the Ripper</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-09-12-multiple-dictionaries-or-wordlists-using-john-the-ripper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Sep 2011 08:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-09-12-multiple-dictionaries-or-wordlists-using-john-the-ripper/</guid>
      <description>John the ripper only takes one word list at a time. There are plenty of docs out there that show you how to cat all of your dictionaries into John&amp;rsquo;s stdin function but I like to run rules against my lists and I didn&amp;rsquo;t see any how-tos on doing this. Here is my way:
ls dicts | xargs -t -I file ./john --pot=victim.pot --format=mscash --wordlist=dicts/file --rules victim_cachedump.txt
This command will ls the &amp;lsquo;dicts&amp;rsquo; directory, pipe it to xargs, which will spit out the command it uses for each itteration (-t) and replace every time it see the word file with the line/itteration its on (-I).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPU Cracking Complaints</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-07-13-gpu-cracking-complaints/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 14:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-07-13-gpu-cracking-complaints/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been cracking passwords for a while and use a myriad of tools in a certain order to get the job done. I find that Cain is still my Go-to for allowing me to visualize the process and do some basic sorting (really wish I could search in-app). But I&amp;rsquo;ve been asking around on twitter some questions like Why is GPU cracking for 50k hashes faster than Rainbow Tables (most say the bottleneck is the HDD read style and speed) and many asked what all of my compalints are so I figured this would be the best place (vice multiple emails)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dumping Hashes on Win2k8 R2 x64 with Metasploit</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-05-16-dumping-hashes-on-win2k8-r2-x64-with-metasploit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 02:35:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-05-16-dumping-hashes-on-win2k8-r2-x64-with-metasploit/</guid>
      <description>When trying to dump password hashes on a Windows 2008 R2 64 bit box I constantly run into the &amp;ldquo;The parameter is incorrect&amp;rdquo; error in meterpreter. So I&amp;rsquo;ve had to fall back on dropping binaries which I really don&amp;rsquo;t like doing because of the added clean up and chance of getting &amp;lsquo;caught&amp;rsquo;. Well, with a bit of migration you&amp;rsquo;ll be back to passing the hash. Here is how, with a bit of the thought process first:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Password / Word lists</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-09-18-password-word-lists/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2009 14:41:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-09-18-password-word-lists/</guid>
      <description>Brute force, even though it&amp;rsquo;s gotten so fast, is still a long way away from cracking long complex passwords. That&amp;rsquo;s were word lists come in handy. It&amp;rsquo;s usually the crackers first go-to solution, slam a word list against the hash, if that doesn&amp;rsquo;t work, try rainbow tables (if they happen to have the tables for that specific hash type), and then the full on brute force. Some would say those first two steps are reversed, and it really is the choice of the the person doing it and the word lists they have to work with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPU Hash / Password Cracking</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-09-18-gpu-hash-password-cracking/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2009 01:44:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-09-18-gpu-hash-password-cracking/</guid>
      <description>I recently upgraded my video card and had a rough time finding programs that fit the hype of GPU password cracking, so here is what I found so that you won&amp;rsquo;t have as hard a time.
Ivan Golubev&amp;rsquo;s SHA1/MD5/MD4 cracker: http://www.golubev.com/hashgpu.htm
Ivan Golubev&amp;rsquo;s RAR pass cracker:
http://www.golubev.com/rargpu.htm
CUDA Multiforcer (down at the time of this posting)
http://www.cryptohaze.com/bruteforcers.php
BarsWF - MD5 Cracker:
http://3.14.by/en/md5
GPU MD5 Crack: (Included in BackTrack 4 repos &amp;ldquo;gpu-md5-crack&amp;rdquo;)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>