<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Novahackers on </title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/categories/novahackers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Novahackers on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 15:53:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://malicious.link/categories/novahackers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NoVA Hackers - 3 years old and still going strong</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-07-07-nova-hackers-3-years-old-and-still-going-strong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 15:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-07-07-nova-hackers-3-years-old-and-still-going-strong/</guid>
      <description>I missed the 3 year anniversary of NoVA Hackers but I did want to make a post about it since we are still going strong and are now at ~150 active members.
Chris Gates and I started this thing together back in October of 2008 which spawned off of Chris&amp;rsquo; idea to start a AHA (Austin Hackers Association)-like group in NoVA. It&amp;rsquo;s ideals merged with the already going NoVA Security Luncheons that I was throwing in Reston VA and DC was where it all started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offensive and Defensive SSH Patching at NoVA Hackers</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2010/2010-12-05-offensive-and-defensive-ssh-patching-at-nova-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2010 06:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2010/2010-12-05-offensive-and-defensive-ssh-patching-at-nova-hackers/</guid>
      <description>This is definitely not my content, but I did want to highlight the talk Nicholas [1] gave at NoVA Hackers [2] this last November.
Nicholas B. gives a talk about SSH Patching for Offensive and Defense at NoVa Hackers November 2010
[1] http://twitter.com/nberthaume
[2] http://novahackers.blogspot.com/2010/10/november-meeting-monday-nov-15th-2010.html</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NoVA Hackers</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-10-20-nova-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2009 14:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-10-20-nova-hackers/</guid>
      <description>I created a google group for the NoVA Hackers meetups (Formerly known as NoVASec Luncheons)
I have added some permissions to the group to maximize privacy options while still allowing for interaction other than me sending out BCC&amp;rsquo;d messages to everyone:
 Private Invite Only - basically to keep spam out
 Only Managers can view Member List - so those who want don&amp;rsquo;t want their email addresses seen can join and just listen for announcements and regular message traffic</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Security - DC-NoVA-MD</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-06-29-local-security-dc-nova-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 23:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-06-29-local-security-dc-nova-md/</guid>
      <description>Looking for local events?
I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten a lot of people asking me recently where the local events are in DC, and I almost every time turn them to the awesome http://www.novainfosecportal.com/ which is hands down the best source for local events for the DC-NoVA-MD area, not just NoVA.
Grecs (follow him on twitter) does an amazing job at keeping it up to date and filled with every event possible. (Subscribe to his google calendar of events, get the RSS feed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>