<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>novahackers on malicious.link</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/categories/novahackers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in novahackers on malicious.link</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 15:53:13 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://malicious.link/categories/novahackers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NoVA Hackers - 3 years old and still going strong</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-07-07-nova-hackers-3-years-old-and-still-going-strong/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2011 15:53:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-07-07-nova-hackers-3-years-old-and-still-going-strong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I missed the &lt;a href=&#34;http://novahackers.blogspot.com/2008/04/working-on-it.html&#34;&gt;3 year anniversary&lt;/a&gt; of NoVA Hackers but I did want to make a post about it since we are still going strong and are now at ~150 &lt;strong&gt;active&lt;/strong&gt; members.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/carnal0wnage&#34;&gt;Chris Gates&lt;/a&gt; and I started this thing together back in October of 2008 which spawned off of Chris&amp;rsquo; idea to start a AHA (Austin Hackers Association)-like group in NoVA. It&amp;rsquo;s ideals merged with the already going NoVA Security Luncheons that I was throwing in Reston VA and DC was where it all started.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The only rule we have is participation, and mutal respect. We wanted to have a place where people could present anything from awesome new ideas and pre-confrerence test-runs to the security settings on a mac. Accessible so that people could learn how to speak and get in front of people, and trusting enough so that people could do those pre-con / crazy idea talks and not worry that it&amp;rsquo;s going to get tweeted/blogged about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With that said Georgia is awesome enough to record the presentations of members who do wish to be recorded and posts them regularly to the interwebs here:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.grmn00bs.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.grmn00bs.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;you can also find them on the rarely updated NoVA Hackers Blog: &lt;a href=&#34;http://novahackers.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;http://novahackers.blogspot.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We now have 5-10 speakers every month (2nd Monday of the month unless moved for other reasons), we have pizza, beer, snacks and an awesome location (thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/llsecurity&#34;&gt;Lucas Lyon&lt;/a&gt;). Out next meeting is July 11th actually, so get invited quick!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you in the NoVA / Maryland / DC area? Ask for an invite here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.google.com/group/novahackers&#34;&gt;http://groups.google.com/group/novahackers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or if you know someone in the group you can simple ask them to invite you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just a word of warning, we do take the participation rule seriously, lurkers and non-participants are cut from the list.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Our definition of participation means asking questions (think instant access to industry experts), starting discussions, or responding to the questions on the mailing list, or showing up for meetings. But the best way and the easiest way to be able to slack a bit on the mailinglist or attendence side is to present. That is the main reason for the group/meetings)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Offensive and Defensive SSH Patching at NoVA Hackers</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2010/2010-12-05-offensive-and-defensive-ssh-patching-at-nova-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2010 06:58:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2010/2010-12-05-offensive-and-defensive-ssh-patching-at-nova-hackers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is definitely not my content, but I did want to highlight the talk Nicholas [1] gave at NoVA Hackers [2] this last November.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nicholas B. gives a talk about SSH Patching for Offensive and Defense at NoVa Hackers November 2010&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/nberthaume&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/nberthaume&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href=&#34;http://novahackers.blogspot.com/2010/10/november-meeting-monday-nov-15th-2010.html&#34;&gt;http://novahackers.blogspot.com/2010/10/november-meeting-monday-nov-15th-2010.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NoVA Hackers</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-10-20-nova-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2009 14:28:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-10-20-nova-hackers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I created a google group for the NoVA Hackers meetups (Formerly known as NoVASec Luncheons)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have added some permissions to the group to maximize privacy options while still allowing for interaction other than me sending out BCC&amp;rsquo;d messages to everyone:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Private Invite Only - basically to keep spam out&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Only Managers can view Member List - so those who want don&amp;rsquo;t want their email addresses seen can join and just listen for announcements and regular message traffic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Managers and Members can invite - this allows for growth by word of mouth with little moderation ( I say little because I&amp;rsquo;ll still get emails when new users join )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are interested in joining please send me the email addresses you would like invited to the group to &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:mubix@hak5.org&#34;&gt;mubix@hak5.org&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;URL is &lt;a href=&#34;http://groups.google.com/group/novahackers/&#34;&gt;http://groups.google.com/group/novahackers/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be doing all following announcements there.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Local Security - DC-NoVA-MD</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-06-29-local-security-dc-nova-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2009 23:18:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-06-29-local-security-dc-nova-md/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking for local events?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten a lot of people asking me recently where the local events are in DC, and I almost every time turn them to the awesome &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.novainfosecportal.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.novainfosecportal.com/&lt;/a&gt; which is hands down the best source for local events for the DC-NoVA-MD area, not just NoVA.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/grecs&#34;&gt;Grecs&lt;/a&gt; (follow him on twitter) does an amazing job at keeping it up to date and filled with every event possible. (Subscribe to his google calendar of events, get the RSS feed.. all good stuff)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But there are other resources too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;DojoSec - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dojosec.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.dojosec.com/&lt;/a&gt;- run by the amazing Marcus J. Carey who recently joined the P&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pauldotcom.com&#34;&gt;aulDotCom Security Weekly&lt;/a&gt; crew. DojoSec is a Monthly min-conference with 1 track and some of the best speakers in the local area, definitely worth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shmoo Group hosts the recently revived Security Geeks mailing list:  &lt;a href=&#34;http://lists.shmoo.com/mailman/listinfo/secgeeks&#34;&gt;http://lists.shmoo.com/mailman/listinfo/secgeeks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I run a luncheon that you can get on the list simply by emailing me (mubix hak5.org) or commenting here if you wish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another site to keep up on is &lt;a href=&#34;http://infosecevents.net/&#34;&gt;http://infosecevents.net/&lt;/a&gt; run by &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/ggee&#34;&gt;GGEE&lt;/a&gt; has a more broad scope of events, not just in the area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hope this helps more people find ways of getting connected with the community.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
