<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Iptv on room362com</title>
    <link>//room362.com/tags/iptv/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Iptv on room362com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 02:56:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//room362.com/tags/iptv/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>ShmooCon infected with podcasters</title>
      <link>//room362.com/post/2007/2007327shmoocon-infected-with-podcasters-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Mar 2007 02:56:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>//room362.com/post/2007/2007327shmoocon-infected-with-podcasters-html/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;//room362.com/uploads/shmoocon.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, it&amp;rsquo;s over. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shmoocon.org&#34;&gt;ShmooCon&lt;/a&gt; and the meet up is finally over. I had a blast, but it put a tax on my time like you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t believe. I can&amp;rsquo;t imagine what life is like for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shmoo.com&#34;&gt;Shmoo group&lt;/a&gt;, especially &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/27158652@N00/86418247/&#34;&gt;Heidi&lt;/a&gt;. I will be posting all of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mubix/sets/72157600031734284/&#34;&gt;pictures on flickr&lt;/a&gt; shortly. I got to do a lot of other things at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shmoocon.org&#34;&gt;ShmooCon&lt;/a&gt; other than just the meet up. I had the distinct opportunity to help bag over &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/bre/431531146/&#34;&gt;1000 bags&lt;/a&gt; with swag, Shmooballs, and adverts. And, yes, if you are reading this Freshman, I AM COMPLAINING! However, I will not complain about doing &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shmoocon.org/labs.html&#34;&gt;ShmooCon Labs&lt;/a&gt;. Here is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://flickr.com/photos/btmspox/434923275/&#34;&gt;network diagram&lt;/a&gt; if you wanna see the extent of what would would have paled most enterprise networks.  Ok, as for the meet up, I need a name for it, and I am totally not creative, so those 3 who read my blog, I charge you to help a fellow Internet addict out. We had people come from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pauldotcom.com/&#34;&gt;Pauldotcom&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hak5.org/&#34;&gt;Hak.5&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://cyberspeak.libsyn.com/&#34;&gt;Cyberspeak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mckeay.net/&#34;&gt;Martin Mckeay&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sploitcast.com/&#34;&gt;SploitCast&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.nmrc.org/~thegnome/&#34;&gt;Simple Nomad&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.flickr.com/photos/mubix/437155223/&#34;&gt;Rodney from the Shmoo&lt;/a&gt; Group, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.renderlab.net/&#34;&gt;Render Man&lt;/a&gt;, and a surprise showing of two other security podcasts you should definitely check out, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.secthis.com/&#34;&gt;Secthis&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://cmdln.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Cmdln&lt;/a&gt;. It went great except for a few things, which didn&amp;rsquo;t make it bad, just a little more interesting. Lets just say &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Murphy&#39;s_law&#34;&gt;Murphy&lt;/a&gt; tried very hard. The manager that knew about our reservation, that gave us the ok to keep the place open late, and have a tab, went MIA. So we improvised by using a gift card that kept being passed around, taking over the whole place so that a reservation wasn&amp;rsquo;t needed, and moving the party to another bar after they forced us out. The travel to the bar was another story all by it&amp;rsquo;s self. We walk about 1.5 miles to the next bar, which no one was sure where it was. Now, &amp;ldquo;WE&amp;rdquo; is about 40 of the 50 to 60 people that were at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chipotle.com/&#34;&gt;Chipotle&lt;/a&gt;, all walking on the side walk, half drunk, a mile and a half. You are now thinking one of two things: 1. That would have been hilarious to see, or 2. People will walk the desert for free beer/drinks.  Check out all the media coverage of the event: &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.technorati.com/photos/tag/shmoocon&#34;&gt;http://www.technorati.com/photos/tag/shmoocon&lt;/a&gt; mubix&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>