<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>shmoocon - Category - Malicious Link - Blog by mubix - Rob Fuller</title>
        <link>https://malicious.link/categories/shmoocon/</link>
        <description>shmoocon - Category - Malicious Link - Blog by mubix - Rob Fuller</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>mubix@hak5.org (Rob Fuller)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>mubix@hak5.org (Rob Fuller)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 02:33:22 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://malicious.link/categories/shmoocon/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Attacker Ghost Stories - ShmooCon 2014</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2014/2014-01-18-attacker-ghost-stories-shmoocon-2014/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 02:33:22 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Rob Fuller</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2014/2014-01-18-attacker-ghost-stories-shmoocon-2014/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[ Attacker Ghost Stories - ShmooCon 2014 from Rob Fuller ]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>ShmooCon 2013 Streaming</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2013/2013-02-15-shmoocon-2013-streaming/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 04:11:29 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2013/2013-02-15-shmoocon-2013-streaming/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Thanks to @spatial_d for the tweet here: https://twitter.com/spatial_d/status/302253050725298176
I&rsquo;m capturing it here more of a bookmark for myself:
Build It: http://www.ustream.tv/channel/build-it-2013 Belay It: http://www.ustream.tv/channel/belay-it-2013 Bring It On: http://www.ustream.tv/channel/bring-it-2013 ]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>ShmooCon Tools</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-02-12-shmoocon-tools/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2009 15:58:59 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-02-12-shmoocon-tools/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[It figures that someone who didn’t go actually made a list of tools. (Probably because they didn’t have to suffer the ShmooFlu)
Check out: http://blog.security4all.be/2009/02/shmoocon-2009-overview-collection-of.html Thanks to Security4all for posting it up!
If you see something that he doesn’t have, pictures, videos, links, or tools, please let him know.
FireTalks / PodCasters Meetup audio can be found here soon: http://pcm.libsyn.com/]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>The Middler gets released at ShmooCon!</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-02-07-the-middler-gets-released-at-shmoocon/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 20:22:02 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-02-07-the-middler-gets-released-at-shmoocon/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[The official link is up and here it is.. well, until they release the beta:
http://inguardians.com/tools/middler-alpha.tgz
Keep up with http://www.inguardians.com/ for all of their great tools.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Podcasters Meetup at ShmooCon</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-01-21-podcasters-meetup-at-shmoocon/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 16:21:58 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-01-21-podcasters-meetup-at-shmoocon/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[More information can be found at http://www.podcastersmeetup.com/
But here is the down and dirty: We are sponsored this year by: HP, SunbeltSoftware, DojoSec, and TheAcademyPro / TheAcademyHome solidly so far.
The following podcasts will be making an appearance:
Hak5 PaulDotCom CyberSpeak Securabit SploitCast Unpersons Phone Losers of America SMBMinute And the schedule goes as such:
1700 - 1800 - Meet and greet, and setup (Everyone involved in the live event please show up as close to this start time as possible) 1800 - 1900 - Live Show (This will probably go over time) 1900 - 1930 - Book signing and transition time 1930 - 2030 - FireTalks (more below) 2030 - 0400 - Food and Drinks on us at local spot.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Podcaster&#39;s Meetup @ ShmooCon Update 1</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-01-20-podcasters-meetup-at-shmoocon-update-1/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 19:33:35 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Rob Fuller</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-01-20-podcasters-meetup-at-shmoocon-update-1/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Sponsors: We have had a lot of great response for everyone on this year&rsquo;s event! I want to reiterate, this event is for podcasters, bloggers, twitter addicts, and everyone in between. I would also like to announce an update to our sponsor&rsquo;s lineup:
TheAcademyPro.com / TheAcademyHome.com
These are twin sites catering videos to the security pro looking to learn about everything from enterprise gear to Maltego, and the home user trying to start the learning about security and how to secure their own computers without going to you the IT guy in the family.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>ShmooCon Room Sharing</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008-11-14-shmoocon-room-sharing/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 20:38:34 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008-11-14-shmoocon-room-sharing/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Update - Shmoocon already had a list: http://lists.shmoo.com/mailman/listinfo/shmoocon-roommates
Go with what your readers want right? Well I have recently been getting a lot of hits on finding room sharing at ShmooCon. I have done this before at cons and I have met some very interesting people. So I created the google group ShmooCon RoomShare. Post that you are looking, post that you have space. It’s all voluntary and you can sign up for email alerts so that you don’t have to check it all the time.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Hack or Halo 5 at ShmooCon 2009</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008-11-10-hack-or-halo-5-at-shmoocon-2009/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 03:05:13 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2008/2008-11-10-hack-or-halo-5-at-shmoocon-2009/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Even if you have been to ShmooCon, something that alludes most con-goers is the Hack or Halo contest. Most of the time you will see it’s organizers at table near the registration desk getting people signed up. What you may not know is how the whole thing goes down. It’s after hours so, you aren’t missing the great content during the day, and it might save you a few dollars of money spending bar time.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Missed Shmoo? Now you can experience in the comfort of your home.</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2007/2007-04-10-missed-shmoo-now-you-can-experience-in-the-comfort-of-your-home/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2007 12:44:59 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2007/2007-04-10-missed-shmoo-now-you-can-experience-in-the-comfort-of-your-home/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[So you couldn&rsquo;t make it. No worry, you have undoubtedly been going through the videos from shmoocon already. If you haven&rsquo;t yet, you should, they were well done and better than last year. But, what you might not have done yet is the Hack or Halo contests.
Update: We&rsquo;ve determined the images have become corrupt during one of the transfers and have been taken offline until the problem has been fixed.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>SploitCast, a Feburary baby, ShmooCon and Tax season</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2006/2006-01-29-sploitcast-a-feburary-baby-shmoocon-and-tax-season/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2006 02:11:55 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2006/2006-01-29-sploitcast-a-feburary-baby-shmoocon-and-tax-season/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Geez. I never have time anymore to put something on this darn thing. I think I am going to stop apologizing for how long it takes me to post, because it is quite quickly becoming the norm. So anyways, since my last post, I have been to ShmooCon &lsquo;06
I met some great people to include but not limited to, Lance James, Kevin Mitnick, Fyodor - A.K.A the creator of NMAP, Skydog, DC-Mike, and Simple Nomad.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>ShmooCon 2006</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2005/2005-10-10-shmoocon-2006/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2005 09:14:57 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2005/2005-10-10-shmoocon-2006/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I did a search on Digg.com and was suprised to see that not a soul has written about ShmooCon 2006. I guess all you west coasters only care about DefCon. That is discrimination and WE DON’T HAVE TO TAKE IT!. Back to reality. Well if you don’t know ShmooCon is basically the DefCon for the east coast and is being held in Washington D.C. . Registration is limited, unlike DefCon, so hurry and whip out those Paypal accounts.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
