<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Book on malicious.link</title>
    <link>/tags/book/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Book on malicious.link</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 09:30:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tribe of Hackers: Red Team Edition</title>
      <link>/post/2019/tribe-of-hackers-red-team-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 09:30:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019/tribe-of-hackers-red-team-edition/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-how-did-you-get-your-start-on-a-red-team&#34;&gt;1. How did you get your start on a red team?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Craig Balding (@craigbalding) gave me my chance to be on my first Red Team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-what-is-the-best-way-to-get-a-red-team-job&#34;&gt;2. What is the best way to get a red team job?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apply? This is like asking how to get a job period. Red Team jobs don&amp;rsquo;t follow any particular rules. Apply for the jobs that are out there and be qualified to do so. Therein lies the tricky bit though right? First, you have to believe that you are qualified, then you have to convince someone else (the recruiter/hiring manager) that you are qualified. Many hiring managers talk about the &amp;ldquo;hacker mindset.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-how-can-someone-gain-red-team-skills-without-getting-in-trouble-with-the-law&#34;&gt;3. How can someone gain red team skills without getting in trouble with the law?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question kind of pisses me off because even in 2005 when I started learning about security, there were plenty of avenues to learn without committing felonies. Sure, in the BBS days and those of the &amp;ldquo;early&amp;rdquo; Internet resources were lacking and many from that era still wear it as a badge of honor. This is fine, they learned the only way they could at the time. That time is long gone. If you think you have to break the law (no matter what you think of the laws in your country), then someone has misguided you. This does take one minor thing for granted, that you have a computer that you are authorized to use and have Internet connectivity. If you have neither of these, then those situations may still be out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me put away my soapbox real quick so we can talk about the ways you can actually do this in 2019. Because red teaming can be made up of a ton of different skill sets from routing, switching, Active Directory, wireless (not just 802.11), physical security, IoT (Internet of Things), web, cloud, cryptography, to databases, etc, etc, etc.. you can come from a vast array of backgrounds and study an even bigger variety of topics that it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t fit in this book without making a Tomb of Hackers. However, looking at VulnHub is where I point most people. On VulnHub you download VMs and attempt to get &amp;ldquo;root&amp;rdquo; on them. The great thing about VulnHub is even if you are just beginning you can download a VM, boot it up, have a go, realize you have no idea where to start and read one of the myriads of walk-throughs they have on the site for each VM. There is ZERO harm in reading ALL of the walkthroughs many times over and getting the practice of doing exactly what they are doing and eventually understanding WHY they are doing it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-why-can-t-we-agree-on-what-a-red-team-is&#34;&gt;4. Why can&amp;rsquo;t we agree on what a red team is?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it means different things to everyone and that&amp;rsquo;s ok. Why does it have to have a precise definition? Can you tell me what a SOC looks like in certain terms? Or what makes up a hospital? We have a ton of collections of things that have general ideas, and that is fine. Such as the fact that a hospital includes an Emergency room but not all of them include long term cancer wards, and a SOC must have screens on the wall for NO REASON WHATSOEVER!! and some are &lt;sup&gt;24&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;7&lt;/sub&gt;, and some are not. These general ideas are accepted in society, why isn&amp;rsquo;t it ok for a red team to also be amorphous?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;5-what-is-one-thing-the-rest-of-information-security-doesn-t-understand-about-being-on-a-red-team-what-is-the-most-toxic-falsehood-you-have-heard-related-to-red-blue-or-purple-teams&#34;&gt;5. What is one thing the rest of information security doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand about being on a red team? What is the most toxic falsehood you have heard related to red, blue, or purple teams?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea what the rest of the information security community/world/whatever understands or doesn&amp;rsquo;t understand. As for toxic falsehoods? Why does anyone care? Go to work, do good things, or build a company, and do good things. Run your own race to your goals. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry about what the &amp;ldquo;rest&amp;rdquo; of information security is doing, or what toxic drama is next up on the Internet. All of that is a waste of your time. You only get so much time on this earth, and you choose who you give that time to, random security fads, or drama is just not worth it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;6-what-is-the-appropriate-point-in-the-maturation-of-a-security-program-to-introduce-a-formal-red-team-into-an-organization&#34;&gt;6. What is the appropriate point in the maturation of a security program to introduce a formal red team into an organization?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As soon as they can afford it. Red Teams a sort of like unit tests. Everyone knows they need them, and they put them in as soon as it starts becoming needed or things start breaking. Same with Red teams, the moment you start to &lt;em&gt;need&lt;/em&gt; a Blue team is about the same time you need a Red team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;7-what-has-been-effective-at-explaining-the-value-of-red-teaming-to-a-reluctant-or-non-technical-client-or-even-to-your-own-organization&#34;&gt;7. What has been effective at explaining the value of red teaming to a reluctant or non-technical client, or even to your own organization?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Listening. If you are there to genuinely help them they will feel that and not be reluctant anymore. If they continue to be reluctant then they don&amp;rsquo;t want your services, you should let them make that decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;8-what-is-the-least-bang-for-your-buck-security-control-that-you-see-implemented&#34;&gt;8. What is the least bang-for-your-buck security control that you see implemented?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logs. The problem with logs is that if you don&amp;rsquo;t have a good team to look at said log they are useless and moreover they cost more money the more you have just sitting around. So unlike AV or a SEIM or a number of other things that can be considered useless under different contexts they usually don&amp;rsquo;t cost you exponentially more money like logs do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;9-have-you-ever-recommended-not-doing-a-red-team-and-offered-something-else-more-suitable-even-when-a-customer-asked-for-one-what-have-you-recommended&#34;&gt;9. Have you ever recommended not doing a red team and offered something else more suitable, even when a customer asked for one? What have you recommended?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plenty of times. I event did a talk called Open Source Pentesting where I talked about the myriad of different offerings that I have offered and think other firms should offer because they fit better than a standard pentest or red team assessment, or source code review. Ultimately however the customer is the one making a business decision to purchase your services, counseling them to do something different may fall on deaf ears or they may have a very good reason for doing so that you have no purview to. You have to be ok with that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;10-what-s-the-most-important-or-easiest-to-implement-control-that-can-prevent-you-from-compromising-a-system-or-network-for-example-how-can-we-help-small-and-medium-businesses-who-have-a-smaller-budget-and-staff&#34;&gt;10. What&amp;rsquo;s the most important or easiest-to-implement control that can prevent you from compromising a system or network? For example, how can we help small and medium businesses who have a smaller budget and staff?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;11-why-do-you-feel-it-is-critical-to-stay-within-the-rules-of-engagement&#34;&gt;11. Why do you feel it is critical to stay within the rules of engagement?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it&amp;rsquo;s a felony is the U.S. if you don&amp;rsquo;t (breaking into something without authorization) and liability insurance only goes so far. It&amp;rsquo;s also an agreed upon document. This is like asking &amp;ldquo;why should you honor a contract?&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;12-tell-about-a-time-you-were-busted-on-a-penetration-test-physical-network-social-engineering-etc-how-did-you-handle-it&#34;&gt;12. Tell about a time you were busted on a penetration test (physical, network, social engineering, etc.). How did you handle it?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This happens a lot and while I do get pissed (mostly at myself for being stupid in some way), it quickly becomes admiration for what the defense team put in place. I did a talk called Attacker Ghost Stories about a number of different occasions when I was caught. One of my favorite stories was the result of a honey pot (an intentionally vulnerable looking software).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time in a red team far far away my team had harvested a few sets of credentials from a phishing exercise and I wanted to test them out on a web application page I found which showed a number of indicators that Active Directory authentication was in play on this page (such as a DOMAIN\jdoe) example. I proceeded to use each of the credentials the team had obtained. Unbeknownst to our team, this was a page that did not actually have connectivity to any backend much less Active Directory. It did however alert the administrators every single user and password that we tried against that page so that they could disable them and have their passwords changed. This page was set up by a system administrator, not even the blue team (defense team) as a way to catch leaked credentials. Needless to say our team was very displeased with me that I had burned all of their work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;13-what-is-the-biggest-ethical-quandary-you-experienced-while-on-an-assigned-objective&#34;&gt;13. What is the biggest ethical quandary you experienced while on an assigned objective?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was a law firm I was testing. It was an internal test and responder was pretty new to the industry so it was a pretty quick assessment. I was sitting there cracking passwords from the domain so I could access the target for the assessment ( dummy case records in their case data storage system), when I saw a credential crack for one of the top partners at this firm. The password was &amp;ldquo;poisonedher&amp;rdquo;. This freaked me out. What would I tell the cops if I called them. This guy confessed in his password that he was or had poisoned some woman somewhere? I expressed my concerns to the point of contact, but I was agonizing over if to tell anyone or not the whole week allotted for the test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;14-describe-the-team-aspect-of-red-teaming-how-do-you-work-together-to-get-the-job-done-including-documentation-reporting-and-working-with-the-blue-team-afterwards&#34;&gt;14. Describe the &amp;ldquo;team&amp;rdquo; aspect of red teaming. How do you work together to get the job done, including documentation, reporting, and working with the blue team afterwards?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a team, much like any other. Teams combine strengths and compinsate for weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;15-what-is-your-approach-to-debriefing-and-supporting-blue-teams-after-an-operation-is-completed&#34;&gt;15. What is your approach to debriefing and supporting blue teams after an operation is completed?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s easy, you give them as much as you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;16-if-you-were-to-switch-to-blue-team-what-would-be-your-first-step-to-better-defend-against-attacks-and-if-it-isn-t-commonly-done-already-why-do-you-suppose-that-s-the-case&#34;&gt;16. If you were to switch to blue team, what would be your first step to better defend against attacks, and if it isn&amp;rsquo;t commonly done already, why do you suppose that&amp;rsquo;s the case?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;17-a-lot-of-people-complain-about-writing-testing-reports-and-a-lot-of-customers-complain-about-the-quality-of-reports-what-is-some-practical-advice-on-writing-a-good-report&#34;&gt;17. A lot of people complain about writing testing reports and a lot of customers complain about the quality of reports. What is some practical advice on writing a good report?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;18-how-do-you-ensure-your-program-results-are-valuable-to-people-who-need-a-full-narrative-and-context-instead-of-a-showcase-of-their-weaknesses-vs-your-skill-set&#34;&gt;18. How do you ensure your program results are valuable to people who need a full narrative and context, instead of a showcase of their weaknesses vs. your skill set?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;19-how-do-you-recommend-security-improvements-other-than-pointing-out-where-it-s-insufficient&#34;&gt;19. How do you recommend security improvements other than pointing out where it&amp;rsquo;s insufficient?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;20-what-non-technical-skills-or-attitudes-do-you-look-for-when-recruiting-and-interviewing-red-team-members-or-what-is-one-of-the-most-beneficial-non-technical-skills-you-use-for-red-team-activities&#34;&gt;20. What non-technical skills or attitudes do you look for when recruiting and interviewing red team members? Or, what is one of the most beneficial non-technical skills you use for red team activities?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;21-what-differentiates-good-red-teamers-from-the-pack-as-far-as-approaching-a-problem-differently&#34;&gt;21. What differentiates good red teamers from the pack as far as approaching a problem differently?&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
