<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Dns on </title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/categories/dns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Dns on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 23:33:50 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://malicious.link/categories/dns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Iterative DNS Brute Forcing</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2014/2014-02-19-iterative-dns-brute-forcing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2014 23:33:50 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2014/2014-02-19-iterative-dns-brute-forcing/</guid>
      <description>Everyone has their list of hostnames they brute force domains with. In my last post I even mentioned a few ways to use one with XARGS or PARALLEL. But one fact about wordlist brute forcing is that there is no &amp;ldquo;one list to rule them all&amp;rdquo;. But over the years of doing DNS record collection I have noticed one thing, most domains have a large number of short hostnames that are easy to remember, usually 4 characters or less.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hostname bruteforcing on the cheap</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2014/2014-01-29-hostname-bruteforcing-on-the-cheap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2014 18:07:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2014/2014-01-29-hostname-bruteforcing-on-the-cheap/</guid>
      <description>Quick update: As @MikeDamm points out, xargs has a -P option that can do the same thing I&amp;rsquo;m using parallel for. If you have a supported version of xargs you can use -P 0 to do the same thing as -j0 with parallel, but if your version doesn&amp;rsquo;t support the 0 you can simply use the same number parallel uses ala:
 cat subdomains.txt | xargs -P 122 -I subdomain dig +noall subdomain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Changing proxychains hardcoded DNS server</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2013/2013-09-10-changing-proxychains-hardcoded-dns-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2013 13:16:39 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2013/2013-09-10-changing-proxychains-hardcoded-dns-server/</guid>
      <description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever used proxychains to push things through Meterpreter, one of the most annoying things is its &amp;ldquo;hardcoded&amp;rdquo; DNS setting for 4.2.2.2, if the org that you are going after doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow this out of their network, or if you are trying to resolve an internal asset, you&amp;rsquo;re SOL. After a ton of googling and annoyed head slams into walls every time I forget where this is I&amp;rsquo;ve finally decided to make a note of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AXFR for DNSSEC: DNSSEC Walker</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2012/2012-10-22-axfr-for-dnssec-dnssec-walker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2012 03:10:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2012/2012-10-22-axfr-for-dnssec-dnssec-walker/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR – DNSSEC Walker traverses a domain’s DNSSEC records to locate it’s regular DNS records.
I like to go through slides of cons I can’t make it out to, and Hack-in-the-Box (HITB) Kul (Malaysia), was one such as they were very quick to release sides:
http://conference.hitb.org/hitbsecconf2011kul/materials/
One that I came across is Marc “van Hauser” Heuse’s talk on IPv6 titled “IPv6 Insecurity Revolutions” (Link directly to PDF on aforementioned materials link).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A @textfiles approach at gathering the world&#39;s DNS - Slides</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2012/2012-02-03-a-textfiles-approach-at-gathering-the-worlds-dns-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 17:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2012/2012-02-03-a-textfiles-approach-at-gathering-the-worlds-dns-slides/</guid>
      <description>This is my talk that I gave at ShmooCon 2012. It was a great honor to be given the chance to speak at ShmooCon as it has been my second home since 2006 (missed the first one&amp;hellip; havent missed one since)
  A @textfiles approach to gathering the world&amp;#x27;s DNS  from Rob Fuller</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interesting DNS Stuff - SRV Records</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-02-16-interesting-dns-stuff-srv-records/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2011 07:48:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-02-16-interesting-dns-stuff-srv-records/</guid>
      <description>The following are good adds to your DNS brute force list:
These are all SRV records so make sure your type is set correctly. The great thing about SRV records is that it tells you the port in the answer. Isn&amp;rsquo;t that nice of them?
I don&amp;rsquo;t know of any DNS tools that utilize SRV as part of their process, but scripting dig to do so isn&amp;rsquo;t tough.
_autodiscover._tcp _caldav._tcp _client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OzymanDNS - Tunneling SSH over DNS</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009310ozymandns-tunneling-ssh-over-dns-html/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2009 22:30:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009310ozymandns-tunneling-ssh-over-dns-html/</guid>
      <description>Hak5 Episode 504 Shownotes (In the episode I say that it&amp;rsquo;s cross platform, use the release links for the Windows binaries to get it working on windows or use cygwin)
DISCLAIMER - I IN NO WAY ENDORSE ILLEGAL ACTIVITIES - USE THE FOLLOWING GUIDE IN A TEST ENVIRONMENT OR AT YOUR OWN LEGAL RISK. UPDATE:Thanks to Chris Gates and Robin Wood for pointing me towards a fixed up version of OzymanDNS and a great tutorial: HERE</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>