<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Room362</title>
    <link>https://room362.com/categories/tutorials/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Room362</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://room362.com/categories/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Practical Exploitation</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2010/2010-02-23-practical-exploitation</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2010 17:00:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2010/2010-02-23-practical-exploitation</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Practical Exploitation is going to be me, explaining things in the way that I see the world on the best medium for what I&amp;rsquo;m explaining, be it a short blog blurb, a video of me, a video of a desktop, or just audio. There is no schedule that I&amp;rsquo;ll be sticking to, but I will guarantee you 3 things though:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you want it explained and it has to do with infosec or hacking (I&amp;rsquo;ll do my best on the hardware side), it will be on the show. Be it a white paper that you don&amp;rsquo;t have time or want to decrypt, a tool you can&amp;rsquo;t figure out, or just something you want to learn more in-depth. That&amp;rsquo;s what it&amp;rsquo;s for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No fluff, I&amp;rsquo;ll get straight to how you use it or can understand the topic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your bullshit flag goes up for even an instant, call me on it, and I&amp;rsquo;ll either explain why I said what I did, or apologize and correct myself. You can email, tweet, PM, IM, ask a question on the tumblr site, or just haul up and punch me at a con. Either way, please take the time to tell me I&amp;rsquo;m wrong and why.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It launches today. I&amp;rsquo;ll start with topics that I know cold, I&amp;rsquo;ll move on to white papers that I thought were interesting but haven&amp;rsquo;t read yet, hopefully intermingling in anything you want to learn about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.practicalexploitation.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.practicalexploitation.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and email: questions at the same domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or call:  (503) 406-8249&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S.  Room362.com and Mubix Links aren&amp;rsquo;t going anywhere. If anything they will probably start getting updated more. Room362 with stuff I cook up, as always, and Mubix Links with anything I find interesting on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>