<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>techphile on malicious.link</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/categories/techphile/</link>
    <description>Recent content in techphile on malicious.link</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2005 17:20:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://malicious.link/categories/techphile/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hak.5 and techPhile merge for a day.</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2005/2005-12-04-hak5-and-techphile-merge-for-a-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2005 17:20:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2005/2005-12-04-hak5-and-techphile-merge-for-a-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hak5.org&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/postimages/hak5_logo_small.gif&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;December 2nd, I drove down to Williamsburg VA to meet up with the guys from Hak.5 and Frank Linhares. For those of you who don&#39;t know. Hak.5 is an IPTV (Vidcast) show, which basically boils down to a TV show on the internet. Anyways, I got to meet up with these fellas and a couple other interesting people. While I was there, I had the privilege of helping out not only in the live &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techphile.ca&#34;&gt;techPhile&lt;/a&gt; podcast by Frank Linhares, but also the &amp;lsquo;glue&amp;rsquo; segments of Ep 5 of Hak.5. I must say, if and of the Hak.5 crew or Frank are reading this; it was a great pleasure to hang out with you guys. I would also like to make some personal shout outs to each one, and because this is my site. I get to. Muhahaha.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frank&lt;/strong&gt;: It was awesome to meet and get to know you. You still owe me dinner! ;-) But seriously, it was an honor to help out with the show.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Darren&lt;/strong&gt;: You have Hak.5 on lock, keep up the awesome work, and it was cool meeting you. Thanks for the invite. Inviting someone you have never met into your home is a big deal to me, thanks for the trust and respect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wess&lt;/strong&gt;: I love you man. We need to tell Alli about us before this gets ugly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Harrison&lt;/strong&gt;: It was sweet meeting you man. We became fast friends; you and I think a lot alike. (&amp;lsquo;cept for cars: Ferrari Sucks) and I think &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.shmoocon.org&#34;&gt;ShmooCon 2006&lt;/a&gt; is gonna rock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jon&lt;/strong&gt;: Man, we will get Gentoo done. If you need any further help you guys got my number - Mubix – Tech Support 24/7 365. Keep it real man.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alli, Paul, Harrison&#39;s Mom, and Jui-Chia&lt;/strong&gt;: It was cool hanging out with you guys. I had a blast down there. 1 1/2 hour commute is worth it to hang out w/ you guys.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last thanks goes out to all the people in the IRC channel &lt;a href=&#34;irc://irc.techphile.ca&#34;&gt;techPhile IRC server&lt;/a&gt; #hak5 and #techphile for making my moderation a cake walk. Except for a certain individual, all the questions were perfect and I only had to fix/deny a few of them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What happened!?</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2005/2005-11-30-what-happened/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2005 04:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2005/2005-11-30-what-happened/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well if you were wondering about me, I didn&#39;t die. I am working on a super secret project for Frank Linhares of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.techphile.ca&#34;&gt;techPhile.ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/postimages/techphile_logo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But don&#39;t tell anyone! That is secret squrrell news. I have also submitted some logo ideas for the new Auditor Security Collection. You can vote for me: &lt;a href=&#34;http://forum.remote-exploit.org/viewtopic.php?t=1408&amp;amp;start=15&amp;amp;sid=8fa9089f2224df115d1f605cbcf704f8&#34;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also got a HP dv1420us which, so far, I really like. It doesn&#39;t like linux too much, but it is challenging me to learn more about the kernel and other aspects of linux to fix the problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyways,&lt;br&gt;
I&#39;ll start posting more&amp;hellip;. promise&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;j.d.mubix&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
