<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interview on malicious.link</title>
    <link>/tags/interview/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interview on malicious.link</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 11:30:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/tags/interview/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Hired: A Few Tips</title>
      <link>/post/2018/getting-hired-a-few-tips/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 11:30:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2018/getting-hired-a-few-tips/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In early August of 2017 &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/mubix/status/892760622563241988&#34;&gt;I posted a few tips to Twitter regarding interviewing and getting hired in general&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo; pasting them here to preserve them. I only had 140 characters to make these, and I think there is a lot more you can do, but 30 tips is a good start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t post obvious CFAA violations to social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you go in without a job and a chip on your shoulder, you&amp;rsquo;ll leave the same way&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t ask follow up questions, I won&amp;rsquo;t have any either, like &amp;ldquo;would you like the job?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exaggerating on your resume isn&amp;rsquo;t a good idea, but if you do, be ready to explain it&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The company is going to look at your social media. Privacy concerns? Don&amp;rsquo;t post publicly. Don&amp;rsquo;t get sassy in the interview about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dropping a vuln in the company during the interview is a stupid move. (Personal experience)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your attire matters. If you look like you just got out of bed, I&amp;rsquo;ll probably just let you go back to it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Being honest about not knowing something is great. Emailing after the interview that you researched it and now understand it is AWESOME!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is always ok to ask why you didn&amp;rsquo;t get the job and where you can improve. Unfortunately straight answers aren&amp;rsquo;t always possible.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Like college, trying many types of Infosec jobs will make you better at all of them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stay humble.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you were referred by a friend that works there already, respect the fact that you are representing them as well.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making money is better than not. If you think you are too good to be a Walmart greeter, you are probably too good for this job too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try not to take it personally if you don&amp;rsquo;t get the job today. You might be able to apply later. You won&amp;rsquo;t if you lash out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contributions to open source projects isn&amp;rsquo;t required, but is a good way to demonstrate values, skills, and mindset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t whine and complain during an interview. It&amp;rsquo;s ok to point out deficiencies, or answer why you left your last job but keep it brief.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set expectations and ask questions like: Can I ping you if I haven&amp;rsquo;t heard from you in a week? What should I wear to the interview&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimal self deprecation is fine, but if you spend the whole interview talking about how much you suck, I&amp;rsquo;ll believe it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include &amp;ldquo;Selected Accomplishments&amp;rdquo; part in your resume. 2-4 things that you are particularly proud of, doesn&amp;rsquo;t have to be done at work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The question &amp;ldquo;where do you want to be / doing 2/4/10 years&amp;rdquo; is a standard question. &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo; is ok, but a prepared answer is better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sarcasm is taken differently by everyone. Might go over good or bad. If it&amp;rsquo;s how you deal w/ nervousness, practice interviewing more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Practice interviewing. Find someone that will give you candid feedback and interview for positions you want with them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t take an interview call in a crowded or loud place. Rescheduling is totally ok as long as it&amp;rsquo;s done with more than 24 hours notice.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The saying &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s not what, but who you know&amp;rdquo; is unfortunately true a lot of times. But it is because &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt; you know can vouch for &lt;em&gt;what&lt;/em&gt; you know.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just because someone is a manager doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean they can&amp;rsquo;t run circles around you technically and are just acting dumb. (Personal experience)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If your LinkedIn profile does not match up with your resume, you will probably be asked about it. (i.e. degree, certs, jobs mismatch)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ask about travel and feel free to ask to talk to potential co-workers about travel and other topics to get the ground truth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Offer letters and nearly all hiring / new-hire documents are contracts. You can &amp;ldquo;X&amp;rdquo; out anything you don&amp;rsquo;t agree with. $employer will have to approve the change.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When asked to list one or more strengths or weaknesses: Strengths: stay humble, Weaknesses: share how you are working to get better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everything on the Internet is suspect. Trust but verify right? Learn things for yourself. Blog, tweet, share how/what you learned. YMMV.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have some yourself? I would love to add it! Please just tweet a reply via Twitter to me and I&amp;rsquo;ll get it added. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
