<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>r5industries on malicious.link</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/tags/r5industries/</link>
    <description>Recent content in r5industries on malicious.link</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 12:02:10 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://malicious.link/tags/r5industries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>R5 Industries</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2015/r5-industries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 12:02:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2015/r5-industries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently took the plunge and joined a startup called R5 Industries. I wanted to say thanks for all the well wishes that I received on social media. It has certainly calmed my nerves about the choice ;-).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&#39;ve had a number of people ask what R5 Industries does. Our primary selling point is AntigenC2, which is a really Command and Control detection product (no agents). But we also do Red Team assessments and some other fun toys if you are interested, &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:contact@r5industries.com&#34;&gt;contact@r5industries.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More info here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://r5industries.com/&#34;&gt;http://r5industries.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thats the end and last sales pitch you&#39;ll get from me on the subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did I make the move?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While, I loved life as an internal Red Team member (highly recommended, if you need reasons why make sure you watch Chris Gates&amp;rsquo; talk at RuxCon: &lt;a href=&#34;https://ruxcon.org.au/speakers/#Chris&#34;&gt;https://ruxcon.org.au/speakers/#Chris&lt;/a&gt; Gates ) where I got to help steer the boat of a Fortune 10 company, I had a number of opportunities that I had to turn down because of it, even though my higher ups went above and beyond to give me as much latitude as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a bunch of crazy project ideas that I wanted to see come to life over the years, I don&#39;t think I would have ever had the time to see them become anything more than mythical ideas without this opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, wish me luck, send me work (as I can finally accept it ;-) [through R5 of course]) and look out for some pretty wacky ideas and products that I&#39;ve been talking about for years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks again, I wouldn&#39;t be here without you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rob&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
