<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cons on Room362</title>
    <link>https://room362.com/categories/cons/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Cons on Room362</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 02:33:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://room362.com/categories/cons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Attacker Ghost Stories - ShmooCon 2014</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2014/2014-01-18-attacker-ghost-stories-shmoocon-2014/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2014 02:33:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2014/2014-01-18-attacker-ghost-stories-shmoocon-2014/</guid>
      <description>Attacker Ghost Stories - ShmooCon 2014  from Rob Fuller</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metasploit Mastery @BlackHatEvents USA 2013</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2013/2013-03-19-metasploit-mastery-blackhatevents-usa-2013/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2013 14:38:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2013/2013-03-19-metasploit-mastery-blackhatevents-usa-2013/</guid>
      <description>Just a quick post to say that egypt and I will be giving Metasploit Mastery twice (2 x 2 day sessions) at BlackHat USA 2013. Come out and get your Metasploit on in Vegas w/ us
Linky: http://www.blackhat.com/us-13/training/metasploit-mastery.html
Current fill rate of July 27-28 session: Current fill rate of July 29-30 session: EOM</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ShmooCon 2013 Streaming</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2013/2013-02-15-shmoocon-2013-streaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2013 04:11:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2013/2013-02-15-shmoocon-2013-streaming/</guid>
      <description>Thanks to @spatial_d for the tweet here: https://twitter.com/spatial_d/status/302253050725298176
I&amp;rsquo;m capturing it here more of a bookmark for myself:
 Build It: http://www.ustream.tv/channel/build-it-2013 Belay It: http://www.ustream.tv/channel/belay-it-2013 Bring It On: http://www.ustream.tv/channel/bring-it-2013  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Metasploit Mastery meets CanSecWest</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2013/2013-01-25-metasploit-mastery-meets-cansecwest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jan 2013 16:12:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2013/2013-01-25-metasploit-mastery-meets-cansecwest/</guid>
      <description>In 2012 @egypt and I taught Metasploit Mastery for a day and a half @DerbyCon . This was a lot of fun but we had to cram a TON of slides into that short period of time. PLUS we had a CTF at the end where people had to break into a corporate network (virtualized) and sell their shells, data, passwords, or flags to us (egypt and I were acting as opposing countries).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dirty Little Secrets They Didn&#39;t Teach You In Pentest Class - Part 2 (Video)</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2012/2012-10-01-dirty-little-secrets-they-didnt-teach-you-in-pentest-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 12:47:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2012/2012-10-01-dirty-little-secrets-they-didnt-teach-you-in-pentest-class/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Ticket Contest - Metasploit Mastery at DerbyCon</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2012/2012-08-07-free-ticket-contest-metasploit-mastery-at-derbycon/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 21:24:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2012/2012-08-07-free-ticket-contest-metasploit-mastery-at-derbycon/</guid>
      <description>Egypt and I have decided to give away a spot in our training event at DerbyCon. This won’t come easy though, you have to submit an essay to us with one of the following topics:
Essay Topic Options:
1. Why I deserve a free training class
2. How I would social engineer Egypt and Mubix out of a ticket to their class
Maximum Length: ~1000 words / 3 pages. (We&amp;rsquo;re lazy)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DerbyCon Training (Sep 27-28 2012)</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2012/2012-05-22-derbycon-training-sep-27-28-2012/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 May 2012 19:44:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2012/2012-05-22-derbycon-training-sep-27-28-2012/</guid>
      <description>@egypt and I have teamed up this year to teach at DerbyCon at the end of September. Here is the very basic outline of the class and subject to change:
(Sign up here: https://www.derbycon.com/training-courses/ )
THURSDAY
 Intro to the Framework The history of the Framework Ninja Demo Usage Recon Exploitation Pillaging Post modules Intro to Ruby  Getting your environment set up Ruby Basics Strings, Arrays, and Methods oh my IRB, Pry - The No-Spoon Portion Navigating Documentation  Module Writing  Auxiliary Modules Exploit Modules Post Modules  Railgun (Windows and ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A @textfiles approach at gathering the world&#39;s DNS - Slides</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2012/2012-02-03-a-textfiles-approach-at-gathering-the-worlds-dns-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2012 17:24:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2012/2012-02-03-a-textfiles-approach-at-gathering-the-worlds-dns-slides/</guid>
      <description>This is my talk that I gave at ShmooCon 2012. It was a great honor to be given the chance to speak at ShmooCon as it has been my second home since 2006 (missed the first one&amp;hellip; havent missed one since)
  A @textfiles approach to gathering the world&amp;#x27;s DNS  from Rob Fuller</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dirty Little Secrets They Didn&#39;t Teach You In Pentesting Class</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2011/2011-10-06-the-dirty-little-secrets-they-didnt-teach-you-in-pentesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2011 15:53:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2011/2011-10-06-the-dirty-little-secrets-they-didnt-teach-you-in-pentesting/</guid>
      <description>Video:  Slides: The Dirty Little Secrets They Didn&amp;rsquo;t Teach You In Pentesting Class [slideshare id=9530403]
Code: https://github.com/mubix/Not-In-Pentesting-Class</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>#DerbyCon Approaches...</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2011/2011-09-17-derbycon-approaches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2011 06:23:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2011/2011-09-17-derbycon-approaches/</guid>
      <description>Chris Gates (@carnal0wnage) and I will be speaking at DerbyCon next week:
The Dirty Little Secrets They Didn&amp;rsquo;t Teach You In Pentesting Class
&amp;ldquo;This talk is about methodologies and tools that we use or have coded that make our lives and pentest schedule a little easier, and why we do things the way we do. Of course, there will be a healthy dose of Metasploit in the mix. &amp;ldquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSA Photos</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2009/2009-04-19-rsa-photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2009 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2009/2009-04-19-rsa-photos/</guid>
      <description>Stolen from: http://www.flickr.com/photos/31513605@N05/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Middler gets released at ShmooCon!</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2009/2009-02-07-the-middler-gets-released-at-shmoocon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 20:22:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2009/2009-02-07-the-middler-gets-released-at-shmoocon/</guid>
      <description>The official link is up and here it is.. well, until they release the beta:
http://inguardians.com/tools/middler-alpha.tgz
 Keep up with http://www.inguardians.com/ for all of their great tools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcasters Meetup at ShmooCon</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2009/2009-01-21-podcasters-meetup-at-shmoocon/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2009 16:21:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2009/2009-01-21-podcasters-meetup-at-shmoocon/</guid>
      <description>More information can be found at http://www.podcastersmeetup.com/
But here is the down and dirty: We are sponsored this year by: HP, SunbeltSoftware, DojoSec, and TheAcademyPro / TheAcademyHome solidly so far.
The following podcasts will be making an appearance:
 Hak5 PaulDotCom CyberSpeak Securabit SploitCast Unpersons Phone Losers of America SMBMinute   And the schedule goes as such:
 1700 - 1800 - Meet and greet, and setup (Everyone involved in the live event please show up as close to this start time as possible) 1800 - 1900 - Live Show (This will probably go over time) 1900 - 1930 - Book signing and transition time 1930 - 2030 - FireTalks (more below) 2030 - 0400 - Food and Drinks on us at local spot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podcaster&#39;s Meetup @ ShmooCon Update 1</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2009/2009-01-20-podcasters-meetup-at-shmoocon-update-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 19:33:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2009/2009-01-20-podcasters-meetup-at-shmoocon-update-1/</guid>
      <description>Sponsors: We have had a lot of great response for everyone on this year&amp;rsquo;s event! I want to reiterate, this event is for podcasters, bloggers, twitter addicts, and everyone in between. I would also like to announce an update to our sponsor&amp;rsquo;s lineup:
TheAcademyPro.com / TheAcademyHome.com &amp;gt; These are twin sites catering videos to the security pro looking to learn about everything from enterprise gear to Maltego, and the home user trying to start the learning about security and how to secure their own computers without going to you the IT guy in the family.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ShmooCon Room Sharing</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-11-14-shmoocon-room-sharing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2008 20:38:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-11-14-shmoocon-room-sharing/</guid>
      <description>Update - Shmoocon already had a list: http://lists.shmoo.com/mailman/listinfo/shmoocon-roommates
Go with what your readers want right? Well I have recently been getting a lot of hits on finding room sharing at ShmooCon. I have done this before at cons and I have met some very interesting people. So I created the google group ShmooCon RoomShare. Post that you are looking, post that you have space. It’s all voluntary and you can sign up for email alerts so that you don’t have to check it all the time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hack or Halo 5 at ShmooCon 2009</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-11-10-hack-or-halo-5-at-shmoocon-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2008 03:05:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-11-10-hack-or-halo-5-at-shmoocon-2009/</guid>
      <description>Even if you have been to ShmooCon, something that alludes most con-goers is the Hack or Halo contest. Most of the time you will see it’s organizers at table near the registration desk getting people signed up. What you may not know is how the whole thing goes down. It’s after hours so, you aren’t missing the great content during the day, and it might save you a few dollars of money spending bar time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Free Pass to CSI 2008</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-10-31-free-pass-to-csi-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2008 06:12:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2008/2008-10-31-free-pass-to-csi-2008/</guid>
      <description>What is CSI? This is what CSI says about it:
 Security is in transition. There is general agreement that security does not work, but not on how to fix it. CSI 2008 is the only event today that faces the challenge to reconsider security. This year at CSI’s annual event, the most innovative minds in security will grapple with the tough questions, providing a reality-check and alternative to cookie-cutter conferences that merely tweak the status quo.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missed Shmoo? Now you can experience in the comfort of your home.</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2007/2007-04-10-missed-shmoo-now-you-can-experience-in-the-comfort-of-your-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2007 12:44:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2007/2007-04-10-missed-shmoo-now-you-can-experience-in-the-comfort-of-your-home/</guid>
      <description>So you couldn&amp;rsquo;t make it. No worry, you have undoubtedly been going through the videos from shmoocon already. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet, you should, they were well done and better than last year. But, what you might not have done yet is the Hack or Halo contests.
 Update: We&amp;rsquo;ve determined the images have become corrupt during one of the transfers and have been taken offline until the problem has been fixed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SploitCast, a Feburary baby, ShmooCon and Tax season</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2006/2006-01-29-sploitcast-a-feburary-baby-shmoocon-and-tax-season/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2006 02:11:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2006/2006-01-29-sploitcast-a-feburary-baby-shmoocon-and-tax-season/</guid>
      <description>Geez. I never have time anymore to put something on this darn thing. I think I am going to stop apologizing for how long it takes me to post, because it is quite quickly becoming the norm. So anyways, since my last post, I have been to ShmooCon &amp;lsquo;06
I met some great people to include but not limited to, Lance James, Kevin Mitnick, Fyodor - A.K.A the creator of NMAP, Skydog, DC-Mike, and Simple Nomad.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ShmooCon 2006</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2005/2005-10-10-shmoocon-2006/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2005 09:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2005/2005-10-10-shmoocon-2006/</guid>
      <description>I did a search on Digg.com and was suprised to see that not a soul has written about ShmooCon 2006. I guess all you west coasters only care about DefCon. That is discrimination and WE DON’T HAVE TO TAKE IT!. Back to reality. Well if you don’t know ShmooCon is basically the DefCon for the east coast and is being held in Washington D.C. . Registration is limited, unlike DefCon, so hurry and whip out those Paypal accounts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>