<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>news on malicious.link</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/categories/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in news on malicious.link</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 16:58:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://malicious.link/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Simplified Astaro UTM now FREE to businesses</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-11-18-a-simplified-astaro-utm-now-free-to-businesses/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2009 16:58:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-11-18-a-simplified-astaro-utm-now-free-to-businesses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I was given a demo license of the new free business product to break/review. No money has traded hands. This is my brutally honest opinion of the product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve played with a gambit of Astaro products, and personally I really hate UTMs, just like I do All-In-One Printer/Copier/Faxes. One thing breaks, they all do. However, Astaro&amp;rsquo;s .. before I go into my opinions of the product, or get on any soap box, here are the facts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Astaro Security Gateway was free for home use already&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(works awesome for VM demos)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;On November 16th 2009, Astaro Security Gateway &amp;ldquo;Essential Firewall Edition&amp;rdquo; is now FREE to any business that wants to run a copy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Essential Firewall Edition is basically a enterprise grade firewall w/ VPN and some reporting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why I like this product is not because it&amp;rsquo;s Astaro, but because it&amp;rsquo;s the bare essentials. It&amp;rsquo;s exactly what a small to mid size business needs for you to stop getting calls from your friend at 5 AM asking why the Linksys you put DD-WRT on to be slick is down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no better gift you can give a business as an IT/Security guy, then the ability to see and log. Test it out, you&amp;rsquo;ll be amazed at what you see on your network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said initially, this is a brutally honest post, and I whole heartedly believe in FREE, and one tool for one job. However so far it&amp;rsquo;s been all fluff and daisies. In coming posts, I&amp;rsquo;ll show how it, and other free alternatives break, or stand up from an attack point of view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a site note, it works flawlessly with the iPhone ;-) - Use public wifi with no less fear, when all of your traffic is going through a VPN automagically. That&amp;rsquo;ll make the boss happy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
