<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Social Engineering on </title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/categories/social-engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Social Engineering on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 17:34:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://malicious.link/categories/social-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Engineering Challenges Back</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2008/2008-10-09-social-engineering-challenges-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 17:34:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2008/2008-10-09-social-engineering-challenges-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got an overwhelming response to me stopping the social engineering challenges, which far out-shadows the large response I got against the challenges. In other words, the &amp;ldquo;AYE&amp;rdquo;s have it. As soon as my Maltego series comes to a close I will be starting the challenges back up again. Thank you for your support and I look forward to the continuation of the challenges, I really had fun with the first one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, if you have ideas for scenarios, please email me or hit me up on twitter. Include as much detail as possible, especially with the answer. Or, if you want to, leave the answer out, and we&amp;rsquo;ll see what we come up with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks again,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mubix&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Engineering Challenge #1 Answer</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2008/2008-10-09-social-engineering-challenge-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2008 04:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2008/2008-10-09-social-engineering-challenge-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well, it’s not the only answer but I will call them that because it’s what worked for me:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sitting a couple rows down from the line so that no one would see me from the bus line I was targeting, I waited for the bus to come. As soon as it came rolling up and quickly moved into a dash for the door, timing it so that I could cut in line to be the 4th on. When contronted by the bus driver, I said that I had dropped my wallet a few stops back and and wanted to find it. Dropping my wallet while I ‘looked’ for it allowed me to certify this lie. I asked the busdriver if I could ride the bus back around to my original stop. He said yes and I was allowed to ride free of charge. And, due to all of this drama the target was already seated and others have taken up bubble-room spots (no body likes to sit together), so I didn’t look completely odd sitting next to the target. I even got up when a elderly woman came to sit down. By that time dialog was already started with the target and my honor was solidified by my kindness to others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These challenges don’t have prizes or winners, it’s just here to make you think. The goal is not to raise too much suspicion and gain trust.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social Engineering Challenge #1</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2008/2008-10-08-social-engineering-challenge-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2008 02:29:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2008/2008-10-08-social-engineering-challenge-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here is the scenerio:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a line of government, and commerical workers that are in line for the bus. The bus is late, and everyone has had a long day of work. Your target is the first person in line. The line is 75 people long for a bus with a max occupancy of 35 people. Your target is the same sex as you and has headphones in their ears. You can use any prop item that would not look out of place in line for a bus with other commuters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your goal is to sit next to your target in order to start a dialog. You do not need to be 1st, 2nd or even 3rd in line, but you do have to get on the bus with the least amount of suspicion raised. (That doesn’t rule out being flambouant)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comment your solutions with detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EDIT: I will post how I was able to do it tomorrow. For all of these challenges I will publish the way I succeeded at 11:59 PM EST of the next day.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
