<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>solarwinds - Tag - Malicious Link - Blog by mubix - Rob Fuller</title>
        <link>https://malicious.link/tags/solarwinds/</link>
        <description>solarwinds - Tag - Malicious Link - Blog by mubix - Rob Fuller</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>mubix@hak5.org (Rob Fuller)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>mubix@hak5.org (Rob Fuller)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:30:44 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://malicious.link/tags/solarwinds/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>SolarFlare Release: Password Dumper for SolarWinds Orion</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2020/solarflare-release-password-dumper-for-solarwinds-orion/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:30:44 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Rob Fuller</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2020/solarflare-release-password-dumper-for-solarwinds-orion/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[TL;DR Here are the concerns I have regarding the SolarWinds/FireEye breach:
The accounts stored in an organization&rsquo;s SolarWinds Orion may be underestimated. I recently did a pentest for a firm that had over 200 credentials stored in their SolarWinds Orion database, but only 15 showed in the interface (the SolarWinds credential interface is complicated with sections for each connection type and different panes for each, it may also not properly delete credentials from the database when &ldquo;removed&rdquo; from the interface, I am unsure).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Erlang Authenticated Remote Code Execution</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2018/erlang-arce/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 15 Sep 2018 09:30:44 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Rob Fuller</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2018/erlang-arce/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Erlang is a programming language that I have tried to learn a few times in the past but never really dug in, that is, until recently.
Erlang is an interesting language because it has &ldquo;built-in concurrency, distribution, and fault tolerance&rdquo;. To me, this means that it does job queuing and distributed tasks right out of the gate.
A little bit of history I first started digging into Erlang again from an attackers point of view at BSides Philadelphia 2016, where I talked about SolarWinds ORION.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
