<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rant on malicious.link</title>
    <link>/categories/rant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rant on malicious.link</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 22:42:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="/categories/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Alive Again</title>
      <link>/post/2014/2014-01-09-alive-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 22:42:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2014/2014-01-09-alive-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a rather long hiatus from blogging. This is mostly because I was fed up with the blogging platform that I had (Squarespace) and didn&amp;rsquo;t really have any alternatives that met all of the features I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, where am I at now? Github actually. Github allows users to create &amp;ldquo;Github Pages&amp;rdquo; for repositories (or be it&amp;rsquo;s own repo). For the most part these pages are written in Markdown. It&amp;rsquo;s late and I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like looking up who, but someone created a project called &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; which is a Ruby based static page generator and then another project called &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://octopress.org/&#34;&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; popped up using Jekyll to create a static html based blogging platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a pain in the butt to use and learn, but once you have a few things automated it gets simpler. It also hits the most bullet points of any other option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect things to pick up pretty quickly here, but as I&amp;rsquo;m typing this I&amp;rsquo;m already thinking that promising something like that is a bad idea. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how it goes, it&amp;rsquo;s just good to be back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problems with blogging software</title>
      <link>/post/2013/2013-08-10-problems-with-blogging-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2013/2013-08-10-problems-with-blogging-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Problems are that everyone does this whole blogging thing in so many different ways. Me, personally? I like to have a client that I can save drafts it, work on things a little bit here and there and then finalize stuff when I&amp;rsquo;m ready to post. I have a couple dozen of these posts ready and set with final tweaks needed but my blogging software Squarespace up and moved on to &amp;ldquo;Squarespace 6&amp;rdquo;. The the current stage you don&amp;rsquo;t have to move to 6 but at some point the owners of Squarespace are going to force everyone over. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to wait for that to happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Octopress and Postach.io are my favorite options right now. Both blog in markdown language which is ok. Converting 8 years of blog posts to markdown is going to be a lot of work but a one time deal. Plus it would give me a chance to go through and fix the things that were broken over the years of modified blogging clients and services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Postach.io has one major downside, they don&amp;rsquo;t have good &amp;ldquo;code&amp;rdquo; block support, whereas Octopress/Jekyll have excellent support as well code hilighting. The major upside? It&amp;rsquo;s based on Evernote. Which means I can blog from whereever I have Evernote. They also used to have an EXCELLENT feature that seems to have disappeared where if you updated a post it would automatically throw the blog post up to the top of your page, meaning your update would get back in your RSS feed and the update wouldn&amp;rsquo;t go unnoticed as most updates to blog posts do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is on your dream team red team?</title>
      <link>/post/2012/2012-03-04-who-is-on-your-dream-team-red-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2012 10:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2012/2012-03-04-who-is-on-your-dream-team-red-team/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was an honest idea to help identify people that might not get the media attention of other &amp;ldquo;Top X in Infosec&amp;rdquo; lists. But I should have known better than to put a poll on the internet&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPU Cracking Complaints</title>
      <link>/post/2011/2011-07-13-gpu-cracking-complaints/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 14:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2011/2011-07-13-gpu-cracking-complaints/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been cracking passwords for a while and use a myriad of tools in a certain order to get the job done. I find that Cain is still my Go-to for allowing me to visualize the process and do some basic sorting (really wish I could search in-app). But I&amp;rsquo;ve been asking around on twitter some questions like Why is GPU cracking for 50k hashes faster than Rainbow Tables (most say the bottleneck is the HDD read style and speed) and many asked what all of my compalints are so I figured this would be the best place (vice multiple emails)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCLAIMER&lt;/strong&gt;: I have very little crypto knowledge and even less GPU programming knowledge so I only get to complain as a user and not as someone who can actually fix the things I complain about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of LM support. I get that this is a complicated hashing algorithm, but the fact that 90% of companies still have it turned on and cracking any more than a few with Rainbow Tables is impractical unless you have a SSD raid with a GPU based cracker ($$$$$).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of dictionary support. Right now the best way to crack passwords is with oclhashcat-plus since it is GPU based and supports rules, multiple hashes (hash files) and directories of hashes. However, it has a very limited list of hashes it supports (No LM, SHA1, etc..) and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t support dump formats, so you need to strip the file so it just has the hash (this is more of just a bother than a gripe).

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I say &amp;lsquo;The best way&amp;rsquo; because anything that has a key space larger than upper-alpha-numeric-32symbol (LM) is just a bit nuts to try and brute force out of the gate unless your goal is to &amp;lsquo;crack them all&amp;rsquo;. Me as a pentester, I want to get as many as possible, as quick as possible, so this means dictionaries are the smarter option. (Maybe later I can do the straight brute if I really need / want to)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of POT. For some reason every cracking app on the planet, save for JtR, thinks it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to crack the same hash multiple times. I wish even Cain would keep a secret store of all the hashes it&amp;rsquo;s cracked stripped of anything unimportant (need the salt (username) sometimes) and store it in the background so that if it comes across the same hash it can say &amp;ldquo;oo oo I know this one&amp;rdquo; and auto populate it even before I start cracking. Why more cracking software writers don&amp;rsquo;t do this I&amp;rsquo;ll never know (would make their software seem a ton faster the more it is used)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of formatting documentation (#ripshairout). Rare is the time I&amp;rsquo;ve found a cracking program that shows you how it wants to consume a hash. JtR is the most egregious offenders of this but they all do it. One would think people would try and make it easy for people to use their software (give examples of what shit is supposed to look like at least if you don&amp;rsquo;t support standard formats)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those are my biggest gripes that the moment. If I am wrong on any account, let me know, I would love to know of a better way to do things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insider Threat Testing</title>
      <link>/post/2011/2011-01-27-insider-threat-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 15:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2011/2011-01-27-insider-threat-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/postimages/201101_insider_1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This day and age everyone is worried about the insider threat. Internal Penetration Testing doesn&amp;rsquo;t really test what would happen if your janitor got paid 50 bucks to put a USB stick in one of your servers. External Penetration Tests are never scoped for that sort of testing. So what is a company to do? How can they know what the risk is? The answer? Usually they guess or assume. Mostly because they are scared to find out, it&amp;rsquo;s happened to them before, or one of a million different justifications. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a webinar coming up to describe exactly this type of testing, but I thought I&amp;rsquo;d go into it a bit here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The FBI has a files upon files and stories stacked miles high about spies and insiders taking everything from accounting information (I could have put LIVES for effect but that&amp;rsquo;s more of a one-off) to staplers (no I don&amp;rsquo;t think Milton has an FBI file). Insiders throughout time have been the biggest threat to organizations even before sabotage and espionage became words. Ok, so what&amp;rsquo;s the big build up for? Simple. We need to build organizations up in the detection department from a pentesters point of view, not signature based. Our pentesters need to talk to our forensics guys, the incident responders need to talk to pentesters and every which way between. We are loosing this battle, and one of the reasons we are is we keep our bag of tricks to our selves, and that&amp;rsquo;s what insider threat testing is all about, getting all the tricks tested in a more open fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Can your organization see a command and control session via IRC? What if it&amp;rsquo;s pushed over port 80? What about a standard meterpreter reverse_tcp connection? There isn&amp;rsquo;t a money based solution for this, just like there isn&amp;rsquo;t for phishing. Added on to all of the other things your security team does, there needs to be an employee, or a consultant that it is on the phone with your team saying &amp;ldquo;did you see this?&amp;rdquo;. Sort of like the &amp;lsquo;Can you hear me now?&amp;rsquo; test. I mean, have you ever met an incident response team that took time out of their day to see if they could get poison ivy (one of the most well known RATS /remote access tools/) through the firewall undetected? Probably, but when they came and told you about it you chastised them for it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/postimages/201101_insider_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, I&amp;rsquo;ve jumped around roles in this post a lot and I want to focus it back on getting true collaborative testing done, but there has to be a balance. If you&amp;rsquo;re staring at a piece of earth, you&amp;rsquo;ll see the ant walk on by, but you&amp;rsquo;ll probably miss a half dozen of them on your way to check the mail. So how do you do this? Why not make it an educational process? Have the senior staff on the phone with the tester, and then tell the junior guys something like &amp;ldquo;We just had a breach and it&amp;rsquo;s starting exfil data to this IP: x.x.x.x&amp;rdquo;. Give them a chance to find it then work through with them where / what happened, and why or why not any alerts or alarms went of and if they saw it in their normal flow. Ideally they spot it before the senior staff even mention it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, this will not fit into the &amp;lsquo;I give you report you give me money&amp;rsquo; scenario. Companies should consider it a training exercise where they get instant and obvious benefit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are many other arenas this helps in too. For example phishing, you know how much harder it will be for an attacker to get a payload to work if you&amp;rsquo;ve already tested, detected and have traps (we&amp;rsquo;ll go into setting traps another time) for all the public avenues of C&amp;amp;C and exfiltration? They will get frustrated, and you&amp;rsquo;ll know that you&amp;rsquo;re being attacked. A proactive stance is what &amp;lsquo;testing&amp;rsquo; is all about, and this is a extremely neglected aspect of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No one will solve &amp;lsquo;security&amp;rsquo;, all we are here to do is minimize the attack surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come to the webinar to heckle, learn, or just hear more, or don&amp;rsquo;t. I just wanted to get this out there and ask the question: Can your most important data leave on a fake Lady Gaga CD without you knowing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Let me squash something real quick. No this is not a new idea. The prevention side is talked about ad nauseum, but hardly anyone talks about testing to see what could really happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jailbreak SSH horrors strike back</title>
      <link>/post/2010/2010-08-04-jailbreak-ssh-horrors-strike-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 04:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2010/2010-08-04-jailbreak-ssh-horrors-strike-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2009 the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.jeltel.com.au/2009/11/interview-with-ikee-iphone-virus.html&#34;&gt;ikee&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; rick-rolling worm went around the iPhone world via the password of &amp;lsquo;alpine&amp;rsquo; on the root account. You are now warned to change your root password when you pop into Cydia and Rock the first time. But this thing just wont stay down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have jailbroken your iPad you might want to check out a little file called &amp;ldquo;master.passwd&amp;rdquo;. In it, there is another user called &amp;lsquo;mobile&amp;rsquo; which has been pointed out since 2008 (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.macosxhints.com/article.php?story=20080224231344798&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) on the iPhone as another account to change the password of. But the media and Cydia/Rock warnings only put emphasis on &amp;lsquo;root&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many iPad and iPhone apps STILL do not use the &amp;ldquo;keyring&amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo; and store your password in plain text or somewhere in a binary file (still plaintext), which the user &amp;ldquo;mobile&amp;rdquo; has access to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[](/images/postimages/201008_jailbreak_1.png)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ok, &amp;ldquo;so what&amp;rdquo; you say. Since this recent jailbreak was using a website, the individuals running that site now have the IP address of freshly jailbroken iPhones and iPads. I am certainly not saying that they have any ill intentions, but sites have been broken into before, and that would be one hell of a gold mine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully AT&amp;amp;T has put in blocks of some sort so that it&amp;rsquo;s customers are protected, but who knows what the other countries around the world that carry iPhones are doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But at the very least, if you have jailbroken your iPhone, iPod Touch or iPad, please.. please set your passwords accordingly and do not have it a simple dictionary password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Remember, you ARE giving up some security when you jail break your phone. It is on you to make sure that you lock what you can back down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To change your password, use &amp;lsquo;Terminal&amp;rsquo; and log in to one account at a time and issue the &amp;ldquo;passwd&amp;rdquo; command. You can also just log in to root and issue the &amp;ldquo;passwd mobile&amp;rdquo; command to change the password of mobile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; on 2010-08-09 19:39 by Rob Fuller&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten a lot of comments stating that OpenSSH isn&amp;rsquo;t installed by default and that this is not a big deal at all. A couple problems exist in that argument though:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Jailbreak is executing code on your phone/touch/ipad. Unless you do a analysis of the entire disk, you can&amp;rsquo;t be sure the jailbreak doesn&amp;rsquo;t leave some other way into the phone. Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s a far fetched chance, but most users would never know.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even if you don&amp;rsquo;t install it Out-of-the-box. There is a good possibility that you will OpenSSH at a later date. Better to get it fixed while you have it on the mind.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vuln Disclosure Summarized</title>
      <link>/post/2010/2010-04-29-vuln-disclosure-summarized/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 03:05:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2010/2010-04-29-vuln-disclosure-summarized/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I have an admittedly limited view of the exploit dev world. However, from what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen devs have very few options: (Please correct me if I&amp;rsquo;m wrong)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;responsible-disclosure&#34;&gt;Responsible Disclosure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Direct Contact =&amp;gt; depending on the size of the vendor and their view on security, this could result in anything from a simple thanks, a reward, to a court hearing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploit Broker =&amp;gt; possibly sell, possibly not, depends on the broker. The vuln could die on the table or stolen due to too much information being given during negotiations. This route has the same financial risk as direct contact, but a lot less risk of getting sued.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ZDI (or other vuln clearing house) =&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;instant&amp;rdquo; cash, but admittedly less than an Exploit Broker could possible get based on the financial risk to ZDI. Close to zero risk of court time (they may come after you for selling the exploit). And a lot less financial risk since (IIRC) they pay up front. But then the vulns go to also undisclosed parties, potentially the highest bidder which is probably not the vendor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;other&amp;rdquo; secretive groups who share vulns for different reasons&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just to friends =&amp;gt; No cash, no judicial risk, but you do risk them stealing/selling your exploit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;full-disclosure&#34;&gt;Full Disclosure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posting it to the web for all to see/user =&amp;gt; Possible court time, but the definite upside is the vendor is forced to react. A very quick way to make enemies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Releasing at a conference =&amp;gt; Probable court time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;no-disclosure&#34;&gt;No Disclosure&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeping it to yourself =&amp;gt; Working under the assumption that your the only one that has found that same bug is still semi relevant due to the incredibly small size of the exploit dev community. However, as Dave said, they&amp;rsquo;ll be toasting to their sleeping dead 0days some day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;no-more-free-bugs&#34;&gt;No More Free Bugs&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My stance on this is split, while I think people should get paid for their work, I relate this movement to mowing someone&amp;rsquo;s lawn and then ringing their doorbell and asking for money. However I&amp;rsquo;m sure Robert Graham&amp;rsquo;s punch in the face metaphor also works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like, I have stated above, I am far and away a newbie to the vuln disclosure world and this debate has been going on since before I owned my own computer, but with the brilliant minds working at it, why doesn&amp;rsquo;t anyone offer up a solid solution to it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My solution? Create a standard, something that we all abide by. I know as hackers we rebel against such things but in the interest of getting better security out there (yes, that&amp;rsquo;s what we are here for right?&amp;hellip;. right?) we should should really work together on this. What sounds right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean, what is the right way to approach someone who&amp;rsquo;s lawn you&amp;rsquo;ve mowed for the work you have done? Maybe free for open source projects, and a price based on exploitability and market share of the affected product?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vuln Trading Markets and You by Michal Zalewski (lcamtuf):&lt;br /&gt;
=&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://lcamtuf.blogspot.com/2010/04/vulnerability-trading-markets-and-you.html&#34;&gt;http://lcamtuf.blogspot.com/2010/04/vulnerability-trading-markets-and-you.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vuln Disclosure is Rude by Robert Graham:&lt;br /&gt;
=&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://erratasec.blogspot.com/2010/04/vuln-disclosure-is-rude.html&#34;&gt;http://erratasec.blogspot.com/2010/04/vuln-disclosure-is-rude.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No More Free Bugs movement by Charlie Miller, Alex Sotirov and Dino Dai Zovi:&lt;br /&gt;
=&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://trailofbits.com/2009/03/22/no-more-free-bugs/&#34;&gt;http://trailofbits.com/2009/03/22/no-more-free-bugs/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dailydave Post by Dave Aitel:&lt;br /&gt;
=&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://lists.immunitysec.com/pipermail/dailydave/2010-April/006100.html&#34;&gt;http://lists.immunitysec.com/pipermail/dailydave/2010-April/006100.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security (CAN BE) an ART not a SCIENCE</title>
      <link>/post/2010/2010-01-26-security-can-be-an-art-not-a-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 14:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2010/2010-01-26-security-can-be-an-art-not-a-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is far from a new idea, however it&amp;rsquo;s not something that is easily provable. So I had an idea this morning. I posed the following question on Twitter:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/postimages/201001_art_1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know what I got in return? a resounding &amp;ldquo;No&amp;rdquo; from everyone. (well I had &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/falconsview/status/8235524239&#34;&gt;one outlier&lt;/a&gt; but, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t when you are trying to apply science to prove art) I challenge you to name another non-artistic career that people are so passionate about that they would stay in it even if they won the lottery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are a few that I would like to highlight:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/schuetzdj&#34;&gt;@schuetzdj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/postimages/201001_art_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TomSellers&#34;&gt;@TomSellers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/postimages/201001_art_3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ethicalhack3r&#34;&gt;@ethicalhack3r&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/postimages/201001_art_4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dookie2000ca&#34;&gt;@dookie2000ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/postimages/201001_art_5.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a somewhat surprising outcome. See a trend? Most people wanted to quit their jobs, and start their own infosec company. Why is this? Is it just &amp;ldquo;The American Dream&amp;rdquo; or is it because they are unhappy with the current people in leadership? Or is it simply the fact that they are hindered from actually pursuing and learning hacking/security at work? The world may never know, but I do implore firms to look at the retention rate of their &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; talent. (No, I don&amp;rsquo;t buy into the No Infosec Peep left behind bull).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a rumor that Google has a practice. 2 hours a day, you (an employee of Google) are REQUIRED to work on a project of your own, that is in no way indebted or owned by Google, even after completion. I can imagine the above answers would change if that were the case where they worked. If their employers fostered learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a result of Infosec / Hacking being an art, do we have our premadonas? Of course. But do we also have our Van Gogh&amp;rsquo;s and Michelangelo&amp;rsquo;s? Definitely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, time for a bit of a reality check:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/daveshackleford&#34;&gt;@daveshackleford&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/postimages/201001_art_6.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ya, you have NO idea what you would really do with millions of instant cash. I think the number is some 80% of lottery winners go BANKRUPT in the first 10 years. This is because you, and EVERYONE you have ANY connection to, goes absolutely crazy. To the point that there are lottery winner support groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the fact that people say it now, shows that they at least have the passion for the art. (or are just fronting)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here some &lt;strong&gt;honest&lt;/strong&gt; answers to even out the tide:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/shmoosr&#34;&gt;@shmoosr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/postimages/201001_art_7.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Bolster&#34;&gt;@Bolster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/postimages/201001_art_8.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/andrewsmhay&#34;&gt;@andrewsmhay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/postimages/201001_art_9.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I believe that hacking is a science, until passion adds the artistic fire to the mix. At least that&amp;rsquo;s what I think, draw your own conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(That&amp;rsquo;s another thing I love about this field, you are constantly challenged to draw your own conclusions, to think, to learn, to improve, to be… better)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linked in to Twitter</title>
      <link>/post/2009/2009-12-22-linked-in-to-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 15:13:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009/2009-12-22-linked-in-to-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed, LinkedIn has started allowing you to link your Twitter account to your LinkedIn account. So, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know this (since I opted out), but apparently LinkedIn will kick your status updates to Twitter&amp;hellip; like when you get a new job&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/postimages/200912_linkedin_1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privacy settings out the window! Woohoo for Web 2.0!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop blaming the admins!</title>
      <link>/post/2009/2009-11-19-stop-blaming-the-admins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 04:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009/2009-11-19-stop-blaming-the-admins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We (the security community) all know, and make fun of &amp;ldquo;Users&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Admins&amp;rdquo;. They are derogatory terms in our community. So much so, that they could almost be classified at curse words. (I can see the XKCD now: Security stick figure talking to IT stick figure. &amp;ldquo;You stupid A****&amp;ldquo;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I neither discount their &amp;ldquo;contribution&amp;rdquo; to making my day fun, I feel that a lot of people miss an even bigger threat: Policies and Procedures, or SOP (Standard Operating Procedures). Those words are virtual kryptonite to anyone in IT, more so to &amp;lsquo;security professionals&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what makes them a threat? Two thing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone hates them so they are rarely updated (you know.. like Windows.. stay with me)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since they are rarely updated, and sometimes even those that are, are written poorly, or actually create vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example lets make all the local admin passwords something really difficult and long, and… all the same so that we can easily administer every machine. This makes it to updates go smoothly and group policy… Oh wait… we don&amp;rsquo;t have those problems anymore (or at least they aren&amp;rsquo;t based on local authentication issues).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, policies and documented procedures are good things. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying they aren&amp;rsquo;t. What I am saying is that when those documented procedures and policies that we blindly follow because the guy that trained me said so, just doesn&amp;rsquo;t cut it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admins: Challenge that policy, find out the reason why you do what they want you to do. The worst that could happen is you could learn something new. The best is that you could change your company&amp;rsquo;s security posture for the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security Pros: Time to get off your A**** and update the wiki! (or the doc/site/binder) so that your predecessor, or someone new to your team can hit the ground running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also challenge you to look at internet policies/procedures… oh wait.. they call those features.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APPLE: A Modern Day Willy Wonka Story</title>
      <link>/post/2009/2009-10-12-apple-a-modern-day-willy-wonka-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 15:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009/2009-10-12-apple-a-modern-day-willy-wonka-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yes, I just called everyone who works at Apple an Oompa Loompa, but I digress:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was reading Brooke Crothers&amp;rsquo; story on the Apple &amp;lsquo;gag&amp;rsquo; order [1] and couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but think of how Apple has created an almost similar situation. Everyone wants to know what Apple is up to, can&amp;rsquo;t stop talking about it. Buzz Out Loud [2] even had people call and email asking them to see if they could do a show without mentioning Apple or the iPhone. According to Brooke&amp;rsquo;s article, people are afraid for their very jobs (pun?) even in the mentioning of Apple. What&amp;rsquo;s behind the curtains at Apple? Is Steve Jobs going to send out 5 golden Apple Tablets? Probably not, but I can&amp;rsquo;t shake the image of Steve coming out on stage to do one of his presentations with a cane and doing a fake fall to the podium.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I pose this crucial question to you, the reader: Who plays the part of Slugworth?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.cnet.com/8301-13924_3-10372535-64.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20&#34;&gt;http://news.cnet.com/8301-13924_3-10372535-64.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href=&#34;http://bol.cnet.com&#34;&gt;http://bol.cnet.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back on Twitter</title>
      <link>/post/2009/2009-10-11-back-on-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 19:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009/2009-10-11-back-on-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been debating making this kind of post for about a week, and I apologize for the RSS spam. But it was getting a bit repetitive telling people via DM, email or other communication what happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I took my hiatus from Twitter, I zero&amp;rsquo;d out my followers, so, if you care to, please check to see if you are still following me. I will be watching my follows closely and will refollow people I might have missed in my initial run through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/mubix&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/mubix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks,
Rob&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corrections and Questions about Nessus on Securabit</title>
      <link>/post/2009/2009-09-16-corrections-and-questions-about-nessus-on-securabit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2009 17:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009/2009-09-16-corrections-and-questions-about-nessus-on-securabit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt; I can&amp;rsquo;t say with 100% certainty that Nessus ever used NMAP as it&amp;rsquo;s base scanner, I was going off of memory. I apologize for not being perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update 2&lt;/em&gt; Since people can&amp;rsquo;t seem to let it go, I would say that I was totally wrong and the nmap was absolutely never used in nessus ever, but then I would be caught in another absolute that I can&amp;rsquo;t confirm. According to their wiki, the nmap nasl script were taken out because people were No, I haven&amp;rsquo;t listened to the latest episode of Securabit in which Paul comes on and talks about Nessus. If he states in there that nmap was never the port scanning engine for nessus, then please go bug him if you think he is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update 3&lt;/em&gt; Ron Gula of Tenable has confirmed via email that Nessus has never used nmap as it&amp;rsquo;s base scanner. Also, Attrition.org posted a bit of history on the subject: &lt;a href=&#34;http://attrition.org/misc/ee/nessus_and_nmap.html&#34;&gt;http://attrition.org/misc/ee/nessus_and_nmap.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.securabit.com/&#34;&gt;Securabit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.securabit.com/2009/08/25/securabit-episode-37-%e2%80%93-mapping-networks-with-fyodor-and-nmap/&#34;&gt; Episode 37&lt;/a&gt; - I made the statement that some people could be running nmap and not even know it. While this could still hold true, the context I put around it. &amp;ldquo;Nessus uses nmap for scanning&amp;rdquo; showed my years a bit. That statement is now a falsehood. Nessus uses it&amp;rsquo;s own &amp;ldquo;optimized&amp;rdquo; port scanner. I put quotes around the word &amp;ldquo;optimized&amp;rdquo; simply because I don&amp;rsquo;t know what tweaks that have been done. Paul Asadorian from PaulDotCom Security Weekly sent an email into Securabit letting us know of the error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t take the news very gallantly, but Paul was nice enough to lay out how someone would go about using nmap with Nessus these day. Those steps are pretty drawn out too, which I find kinda disheartining that not only do you not have nmap as your base port scanner, but the NASL scripts to use nmap are no longer included in the base install of Nessus (according to Paul, I haven&amp;rsquo;t confirmed that, but he does work for the company). And who knows why they decided to leave those script out, but you will have your chance to ask those questions because Paul will be on Securabit LIVE tonight to tie up any loose ends and talk about Nessus tonight at 8 PM EST (September 16th 2009).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For more info about tonight&amp;rsquo;s show:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.securabit.com/2009/09/15/securabit-live-wednesday-with-paul-asadoorian-from-pauldotcom/&#34;&gt;http://www.securabit.com/2009/09/15/securabit-live-wednesday-with-paul-asadoorian-from-pauldotcom/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplicity is Security</title>
      <link>/post/2009/2009-08-13-simplicity-is-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 15:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009/2009-08-13-simplicity-is-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Per the best of the best in presenting, what breeds a good presentation slide deck? Simplicity&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to pose a statement. &amp;ldquo;Simplicity is Security&amp;rdquo;. The reason I say this is that this day in age, at least in the US, &amp;lsquo;convenience&amp;rsquo; is king. And we try to protect those conveniences with &amp;lsquo;security&amp;rsquo;. Let me start over a bit, this train of thought all started when I started to explain the insecurities in WiMAX to my wife. We saw a WiMAX device that plugged straight into your computer. I told her this was bad because by connecting to this you have no barrier between you and the &amp;lsquo;bad guys&amp;rsquo; other than possibly the Windows Firewall. Her answer surprised me. &amp;lsquo;So?&amp;rsquo; is all she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Japan doesn&amp;rsquo;t use &amp;lsquo;Check Cards&amp;rsquo; or even really credit cards for that matter. To get such a card you need to go through a book worth of paper work, so it&amp;rsquo;s just not &amp;lsquo;convenient&amp;rsquo; for most people, so they don&amp;rsquo;t get them. So guess what? They don&amp;rsquo;t bank online, and they don&amp;rsquo;t buy stuff online. I racked my brain to figure out what possibly could be on her computer that a &amp;lsquo;bad guy&amp;rsquo; would want. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of anything (maybe you can). The government relies on paper backups of anything electronic (so they hardly make electronic versions). Signatures are based on stamps that are difficult to copy. The worst a hacker could do on her computer is use it as a zombie, and even then, their ISPs detect and disconnect excessive use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where did we as &amp;ldquo;Security Professionals&amp;rdquo; go wrong? Was it the fat paychecks we wanted? Was it the fear of the &amp;lsquo;underground&amp;rsquo;? Reality seems to dictate that we will continue on this path from the analog to the digital, from paper and clerks to networks and AI. The question I want to ask you though is; Should we continue down the path of &amp;ldquo;MORE SECURITY&amp;rdquo; or should we deviate a bit for simpler, possibly non-technical practices?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In these last two posts you may assume that I favor the Japanese culture and way of life over a US one. You would be mistaken, I simply learn, take the best parts of what I learn, and try to apply them where I can. Learning from others triumphs and defeats, strengths and weaknesses is a basic human function that we a humanoids should embrace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applied Network Security Density</title>
      <link>/post/2009/2009-08-12-applied-network-security-density/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 15:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009/2009-08-12-applied-network-security-density/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently visited Tokyo, Japan. Just as always, my curiosity got the best of me and I started to calculate the population density of the buildings where I was staying. Giving fudge factor of non-populated apartments, I estimated 8,500 families in twelve 15 story buildings, living in a 1.5 mile square piece of land.That&amp;rsquo;s CRAZY. Mass transit and unrestricted modes of transit are not a whim, they are a requirement. I bet you&amp;rsquo;re asking how this applies to security, or for that matter computers at all. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t. But one of it&amp;rsquo;s effects does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an effect of this density, the Mom &amp;amp; Pap stores businesses flourish. In it&amp;rsquo;s density, the &amp;ldquo;big iron&amp;rdquo; is just too inconvenient, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. I used the reference for a reason. It was my own mental bridge between the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; and security world (anyone who denies the difference is confused, and/or just left DefCon).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is the &amp;ldquo;Big Iron&amp;rdquo; in the security world? Central management, Correlation, and other ways of supposedly spending &amp;ldquo;less&amp;rdquo; on security by having less points of failure. So this is where I stray from the path. I think that networks need to mimic their worldly equivalent. Large organizations need to take an page from Tokyo and decentralize. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s hard getting &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; people, and trust is not something we easily come by in this industry, but from an offensive point of view, centralization just means a bigger payoff. Higher walls, maybe, but an &amp;lsquo;easier&amp;rsquo; target to zero in on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does this mean? I eluded to it a bit in my previous paragraph, but what it means is more hands on. We need to train the &amp;lsquo;security guards&amp;rsquo; of our network and put them at every location we have a grouping of nodes. The smaller the grouping of nodes the better. VLANs are not enough. I&amp;rsquo;m going to use the the dreaded &amp;ldquo;Defense in Depth&amp;rdquo; phrase: We need to make our defense in depth smaller, more compact. Make it to the point where you don&amp;rsquo;t NEED &amp;ldquo;Big Iron&amp;rdquo; because you have such small perimeters that open source stuff on an old *nix box would work just fine. Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an exaggeration but you get the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every city is different and unique, as is any network, and I am by no means saying that decentralization is for everyone. What I do think is that big organizations are getting too hung up on devices and one stop shops where they can set up a NOC and expect a number, however many, of people to be able to watch everything going on. Exactly the way that corporations lose touch with their employees because of their size, they are loosing touch with their network and how it works. How many places have you worked that they have a good diagram of nodes (not just subnets) on their network? Much less documentation on those nodes. How exactly are you supposed to centrally monitor something you have very little knowledge of? Will it take as many years as it did with personnel to reconnect with the life of the network? Probably, but I hope not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, I am open to debate and hearing about flaws in my logic, so please leave a comment and tell me what you think.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lies</title>
      <link>/post/2009/2009-08-12-lies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 09:11:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009/2009-08-12-lies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I was in middle school, I told a lie. I was so good at telling lies, and remembering even the infinite details of these lies that I could make them believable. Later in life, I learned that this skill was called “Social Engineering ;-)”, but back to the story; I told everyone that I had won a shopping spree at “Incredible Universe”, now named “Fry’s”. Even the teacher believed me. The kids made lists of what they wanted me to get for them, and I strung it on for way too long. You tell a lie like that though and you get caught eventually. As I did, and learned a hard lesson. At that time in my life I was going through some really rough waters, and having everyone “like” me for even that finite amount of time, helped me cope. Does that make it right? Definitely not. But I remember that experience to this day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why tell you all this? Because this post is both self serving (as it will make it impossible for me to lie about the following any more) and apologetic. I have lied to those I call friend. Recently these lies were told to some very good friends and I had my first physical reaction to the guilt of telling them. I was literally unable to eat that night. Enough stalling and making excuses here they are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I am not a Marine Scout Sniper, nor ever been to Marine Scout Sniper school. I truly wish I had been and admire all those who have made it through.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have never been to SEARS training.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The gentleman by the name of Fuzzy, was a gas attendant with me. Great guy, but he wasn’t an explosives expert in Okinawa to the best of my knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Never met the Rock Marines of Korea, or for that matter trained with any other foreign military.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have never been to a Masseuse school, but I give great massages, ask anyone.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was never a bouncer in NY or lived there. Only been there twice on vacation, but love the city, and the Yankees (although I have no idea who plays for or owns the team) nor do I follow them, or for that matter any sports team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have been a bartender, but it was for a base beach snack bar that I followed mix solutions on a printed paper for, so I know absolutely nothing about mixed drinks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have never told these lies during an interview or any other formal means, but I have told them to friends and acquaintances. I would like to apologize to all of them, here and now. I originally thought I should email them, but decided this public forum was a better and a bit more transparent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are the lies damaging to anyone but me? Did I have to tell anyone? No, not really. Would someone figure out that they were lies? There is a small chance. But that’s not the point. I try to be as brutally honest as I can with people, and I want that to extend to things about myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of me what you will, and I am deeply sorry if I misrepresented myself to you in any fashion at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rob&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sexism and the religion of hackers</title>
      <link>/post/2009/2009-07-13-sexism-and-the-religion-of-hackers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 19:36:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009/2009-07-13-sexism-and-the-religion-of-hackers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Let me preempt this post with the following facts: I am a white male veteran with amazing parents. I went to a good school, and was never under-valued by the people I cared about. I fit no minority profiles in other words. I tell you this so that you can latch on to it as why I don&amp;rsquo;t understand anything in your rebuttal. But I think this gives me a unique view on the issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;People are stupid. They will believe a lie because they want to believe it&amp;rsquo;s true, or because they are afraid it might be true.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;mdash;-Wizard&amp;rsquo;s First Rule - By Terry Goodkind&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post was a long time coming. I feel pretty passionate about &amp;ldquo;my community&amp;rdquo;. I don&amp;rsquo;t say that in a lead-follower sense, but more of a Kum Ba Ya one. The feather that pushed this post over the edge into existence is @&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/shazzzam&#34;&gt;shazzzam&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rsquo;s post &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://demosthenes.tumblr.com/post/140922392/female-stereotyping-in-security-research&#34;&gt;Female stereotyping in security research&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; which was in response to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://hackerschool.org/DefconCTF/17/B300.html&#34;&gt;Saphead&amp;rsquo;s Binary 300 solution cartoon&lt;/a&gt;. But please keep in mind, this only set the cogs in motion for this post that I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking about way before this cartoon came into existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sexism, and for that matter, any &amp;ldquo;-ism&amp;rdquo; is flawed on both sides. Now, Shazzzam went no where near the extreme that most of the &amp;ldquo;-ists&amp;rdquo; do for their &amp;ldquo;-isms&amp;rdquo;, she actually had some great points however, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t excuse the presumptions she made. Pusscat, Hypatia, and Shazzzam (+ the many other women in IT) have made enormous contributions, just as males have. Hackers are hackers. The only thing we measure by is the brain in your noggin, but I&amp;rsquo;ll go into that later. Where Shazzzam went wrong is that she assumed that this cartoon was depicting the female falsely, which may or may have not been the case. She then used it as a soap box to express her hate for people who make presumptions about her mental abilities because of her sex.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Damn men, &amp;ldquo;they&amp;rdquo; are always assuming I&amp;rsquo;m an idiot)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the difference between a WM (woman-Marine) and a hooker? Hooker gets paid in the morning and the WM gets paid on the 1st and 15th.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;mdash;-old Marine joke, origin unknown&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While this is a crude joke, it illustrates a point. During my time in the Marine Corps I witnessed female Marines that were useless, ones that slept around, and those that outshined their peers, male and female alike. But guess what, those that did well were sadly the minority in my experiences. Now you might hinge your argument on that it&amp;rsquo;s my biased opinion that &amp;lsquo;saw&amp;rsquo; what I wanted to see, and you very well could be right. I hardly consider myself perfect, but lets just say for the sake of argument that what I say is true. We all make assumptions, you are not perfect either, is it so wrong to bet on odds or experience when making assumptions? It&amp;rsquo;s human nature, but keeping an open mind is the key to this. How many Mark Dowds, HDs, Shazzzams and Pusscats are there in this world? How many times have you complained about an idiot boss or co-worker? How many times have you complained about script kiddies? or whatever you complain about on an assumption or amassed experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Stupid woman, &amp;ldquo;they&amp;rdquo; never do anything right, can&amp;rsquo;t even drive straight)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings us to my favorite part, and why I love our community. Hackers are hackers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;snip&gt; (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.phrack.org/issues.html?issue=7&amp;amp;id=3&amp;amp;mode=txt&#34;&gt;original - phrak&lt;/a&gt;)
We exist without skin color, without nationality, without religious &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;(or sexual)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; bias&amp;hellip; and you call us criminals. You build atomic bombs, you wage wars, you murder, cheat, and lie to us and try to make us believe it&amp;rsquo;s for our own good, yet we&amp;rsquo;re the criminals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes, I am a criminal. My crime is that of curiosity. My crime is that of judging people by what they say and think, not what they look like. My crime is that of outsmarting you, something that you will never forgive me for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a hacker, and this is my manifesto. You may stop this individual, but you can&amp;rsquo;t stop us all&amp;hellip; after all, we&amp;rsquo;re all alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;+++The Mentor+++&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve taken the liberty of adding &amp;ldquo;(or sexual)&amp;rdquo; to this famous manifesto. But I think it stays in the spirit of it&amp;rsquo;s writer&amp;rsquo;s intent. This is my religion. I think all &amp;ldquo;ists&amp;rdquo; have forgotten what they fight for and just fight to be right. My suggestion? Make a mental note of those who have forgotten how to truly be what they claim as a title. For they will out themselves time and time again, and be destined to fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Damn kids. They&amp;rsquo;re all alike.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;edit-nikita-has-done-an-excellent-job-of-expressing-what-i-so-obviously-failed-at-doing-http-attrition-org-news-content-09-07-14-001-html-http-attrition-org-news-content-09-07-14-001-html&#34;&gt;EDIT: Nikita has done an excellent job of expressing what I so obviously failed at doing: &lt;a href=&#34;http://attrition.org/news/content/09-07-14.001.html&#34;&gt;http://attrition.org/news/content/09-07-14.001.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rant Back – ValSmith</title>
      <link>/post/2009/2009-06-11-rant-back-valsmith/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 02:11:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009/2009-06-11-rant-back-valsmith/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Val Smith recently wrote a post on the new &lt;a href=&#34;http://carnal0wnage.attackresearch.com&#34;&gt;Attack Research / carnal0wnage blog&lt;/a&gt; titled:&lt;br /&gt;
”&lt;a href=&#34;http://carnal0wnage.attackresearch.com/node/361&#34;&gt;Security Conferences, pen tests and incident response&lt;/a&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my thoughts on what he wrote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In paragraphs 2-6 he talks about two points. The first being that Hacker Conferences have become sort of commercialized with most speakers going for their day in the lime light or to pimp some product/0day. And the second being a lot of the talks are things that most can’t go home / back to work and test out or implement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree with him on both points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the first point I think that one detail was left out of this evaluation. Size. Back when DEFCON was &amp;lt;500 people, almost everyone knew each other. 90% of those attending had the passion, had the fire for that what makes our line of work such an art. Now that our community has become “popular”, that percentage is around 20-30%. These numbers aren’t based on any stats, just something that I have been observing as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the second point, my first security conference was ShmooCon ‘06. I was glued to might seat in each talk I attended, and in just 3 short years I have seen EXACTLY what he’s talking about. I used to have to decide between awesome talks in the same hour. Now I actually find times where I’m not interested in anything being presented for that hour. But, rooms still get packed so I guess that’s just my own pickiness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Penetration Testing and Incident is the second portion of his post and I really think he’s hit the nail on the head, Pen Testing and Incident Response should work closely together. I want to throw Vulnerability Assessment and Forensics into the mix as well, feeding each other, sharing data, and assisting. The segmentation of duties / teams is killing collaboration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lets get back to the basics, and really show what this community is capable of.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Manager Training Camp - Bootcamp Style</title>
      <link>/post/2009/2009-03-14-manager-training-camp-bootcamp-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2009 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009/2009-03-14-manager-training-camp-bootcamp-style/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/postimages/200903_manager_1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Friday (March 6th, 2009) I posed the question above. What I got in return was nothing short of amazing, and to tell you the truth, it amazed me how the tally rounded out. I categorized the answers and counted them up (MANAGERS, listen up!):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;(12 votes) - Security Fundamentals: This category involves the application of A/V, IDS/IPS, basic safe surfing techniques, least privilege use, and an understanding of phishing. It astounds me that this is at the top of the list. I grouped all of these answers together because they truly are the BASICS of Information Security. Why after all these years have managers of security professionals not gotten this drilled into them to the point of bleeding? What are we doing wrong?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;(8 votes) - Targeting: &amp;ldquo;We aren&amp;rsquo;t a target&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;There isn&amp;rsquo;t anything on saying we are getting attacked&amp;rdquo;. This is another that surprised me to be at the top of the list. How can managers not think that 1. that they are a target, and 2. think that because there aren&amp;rsquo;t any alarms going off, they aren&amp;rsquo;t getting attacked?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;(6 votes) - Passwords: Complexity, not using stickies, rotation, etc. I left this out of Security Fundamentals, because it&amp;rsquo;s not an easy beast to over come. It&amp;rsquo;s something that definitely needs to be addressed and a plan set down for the application, enforcement and technology behind it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;(6 votes) - Compliance and Policy: Everyone in this category made it abundantly clear that compliance to a standard does NOT mean that you are secure, but not at least making the compliance bar is worse. Internal policies need to be created to provide a stricter regimen then the compliance checklist demonstrates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;(5 votes) - Accountability: From basic user to CEO and Security Analyst. Accountability has many faces but it usually shows none of them in the security world. Users of the world learn quick when one of coworkers get restricted access because they clicked test phishing  after they had just gone through phishing training.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;(5 votes) - Defense In Depth: This is an old concept as well, but in recent years have been twisted to include DiD at host and network infrastructure level. The phrase Defense In Dept will continue to grow as the depths at which we can put protections on info systems grows. You need to realize that you ARE a target and you NEED to move with this evolution, not ignore it. Doing so doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it &amp;ldquo;go away&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;(3 votes) - Users are stupid: I can&amp;rsquo;t believe that this even made it as an item. Managers, you seriously don&amp;rsquo;t understand that your weakest link on your network is the users?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;(2 votes) - Data Layer Protection: Encryption. Even if the client data is stored on a super &amp;ldquo;secure&amp;rdquo; data node, that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean somewhere between point A and point B isnt&amp;rsquo; compromised. If it&amp;rsquo;s sensitive or secret, it needs to be treated as such at EVERY juncture where that data is transferred or can be accessed from.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;(2 votes) - Risk Management: Managers, this is supposedly your specialty. Get back to it, they want you to be open to understand technically why this or that isn&amp;rsquo;t a threat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;(1 vote) - Company buy-in: I am truly surprised this didn&amp;rsquo;t make the top of the list. I personally think that company buy-in to security should precede the rest of the categories.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is simply a top 10 list of things we as Security Professionals want you to know. It would not be hard to create training in your organization around these 10 categories. If you are a manager or one of us, get it started, make the slides and start getting these topics nailed down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have included the raw tweets from the poll so that you as managers can understand what your people want you to learn:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;lorddrachenblut
&amp;gt; passwords dont go on post it notes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;taiyed
&amp;gt; The importance of protecting client data with encryption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;oneeyedcarmen
&amp;gt; Compliance != Security&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;clamasters - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.curtis-lamasters.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.curtis-lamasters.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; definitely not my quote but &amp;ldquo;If you can&amp;rsquo;t measure it, you can&amp;rsquo;t improve it&amp;rdquo; Put that into security terms and make sure he understands&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;techsnax - &lt;a href=&#34;http://techsnax.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;http://techsnax.blogspot.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; that security means more than just passwords!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;strcpy - &lt;a href=&#34;http://strcpy.net/&#34;&gt;http://strcpy.net/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; that IDS is completely a flawed concept. Either that or firewalls are not an end-all solution for security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tcrweb - &lt;a href=&#34;http://tcrweb.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;http://tcrweb.wordpress.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; That users are the weakest link, convenience and security don&amp;rsquo;t always mesh well
_natron_ - &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.invisibledenizen.org/&#34;&gt;http://blog.invisibledenizen.org/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt;/s/boss/client, layered security&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;armorguy - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.linkedin.com/in/martinjfisher&#34;&gt;http://www.linkedin.com/in/martinjfisher&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; I&amp;rsquo;d be ecstatic if my boss understood defense in depth. &amp;ldquo;If we have A/V why do we need other endpoint products?&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;andywillingham - &lt;a href=&#34;http://andyitguy.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;http://andyitguy.blogspot.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; Management has to quit exempting themselves from security policies or others won&amp;rsquo;t buy into them&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iamnowonmai
&amp;gt; Classifying data in containers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multimode - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chromedpork.net/&#34;&gt;http://www.chromedpork.net/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; Risk Management - Identifing the $ risk and priorization of tasks based on that risk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;l3d
&amp;gt; defense in depth&amp;hellip; But i don&amp;rsquo;t have this issue, thank god.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ilovegarick
&amp;gt; I&amp;rsquo;d have all my co-workers understand not to open email attachments from unknown senders and not to forward them on either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multimode -&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chromedpork.net/&#34;&gt;http://www.chromedpork.net/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; And accuracy in the presentation of those risks to peer and upper management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mortman
&amp;gt; but !compliant == !secure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ramblinpeck
&amp;gt; Ill replace boss with clients, but actually understanding AND using a real least privilege model would be great step for everyone&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DFrain - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brinkmasterj.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.brinkmasterj.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; @ Compliance as well!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sintixerr - &lt;a href=&#34;http://sintixerr.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;http://sintixerr.wordpress.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; That security is only tangentially related to technology&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multimode - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chromedpork.net/&#34;&gt;http://www.chromedpork.net/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; Becuase an unsuccesful phishing email is often put way higher on the list then patching critical infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tnicholson - &lt;a href=&#34;http://nicholsonsecurity.com/&#34;&gt;http://nicholsonsecurity.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; That people (good/bad) are the weakest link regardless of policies or security related technology. Educate users about security!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cyberhiker - &lt;a href=&#34;http://howisthatassuranceevidence.blogspot.com/&#34;&gt;http://howisthatassuranceevidence.blogspot.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; The parts of infosec that make you secure are not the parts that are sexy or come from a vendor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;post_break - &lt;a href=&#34;http://iamthekiller.net/&#34;&gt;http://iamthekiller.net/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; The notion that forced password changes tend to be more of a security risk rather than a security method. (unless someone got fired)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cloudchaos - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.cloudchaos.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.cloudchaos.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; the need for a good password/phrases that are changed regularly. |&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Techdulla - &lt;a href=&#34;http://techdulla.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;http://techdulla.wordpress.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; That threats (specifically web threats) do not discriminate based on the size of your organization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;michaeldickey
&amp;gt; Hard question, and worthy of a blog post. I&amp;rsquo;d say &amp;ldquo;You &lt;em&gt;will&lt;/em&gt; have a security incident. Plan for it and plan to find it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RonW123
&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;If you have responsibility for security, but have no authority, your role is to take the blame when something goes wrong&amp;rdquo; Spafford&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tottenkoph
&amp;gt; The importance of email and Internet use policies, they&amp;rsquo;re usually overlooked by password policies. :/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jaysonstreet - &lt;a href=&#34;http://f0rb1dd3n.com/&#34;&gt;http://f0rb1dd3n.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; Just because there is no perceptible change does not mean you are not being attacked. The better your security the less they notice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ChrisJohnRiley - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.c22.cc/&#34;&gt;http://www.c22.cc/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; Security testing is all well and good, but not following through to fix the issues makes the process a pointless exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MarcoFigueroa - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mafcorp.net/&#34;&gt;http://www.mafcorp.net/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; I would make my boss understand that spending less than 1% of the total gross of the company income on Security is unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MarcoFigueroa - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mafcorp.net/&#34;&gt;http://www.mafcorp.net/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; This seems to be the norm, the ratio of percentage spent on security is always a huge difference in most companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;dgeorghiou
&amp;gt; Security is only as good as the system&amp;rsquo;s weakest link.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MarcoFigueroa - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mafcorp.net/&#34;&gt;http://www.mafcorp.net/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; @tnicholson We have a security awareness program. It makes them aware but they still get compromised. There excuse is I didn&amp;rsquo;t know!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ddahlen - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.poorboys.tv/&#34;&gt;http://www.poorboys.tv/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; That even non-windows machines are vulnerable and targets for attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;timmedin
&amp;gt; Getting rid of the &amp;ldquo;we will never be a target&amp;rdquo; mentality&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;slick0 - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.basenetradio.net/&#34;&gt;http://www.basenetradio.net/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; The importance of having an antivirus/antispyware solution in the office. I wish I were joking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;bug_bear
&amp;gt; Antivirus is not a valid primary defense&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;lorddrachenblut
&amp;gt; @slick0 and firewalls per machine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;richardebaker
&amp;gt; that one computer hooked to 2 networks is in fact a gigantic hole in the air gap security on a control net.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;lbhuston - &lt;a href=&#34;http://stateofsecurity.com/&#34;&gt;http://stateofsecurity.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; One concept: That threats can be identified by transactions with non-real services, accounts and things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CrucialCarl - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dontpanictech.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.dontpanictech.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; (cool topic) my concept: Ignorance is not a valid defense and will not make you any less accountable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;danphilpott - &lt;a href=&#34;http://fismapedia.org/&#34;&gt;http://fismapedia.org/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; One security concept: Never believe what a sales person says, always get independent analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;lorddrachenblut
&amp;gt; passwords dont go on post it notes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BrianWGray
&amp;gt; the importance of PUBLISHED policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;hmjgriffon
&amp;gt; stop wrting your password on a sticky note on your monitor, and stop making it 123456&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jodyfranklin - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.elder-n00b.org/&#34;&gt;http://www.elder-n00b.org/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; if you&amp;rsquo;re still compiling the list how about long passwd != strong passwd&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;JosephDawson - &lt;a href=&#34;http://bitstop.ca/&#34;&gt;http://bitstop.ca/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; get your client to understand one security concept fully&amp;hellip; You can&amp;rsquo;t add security after&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;curtw
&amp;gt; within the context of the organization, I&amp;rsquo;d say the importance of executive representation and project approve/deny power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Replies sent to CORE Security&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ben_p - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thegeekzone.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.thegeekzone.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; @CoreSecurity I would love for him to understand that security needs a budget. We have a lot of good ideas but no dedicated resources&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ben_p - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.thegeekzone.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.thegeekzone.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; @CoreSecurity Actually, they get that but it&amp;rsquo;s the people above them (with the checkbook) that need that realization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sonofshirt
&amp;gt; @CoreSecurity That Red Teaming and auditing are not synonymous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;jason_nixon - &lt;a href=&#34;http://jasonnixon.net/&#34;&gt;http://jasonnixon.net/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; @CoreSecurity Patch management is proactive requirement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;spinzon - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.scottpinzon.com/&#34;&gt;http://www.scottpinzon.com/&lt;/a&gt;
&amp;gt; @CoreSecurity One security concept: that the threat is real. Too much security is done to a compliance checklist. Take it seriously, boss!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;steveshead
&amp;gt; @CoreSecurity - that it only takes one &amp;lsquo;mistake&amp;rsquo; to bring it all down!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AnonymASS - Hiding Behind The Tubes</title>
      <link>/post/2009/2009-03-13-anonymass-hiding-behind-the-tubes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 05:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2009/2009-03-13-anonymass-hiding-behind-the-tubes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;First I wanted to say, sorry for this and the last installment of Room362 being non-technical. They are topics that I feel strongly about and so felt impelled to share.One of the biggest problems in the world, IMHO, are people who have unfounded hate. This is compounded by the anonymity of the Internet. Allowing that hate to have no reprocussion or identity. Let me also say I have a deep respect for Free Speech, the depths of which I fear, few truly know. What I don&amp;rsquo;t have a respect for is people who abuse that right. It&amp;rsquo;s ultimately a respect of your fellow man/woman/it, that transends any nationality, race, creed, or color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you know where I stand, let me step down to a slightly lower soap box. On my last post about ethics, I received a comment from an individual who posted under the guise of not only a false email and name, but also from a proxied address. They were on my side of the argument and were digusted with Dave&amp;rsquo;s. His/her/it&amp;rsquo;s post was pointed, rude, and had no constructive criticism or facts. It was deleted. It does not deserve a direct response. So I am issuing a response to all who tred here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These types of posts are allowed to flow on other forums, blogs, and mediums of the Internet. &lt;strong&gt;They WILL NOT be allowed here. Period. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may think of me what you will, pompous, self righteous. I don&amp;rsquo;t care. I will keep my bit of the Internet clean how I see fit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lastly, I hope I demonstrated this fact already, but I want to reiterate it here. I will never delete comments on any side of any discussion I have here, even if I disagree with the comment. I enjoy debat and discussion. I am religous in my faith fight for free speech and it&amp;rsquo;s application on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You have something to say fine. You better do it with respect or you can take your posts to slashdot, digg, or some other place. They won&amp;rsquo;t see the light of day here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
