<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>rant - Category - Malicious Link - Blog by mubix - Rob Fuller</title>
        <link>https://malicious.link/categories/rant/</link>
        <description>rant - Category - Malicious Link - Blog by mubix - Rob Fuller</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>mubix@hak5.org (Rob Fuller)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>mubix@hak5.org (Rob Fuller)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 22:42:14 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://malicious.link/categories/rant/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>Alive Again</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2014/2014-01-09-alive-again/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 22:42:14 -0500</pubDate>
    <author>Rob Fuller</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2014/2014-01-09-alive-again/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I&rsquo;ve taken a rather long hiatus from blogging. This is mostly because I was fed up with the blogging platform that I had (Squarespace) and didn&rsquo;t really have any alternatives that met all of the features I wanted.
So, where am I at now? Github actually. Github allows users to create &ldquo;Github Pages&rdquo; for repositories (or be it&rsquo;s own repo). For the most part these pages are written in Markdown. It&rsquo;s late and I don&rsquo;t feel like looking up who, but someone created a project called &ldquo;Jekyll&rdquo; which is a Ruby based static page generator and then another project called &ldquo;Octopress&rdquo; popped up using Jekyll to create a static html based blogging platform.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Problems with blogging software</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2013/2013-08-10-problems-with-blogging-software/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <author>Rob Fuller</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2013/2013-08-10-problems-with-blogging-software/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Problems are that everyone does this whole blogging thing in so many different ways. Me, personally? I like to have a client that I can save drafts it, work on things a little bit here and there and then finalize stuff when I&rsquo;m ready to post. I have a couple dozen of these posts ready and set with final tweaks needed but my blogging software Squarespace up and moved on to &ldquo;Squarespace 6&rdquo;.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Who is on your dream team red team?</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2012/2012-03-04-who-is-on-your-dream-team-red-team/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2012 10:21:21 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2012/2012-03-04-who-is-on-your-dream-team-red-team/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This was an honest idea to help identify people that might not get the media attention of other &ldquo;Top X in Infosec&rdquo; lists. But I should have known better than to put a poll on the internet&hellip;]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>GPU Cracking Complaints</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2011/2011-07-13-gpu-cracking-complaints/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 14:02:13 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2011/2011-07-13-gpu-cracking-complaints/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I&rsquo;ve been cracking passwords for a while and use a myriad of tools in a certain order to get the job done. I find that Cain is still my Go-to for allowing me to visualize the process and do some basic sorting (really wish I could search in-app). But I&rsquo;ve been asking around on twitter some questions like Why is GPU cracking for 50k hashes faster than Rainbow Tables (most say the bottleneck is the HDD read style and speed) and many asked what all of my compalints are so I figured this would be the best place (vice multiple emails)]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Insider Threat Testing</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2011/2011-01-27-insider-threat-testing/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 15:41:10 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2011/2011-01-27-insider-threat-testing/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This day and age everyone is worried about the insider threat. Internal Penetration Testing doesn&rsquo;t really test what would happen if your janitor got paid 50 bucks to put a USB stick in one of your servers. External Penetration Tests are never scoped for that sort of testing. So what is a company to do? How can they know what the risk is? The answer? Usually they guess or assume.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Jailbreak SSH horrors strike back</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2010/2010-08-04-jailbreak-ssh-horrors-strike-back/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 04:30:36 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2010/2010-08-04-jailbreak-ssh-horrors-strike-back/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Back in 2009 the &ldquo;ikee&rdquo; rick-rolling worm went around the iPhone world via the password of &lsquo;alpine&rsquo; on the root account. You are now warned to change your root password when you pop into Cydia and Rock the first time. But this thing just wont stay down.
If you have jailbroken your iPad you might want to check out a little file called &ldquo;master.passwd&rdquo;. In it, there is another user called &lsquo;mobile&rsquo; which has been pointed out since 2008 (here) on the iPhone as another account to change the password of.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Vuln Disclosure Summarized</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2010/2010-04-29-vuln-disclosure-summarized/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 03:05:13 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2010/2010-04-29-vuln-disclosure-summarized/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I have an admittedly limited view of the exploit dev world. However, from what I&rsquo;ve seen devs have very few options: (Please correct me if I&rsquo;m wrong)
Responsible Disclosure Direct Contact =&gt; depending on the size of the vendor and their view on security, this could result in anything from a simple thanks, a reward, to a court hearing. Exploit Broker =&gt; possibly sell, possibly not, depends on the broker. The vuln could die on the table or stolen due to too much information being given during negotiations.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Security (CAN BE) an ART not a SCIENCE</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2010/2010-01-26-security-can-be-an-art-not-a-science/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 14:44:37 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2010/2010-01-26-security-can-be-an-art-not-a-science/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[This is far from a new idea, however it&rsquo;s not something that is easily provable. So I had an idea this morning. I posed the following question on Twitter:
You know what I got in return? a resounding &ldquo;No&rdquo; from everyone. (well I had one outlier but, who doesn&rsquo;t when you are trying to apply science to prove art) I challenge you to name another non-artistic career that people are so passionate about that they would stay in it even if they won the lottery.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Linked in to Twitter</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-12-22-linked-in-to-twitter/</link>
    <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 15:13:06 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-12-22-linked-in-to-twitter/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[If you hadn&rsquo;t noticed, LinkedIn has started allowing you to link your Twitter account to your LinkedIn account. So, I didn&rsquo;t know this (since I opted out), but apparently LinkedIn will kick your status updates to Twitter&hellip; like when you get a new job&hellip;
Privacy settings out the window! Woohoo for Web 2.0!]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Stop blaming the admins!</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-11-19-stop-blaming-the-admins/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 04:00:06 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-11-19-stop-blaming-the-admins/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[We (the security community) all know, and make fun of &ldquo;Users&rdquo;, and &ldquo;Admins&rdquo;. They are derogatory terms in our community. So much so, that they could almost be classified at curse words. (I can see the XKCD now: Security stick figure talking to IT stick figure. &ldquo;You stupid A****&rdquo;).
While I neither discount their &ldquo;contribution&rdquo; to making my day fun, I feel that a lot of people miss an even bigger threat: Policies and Procedures, or SOP (Standard Operating Procedures).]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>APPLE: A Modern Day Willy Wonka Story</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-10-12-apple-a-modern-day-willy-wonka-story/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 15:42:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-10-12-apple-a-modern-day-willy-wonka-story/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Yes, I just called everyone who works at Apple an Oompa Loompa, but I digress:
I was reading Brooke Crothers&rsquo; story on the Apple &lsquo;gag&rsquo; order [1] and couldn&rsquo;t help but think of how Apple has created an almost similar situation. Everyone wants to know what Apple is up to, can&rsquo;t stop talking about it. Buzz Out Loud [2] even had people call and email asking them to see if they could do a show without mentioning Apple or the iPhone.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Back on Twitter</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-10-11-back-on-twitter/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 19:09:24 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-10-11-back-on-twitter/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I&rsquo;ve been debating making this kind of post for about a week, and I apologize for the RSS spam. But it was getting a bit repetitive telling people via DM, email or other communication what happened.
When I took my hiatus from Twitter, I zero&rsquo;d out my followers, so, if you care to, please check to see if you are still following me. I will be watching my follows closely and will refollow people I might have missed in my initial run through.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Corrections and Questions about Nessus on Securabit</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-09-16-corrections-and-questions-about-nessus-on-securabit/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2009 17:52:22 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-09-16-corrections-and-questions-about-nessus-on-securabit/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Update I can&rsquo;t say with 100% certainty that Nessus ever used NMAP as it&rsquo;s base scanner, I was going off of memory. I apologize for not being perfect.
Update 2 Since people can&rsquo;t seem to let it go, I would say that I was totally wrong and the nmap was absolutely never used in nessus ever, but then I would be caught in another absolute that I can&rsquo;t confirm. According to their wiki, the nmap nasl script were taken out because people were No, I haven&rsquo;t listened to the latest episode of Securabit in which Paul comes on and talks about Nessus.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Simplicity is Security</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-08-13-simplicity-is-security/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 15:30:29 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-08-13-simplicity-is-security/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Per the best of the best in presenting, what breeds a good presentation slide deck? Simplicity
I want to pose a statement. &ldquo;Simplicity is Security&rdquo;. The reason I say this is that this day in age, at least in the US, &lsquo;convenience&rsquo; is king. And we try to protect those conveniences with &lsquo;security&rsquo;. Let me start over a bit, this train of thought all started when I started to explain the insecurities in WiMAX to my wife.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Applied Network Security Density</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-08-12-applied-network-security-density/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 15:30:16 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-08-12-applied-network-security-density/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I recently visited Tokyo, Japan. Just as always, my curiosity got the best of me and I started to calculate the population density of the buildings where I was staying. Giving fudge factor of non-populated apartments, I estimated 8,500 families in twelve 15 story buildings, living in a 1.5 mile square piece of land.That&rsquo;s CRAZY. Mass transit and unrestricted modes of transit are not a whim, they are a requirement. I bet you&rsquo;re asking how this applies to security, or for that matter computers at all.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Lies</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-08-12-lies/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 09:11:48 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-08-12-lies/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[When I was in middle school, I told a lie. I was so good at telling lies, and remembering even the infinite details of these lies that I could make them believable. Later in life, I learned that this skill was called “Social Engineering ;-)”, but back to the story; I told everyone that I had won a shopping spree at “Incredible Universe”, now named “Fry’s”. Even the teacher believed me.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Sexism and the religion of hackers</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-07-13-sexism-and-the-religion-of-hackers/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jul 2009 19:36:05 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-07-13-sexism-and-the-religion-of-hackers/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Let me preempt this post with the following facts: I am a white male veteran with amazing parents. I went to a good school, and was never under-valued by the people I cared about. I fit no minority profiles in other words. I tell you this so that you can latch on to it as why I don&rsquo;t understand anything in your rebuttal. But I think this gives me a unique view on the issue.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Rant Back – ValSmith</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-06-11-rant-back-valsmith/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2009 02:11:47 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-06-11-rant-back-valsmith/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Val Smith recently wrote a post on the new Attack Research / carnal0wnage blog titled:
”Security Conferences, pen tests and incident response”
Here are my thoughts on what he wrote:
In paragraphs 2-6 he talks about two points. The first being that Hacker Conferences have become sort of commercialized with most speakers going for their day in the lime light or to pimp some product/0day. And the second being a lot of the talks are things that most can’t go home / back to work and test out or implement.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>Manager Training Camp - Bootcamp Style</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-03-14-manager-training-camp-bootcamp-style/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 14 Mar 2009 06:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-03-14-manager-training-camp-bootcamp-style/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Last Friday (March 6th, 2009) I posed the question above. What I got in return was nothing short of amazing, and to tell you the truth, it amazed me how the tally rounded out. I categorized the answers and counted them up (MANAGERS, listen up!):
(12 votes) - Security Fundamentals: This category involves the application of A/V, IDS/IPS, basic safe surfing techniques, least privilege use, and an understanding of phishing.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>AnonymASS - Hiding Behind The Tubes</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-03-13-anonymass-hiding-behind-the-tubes/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2009 05:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
    <author>mubix</author>
    <guid>https://malicious.link/posts/2009/2009-03-13-anonymass-hiding-behind-the-tubes/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[First I wanted to say, sorry for this and the last installment of Room362 being non-technical. They are topics that I feel strongly about and so felt impelled to share.One of the biggest problems in the world, IMHO, are people who have unfounded hate. This is compounded by the anonymity of the Internet. Allowing that hate to have no reprocussion or identity. Let me also say I have a deep respect for Free Speech, the depths of which I fear, few truly know.]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
