<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rant on malicious.link</title>
    <link>https://malicious.link/categories/rant/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rant on malicious.link</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 22:42:14 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://malicious.link/categories/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Alive Again</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2014/2014-01-09-alive-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 22:42:14 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2014/2014-01-09-alive-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve taken a rather long hiatus from blogging. This is mostly because I was fed up with the blogging platform that I had (Squarespace) and didn&amp;rsquo;t really have any alternatives that met all of the features I wanted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, where am I at now? Github actually. Github allows users to create &amp;ldquo;Github Pages&amp;rdquo; for repositories (or be it&amp;rsquo;s own repo). For the most part these pages are written in Markdown. It&amp;rsquo;s late and I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like looking up who, but someone created a project called &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; which is a Ruby based static page generator and then another project called &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://octopress.org/&#34;&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; popped up using Jekyll to create a static html based blogging platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a bit of a pain in the butt to use and learn, but once you have a few things automated it gets simpler. It also hits the most bullet points of any other option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Expect things to pick up pretty quickly here, but as I&amp;rsquo;m typing this I&amp;rsquo;m already thinking that promising something like that is a bad idea. We&amp;rsquo;ll see how it goes, it&amp;rsquo;s just good to be back.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Problems with blogging software</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2013/2013-08-10-problems-with-blogging-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2013 00:43:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2013/2013-08-10-problems-with-blogging-software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Problems are that everyone does this whole blogging thing in so many different ways. Me, personally? I like to have a client that I can save drafts it, work on things a little bit here and there and then finalize stuff when I&amp;rsquo;m ready to post. I have a couple dozen of these posts ready and set with final tweaks needed but my blogging software Squarespace up and moved on to &amp;ldquo;Squarespace 6&amp;rdquo;. The the current stage you don&amp;rsquo;t have to move to 6 but at some point the owners of Squarespace are going to force everyone over. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to wait for that to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Octopress and Postach.io are my favorite options right now. Both blog in markdown language which is ok. Converting 8 years of blog posts to markdown is going to be a lot of work but a one time deal. Plus it would give me a chance to go through and fix the things that were broken over the years of modified blogging clients and services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Postach.io has one major downside, they don&amp;rsquo;t have good &amp;ldquo;code&amp;rdquo; block support, whereas Octopress/Jekyll have excellent support as well code hilighting. The major upside? It&amp;rsquo;s based on Evernote. Which means I can blog from whereever I have Evernote. They also used to have an EXCELLENT feature that seems to have disappeared where if you updated a post it would automatically throw the blog post up to the top of your page, meaning your update would get back in your RSS feed and the update wouldn&amp;rsquo;t go unnoticed as most updates to blog posts do.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who is on your dream team red team?</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2012/2012-03-04-who-is-on-your-dream-team-red-team/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2012 10:21:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2012/2012-03-04-who-is-on-your-dream-team-red-team/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was an honest idea to help identify people that might not get the media attention of other &amp;ldquo;Top X in Infosec&amp;rdquo; lists. But I should have known better than to put a poll on the internet&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPU Cracking Complaints</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-07-13-gpu-cracking-complaints/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2011 14:02:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-07-13-gpu-cracking-complaints/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been cracking passwords for a while and use a myriad of tools in a certain order to get the job done. I find that Cain is still my Go-to for allowing me to visualize the process and do some basic sorting (really wish I could search in-app). But I&amp;rsquo;ve been asking around on twitter some questions like Why is GPU cracking for 50k hashes faster than Rainbow Tables (most say the bottleneck is the HDD read style and speed) and many asked what all of my compalints are so I figured this would be the best place (vice multiple emails)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DISCLAIMER&lt;/strong&gt;: I have very little crypto knowledge and even less GPU programming knowledge so I only get to complain as a user and not as someone who can actually fix the things I complain about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of LM support. I get that this is a complicated hashing algorithm, but the fact that 90% of companies still have it turned on and cracking any more than a few with Rainbow Tables is impractical unless you have a SSD raid with a GPU based cracker ($$$$$).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of dictionary support. Right now the best way to crack passwords is with oclhashcat-plus since it is GPU based and supports rules, multiple hashes (hash files) and directories of hashes. However, it has a very limited list of hashes it supports (No LM, SHA1, etc..) and it doesn&amp;rsquo;t support dump formats, so you need to strip the file so it just has the hash (this is more of just a bother than a gripe).
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I say &amp;lsquo;The best way&amp;rsquo; because anything that has a key space larger than upper-alpha-numeric-32symbol (LM) is just a bit nuts to try and brute force out of the gate unless your goal is to &amp;lsquo;crack them all&amp;rsquo;. Me as a pentester, I want to get as many as possible, as quick as possible, so this means dictionaries are the smarter option. (Maybe later I can do the straight brute if I really need / want to)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of POT. For some reason every cracking app on the planet, save for JtR, thinks it&amp;rsquo;s a good idea to crack the same hash multiple times. I wish even Cain would keep a secret store of all the hashes it&amp;rsquo;s cracked stripped of anything unimportant (need the salt (username) sometimes) and store it in the background so that if it comes across the same hash it can say &amp;ldquo;oo oo I know this one&amp;rdquo; and auto populate it even before I start cracking. Why more cracking software writers don&amp;rsquo;t do this I&amp;rsquo;ll never know (would make their software seem a ton faster the more it is used)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of formatting documentation (#ripshairout). Rare is the time I&amp;rsquo;ve found a cracking program that shows you how it wants to consume a hash. JtR is the most egregious offenders of this but they all do it. One would think people would try and make it easy for people to use their software (give examples of what shit is supposed to look like at least if you don&amp;rsquo;t support standard formats)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those are my biggest gripes that the moment. If I am wrong on any account, let me know, I would love to know of a better way to do things.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Insider Threat Testing</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-01-27-insider-threat-testing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jan 2011 15:41:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2011/2011-01-27-insider-threat-testing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/postimages/201101_insider_1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This day and age everyone is worried about the insider threat. Internal Penetration Testing doesn&amp;rsquo;t really test what would happen if your janitor got paid 50 bucks to put a USB stick in one of your servers. External Penetration Tests are never scoped for that sort of testing. So what is a company to do? How can they know what the risk is? The answer? Usually they guess or assume. Mostly because they are scared to find out, it&amp;rsquo;s happened to them before, or one of a million different justifications. I&amp;rsquo;ve got a webinar coming up to describe exactly this type of testing, but I thought I&amp;rsquo;d go into it a bit here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The FBI has a files upon files and stories stacked miles high about spies and insiders taking everything from accounting information (I could have put LIVES for effect but that&amp;rsquo;s more of a one-off) to staplers (no I don&amp;rsquo;t think Milton has an FBI file). Insiders throughout time have been the biggest threat to organizations even before sabotage and espionage became words. Ok, so what&amp;rsquo;s the big build up for? Simple. We need to build organizations up in the detection department from a pentesters point of view, not signature based. Our pentesters need to talk to our forensics guys, the incident responders need to talk to pentesters and every which way between. We are loosing this battle, and one of the reasons we are is we keep our bag of tricks to our selves, and that&amp;rsquo;s what insider threat testing is all about, getting all the tricks tested in a more open fashion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can your organization see a command and control session via IRC? What if it&amp;rsquo;s pushed over port 80? What about a standard meterpreter reverse_tcp connection? There isn&amp;rsquo;t a money based solution for this, just like there isn&amp;rsquo;t for phishing. Added on to all of the other things your security team does, there needs to be an employee, or a consultant that it is on the phone with your team saying &amp;ldquo;did you see this?&amp;rdquo;. Sort of like the &amp;lsquo;Can you hear me now?&amp;rsquo; test. I mean, have you ever met an incident response team that took time out of their day to see if they could get poison ivy (one of the most well known RATS /remote access tools/) through the firewall undetected? Probably, but when they came and told you about it you chastised them for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/postimages/201101_insider_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In any case, I&amp;rsquo;ve jumped around roles in this post a lot and I want to focus it back on getting true collaborative testing done, but there has to be a balance. If you&amp;rsquo;re staring at a piece of earth, you&amp;rsquo;ll see the ant walk on by, but you&amp;rsquo;ll probably miss a half dozen of them on your way to check the mail. So how do you do this? Why not make it an educational process? Have the senior staff on the phone with the tester, and then tell the junior guys something like &amp;ldquo;We just had a breach and it&amp;rsquo;s starting exfil data to this IP: x.x.x.x&amp;rdquo;. Give them a chance to find it then work through with them where / what happened, and why or why not any alerts or alarms went of and if they saw it in their normal flow. Ideally they spot it before the senior staff even mention it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No, this will not fit into the &amp;lsquo;I give you report you give me money&amp;rsquo; scenario. Companies should consider it a training exercise where they get instant and obvious benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many other arenas this helps in too. For example phishing, you know how much harder it will be for an attacker to get a payload to work if you&amp;rsquo;ve already tested, detected and have traps (we&amp;rsquo;ll go into setting traps another time) for all the public avenues of C&amp;amp;C and exfiltration? They will get frustrated, and you&amp;rsquo;ll know that you&amp;rsquo;re being attacked. A proactive stance is what &amp;lsquo;testing&amp;rsquo; is all about, and this is a extremely neglected aspect of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No one will solve &amp;lsquo;security&amp;rsquo;, all we are here to do is minimize the attack surface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Come to the webinar to heckle, learn, or just hear more, or don&amp;rsquo;t. I just wanted to get this out there and ask the question: Can your most important data leave on a fake Lady Gaga CD without you knowing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt;: Let me squash something real quick. No this is not a new idea. The prevention side is talked about ad nauseum, but hardly anyone talks about testing to see what could really happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jailbreak SSH horrors strike back</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2010/2010-08-04-jailbreak-ssh-horrors-strike-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Aug 2010 04:30:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2010/2010-08-04-jailbreak-ssh-horrors-strike-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back in 2009 the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.jeltel.com.au/2009/11/interview-with-ikee-iphone-virus.html&#34;&gt;ikee&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo; rick-rolling worm went around the iPhone world via the password of &amp;lsquo;alpine&amp;rsquo; on the root account. You are now warned to change your root password when you pop into Cydia and Rock the first time. But this thing just wont stay down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have jailbroken your iPad you might want to check out a little file called &amp;ldquo;master.passwd&amp;rdquo;. In it, there is another user called &amp;lsquo;mobile&amp;rsquo; which has been pointed out since 2008 (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.macosxhints.com/article.php?story=20080224231344798&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;) on the iPhone as another account to change the password of. But the media and Cydia/Rock warnings only put emphasis on &amp;lsquo;root&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many iPad and iPhone apps STILL do not use the &amp;ldquo;keyring&#39;&amp;rdquo; and store your password in plain text or somewhere in a binary file (still plaintext), which the user &amp;ldquo;mobile&amp;rdquo; has access to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/postimages/201008_jailbreak_1.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ok, &amp;ldquo;so what&amp;rdquo; you say. Since this recent jailbreak was using a website, the individuals running that site now have the IP address of freshly jailbroken iPhones and iPads. I am certainly not saying that they have any ill intentions, but sites have been broken into before, and that would be one hell of a gold mine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hopefully AT&amp;amp;T has put in blocks of some sort so that it&amp;rsquo;s customers are protected, but who knows what the other countries around the world that carry iPhones are doing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But at the very least, if you have jailbroken your iPhone, iPod Touch or iPad, please.. please set your passwords accordingly and do not have it a simple dictionary password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, you ARE giving up some security when you jail break your phone. It is on you to make sure that you lock what you can back down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To change your password, use &amp;lsquo;Terminal&amp;rsquo; and log in to one account at a time and issue the &amp;ldquo;passwd&amp;rdquo; command. You can also just log in to root and issue the &amp;ldquo;passwd mobile&amp;rdquo; command to change the password of mobile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; on 2010-08-09 19:39 by Rob Fuller&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve gotten a lot of comments stating that OpenSSH isn&amp;rsquo;t installed by default and that this is not a big deal at all. A couple problems exist in that argument though:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jailbreak is executing code on your phone/touch/ipad. Unless you do a analysis of the entire disk, you can&amp;rsquo;t be sure the jailbreak doesn&amp;rsquo;t leave some other way into the phone. Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s a far fetched chance, but most users would never know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even if you don&amp;rsquo;t install it Out-of-the-box. There is a good possibility that you will OpenSSH at a later date. Better to get it fixed while you have it on the mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vuln Disclosure Summarized</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2010/2010-04-29-vuln-disclosure-summarized/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Apr 2010 03:05:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2010/2010-04-29-vuln-disclosure-summarized/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have an admittedly limited view of the exploit dev world. However, from what I&amp;rsquo;ve seen devs have very few options: (Please correct me if I&amp;rsquo;m wrong)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;responsible-disclosure&#34;&gt;Responsible Disclosure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Direct Contact =&amp;gt; depending on the size of the vendor and their view on security, this could result in anything from a simple thanks, a reward, to a court hearing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploit Broker =&amp;gt; possibly sell, possibly not, depends on the broker. The vuln could die on the table or stolen due to too much information being given during negotiations. This route has the same financial risk as direct contact, but a lot less risk of getting sued.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ZDI (or other vuln clearing house) =&amp;gt; &amp;ldquo;instant&amp;rdquo; cash, but admittedly less than an Exploit Broker could possible get based on the financial risk to ZDI. Close to zero risk of court time (they may come after you for selling the exploit). And a lot less financial risk since (IIRC) they pay up front. But then the vulns go to also undisclosed parties, potentially the highest bidder which is probably not the vendor.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;ldquo;other&amp;rdquo; secretive groups who share vulns for different reasons&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Just to friends =&amp;gt; No cash, no judicial risk, but you do risk them stealing/selling your exploit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;full-disclosure&#34;&gt;Full Disclosure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Posting it to the web for all to see/user =&amp;gt; Possible court time, but the definite upside is the vendor is forced to react. A very quick way to make enemies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Releasing at a conference =&amp;gt; Probable court time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;no-disclosure&#34;&gt;No Disclosure&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeping it to yourself =&amp;gt; Working under the assumption that your the only one that has found that same bug is still semi relevant due to the incredibly small size of the exploit dev community. However, as Dave said, they&amp;rsquo;ll be toasting to their sleeping dead 0days some day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;no-more-free-bugs&#34;&gt;No More Free Bugs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My stance on this is split, while I think people should get paid for their work, I relate this movement to mowing someone&amp;rsquo;s lawn and then ringing their doorbell and asking for money. However I&amp;rsquo;m sure Robert Graham&amp;rsquo;s punch in the face metaphor also works.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Like, I have stated above, I am far and away a newbie to the vuln disclosure world and this debate has been going on since before I owned my own computer, but with the brilliant minds working at it, why doesn&amp;rsquo;t anyone offer up a solid solution to it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My solution? Create a standard, something that we all abide by. I know as hackers we rebel against such things but in the interest of getting better security out there (yes, that&amp;rsquo;s what we are here for right?&amp;hellip;. right?) we should should really work together on this. What sounds right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I mean, what is the right way to approach someone who&amp;rsquo;s lawn you&amp;rsquo;ve mowed for the work you have done? Maybe free for open source projects, and a price based on exploitability and market share of the affected product?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference&#34;&gt;Reference:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vuln Trading Markets and You by Michal Zalewski (lcamtuf):  &lt;br&gt;
=&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://lcamtuf.blogspot.com/2010/04/vulnerability-trading-markets-and-you.html&#34;&gt;http://lcamtuf.blogspot.com/2010/04/vulnerability-trading-markets-and-you.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vuln Disclosure is Rude by Robert Graham:   &lt;br&gt;
=&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://erratasec.blogspot.com/2010/04/vuln-disclosure-is-rude.html&#34;&gt;http://erratasec.blogspot.com/2010/04/vuln-disclosure-is-rude.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No More Free Bugs movement by Charlie Miller, Alex Sotirov and Dino Dai Zovi:   &lt;br&gt;
=&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://trailofbits.com/2009/03/22/no-more-free-bugs/&#34;&gt;http://trailofbits.com/2009/03/22/no-more-free-bugs/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dailydave Post by Dave Aitel:   &lt;br&gt;
=&amp;gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://lists.immunitysec.com/pipermail/dailydave/2010-April/006100.html&#34;&gt;http://lists.immunitysec.com/pipermail/dailydave/2010-April/006100.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security (CAN BE) an ART not a SCIENCE</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2010/2010-01-26-security-can-be-an-art-not-a-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2010 14:44:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2010/2010-01-26-security-can-be-an-art-not-a-science/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is far from a new idea, however it&amp;rsquo;s not something that is easily provable. So I had an idea this morning. I posed the following question on Twitter:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/postimages/201001_art_1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know what I got in return? a resounding &amp;ldquo;No&amp;rdquo; from everyone. (well I had &lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/falconsview/status/8235524239&#34;&gt;one outlier&lt;/a&gt; but, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t when you are trying to apply science to prove art) I challenge you to name another non-artistic career that people are so passionate about that they would stay in it even if they won the lottery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are a few that I would like to highlight:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/schuetzdj&#34;&gt;@schuetzdj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/postimages/201001_art_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/TomSellers&#34;&gt;@TomSellers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/postimages/201001_art_3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/ethicalhack3r&#34;&gt;@ethicalhack3r&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/postimages/201001_art_4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/dookie2000ca&#34;&gt;@dookie2000ca&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/postimages/201001_art_5.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was a somewhat surprising outcome. See a trend? Most people wanted to quit their jobs, and start their own infosec company. Why is this? Is it just &amp;ldquo;The American Dream&amp;rdquo; or is it because they are unhappy with the current people in leadership? Or is it simply the fact that they are hindered from actually pursuing and learning hacking/security at work? The world may never know, but I do implore firms to look at the retention rate of their &lt;em&gt;actual&lt;/em&gt; talent. (No, I don&amp;rsquo;t buy into the No Infosec Peep left behind bull).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a rumor that Google has a practice. 2 hours a day, you (an employee of Google) are REQUIRED to work on a project of your own, that is in no way indebted or owned by Google, even after completion. I can imagine the above answers would change if that were the case where they worked. If their employers fostered learning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a result of Infosec / Hacking being an art, do we have our premadonas? Of course. But do we also have our Van Gogh&amp;rsquo;s and Michelangelo&amp;rsquo;s? Definitely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, time for a bit of a reality check:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/daveshackleford&#34;&gt;@daveshackleford&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/postimages/201001_art_6.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ya, you have NO idea what you would really do with millions of instant cash. I think the number is some 80% of lottery winners go BANKRUPT in the first 10 years. This is because you, and EVERYONE you have ANY connection to, goes absolutely crazy. To the point that there are lottery winner support groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the fact that people say it now, shows that they at least have the passion for the art. (or are just fronting)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here some &lt;strong&gt;honest&lt;/strong&gt; answers to even out the tide:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/shmoosr&#34;&gt;@shmoosr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/postimages/201001_art_7.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/Bolster&#34;&gt;@Bolster&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/postimages/201001_art_8.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/andrewsmhay&#34;&gt;@andrewsmhay&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/postimages/201001_art_9.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, I believe that hacking is a science, until passion adds the artistic fire to the mix. At least that&amp;rsquo;s what I think, draw your own conclusions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(That&amp;rsquo;s another thing I love about this field, you are constantly challenged to draw your own conclusions, to think, to learn, to improve, to be… better)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Linked in to Twitter</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-12-22-linked-in-to-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2009 15:13:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-12-22-linked-in-to-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you hadn&amp;rsquo;t noticed, LinkedIn has started allowing you to link your Twitter account to your LinkedIn account. So, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know this (since I opted out), but apparently LinkedIn will kick your status updates to Twitter&amp;hellip; like when you get a new job&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://malicious.link/images/postimages/200912_linkedin_1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Privacy settings out the window! Woohoo for Web 2.0!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stop blaming the admins!</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-11-19-stop-blaming-the-admins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Nov 2009 04:00:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-11-19-stop-blaming-the-admins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We (the security community) all know, and make fun of &amp;ldquo;Users&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Admins&amp;rdquo;. They are derogatory terms in our community. So much so, that they could almost be classified at curse words. (I can see the XKCD now: Security stick figure talking to IT stick figure. &amp;ldquo;You stupid A****&amp;quot;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While I neither discount their &amp;ldquo;contribution&amp;rdquo; to making my day fun, I feel that a lot of people miss an even bigger threat: Policies and Procedures, or SOP (Standard Operating Procedures). Those words are virtual kryptonite to anyone in IT, more so to &amp;lsquo;security professionals&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what makes them a threat? Two thing:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone hates them so they are rarely updated (you know.. like Windows.. stay with me)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since they are rarely updated, and sometimes even those that are, are written poorly, or actually create vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example lets make all the local admin passwords something really difficult and long, and… all the same so that we can easily administer every machine. This makes it to updates go smoothly and group policy… Oh wait… we don&amp;rsquo;t have those problems anymore (or at least they aren&amp;rsquo;t based on local authentication issues).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, policies and documented procedures are good things. I&amp;rsquo;m not saying they aren&amp;rsquo;t. What I am saying is that when those documented procedures and policies that we blindly follow because the guy that trained me said so, just doesn&amp;rsquo;t cut it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Admins: Challenge that policy, find out the reason why you do what they want you to do. The worst that could happen is you could learn something new. The best is that you could change your company&amp;rsquo;s security posture for the better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Security Pros: Time to get off your A**** and update the wiki! (or the doc/site/binder) so that your predecessor, or someone new to your team can hit the ground running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also challenge you to look at internet policies/procedures… oh wait.. they call those features.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>APPLE: A Modern Day Willy Wonka Story</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-10-12-apple-a-modern-day-willy-wonka-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2009 15:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-10-12-apple-a-modern-day-willy-wonka-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yes, I just called everyone who works at Apple an Oompa Loompa, but I digress:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was reading Brooke Crothers&#39; story on the Apple &amp;lsquo;gag&amp;rsquo; order [1] and couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but think of how Apple has created an almost similar situation. Everyone wants to know what Apple is up to, can&amp;rsquo;t stop talking about it. Buzz Out Loud [2] even had people call and email asking them to see if they could do a show without mentioning Apple or the iPhone. According to Brooke&amp;rsquo;s article, people are afraid for their very jobs (pun?) even in the mentioning of Apple. What&amp;rsquo;s behind the curtains at Apple? Is Steve Jobs going to send out 5 golden Apple Tablets? Probably not, but I can&amp;rsquo;t shake the image of Steve coming out on stage to do one of his presentations with a cane and doing a fake fall to the podium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I pose this crucial question to you, the reader: Who plays the part of Slugworth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[1] &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.cnet.com/8301-13924_3-10372535-64.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20&#34;&gt;http://news.cnet.com/8301-13924_3-10372535-64.html?part=rss&amp;amp;subj=news&amp;amp;tag=2547-1_3-0-20&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[2] &lt;a href=&#34;http://bol.cnet.com&#34;&gt;http://bol.cnet.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back on Twitter</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-10-11-back-on-twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2009 19:09:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-10-11-back-on-twitter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been debating making this kind of post for about a week, and I apologize for the RSS spam. But it was getting a bit repetitive telling people via DM, email or other communication what happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I took my hiatus from Twitter, I zero&amp;rsquo;d out my followers, so, if you care to, please check to see if you are still following me. I will be watching my follows closely and will refollow people I might have missed in my initial run through.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://twitter.com/mubix&#34;&gt;http://twitter.com/mubix&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks,
Rob&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Corrections and Questions about Nessus on Securabit</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-09-16-corrections-and-questions-about-nessus-on-securabit/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2009 17:52:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-09-16-corrections-and-questions-about-nessus-on-securabit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update&lt;/em&gt; I can&amp;rsquo;t say with 100% certainty that Nessus ever used NMAP as it&amp;rsquo;s base scanner, I was going off of memory. I apologize for not being perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update 2&lt;/em&gt; Since people can&amp;rsquo;t seem to let it go, I would say that I was totally wrong and the nmap was absolutely never used in nessus ever, but then I would be caught in another absolute that I can&amp;rsquo;t confirm. According to their wiki, the nmap nasl script were taken out because people were No, I haven&amp;rsquo;t listened to the latest episode of Securabit in which Paul comes on and talks about Nessus. If he states in there that nmap was never the port scanning engine for nessus, then please go bug him if you think he is wrong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update 3&lt;/em&gt; Ron Gula of Tenable has confirmed via email that Nessus has never used nmap as it&amp;rsquo;s base scanner. Also, Attrition.org posted a bit of history on the subject: &lt;a href=&#34;http://attrition.org/misc/ee/nessus_and_nmap.html&#34;&gt;http://attrition.org/misc/ee/nessus_and_nmap.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.securabit.com/&#34;&gt;Securabit&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.securabit.com/2009/08/25/securabit-episode-37-%e2%80%93-mapping-networks-with-fyodor-and-nmap/&#34;&gt; Episode 37&lt;/a&gt; - I made the statement that some people could be running nmap and not even know it. While this could still hold true, the context I put around it. &amp;ldquo;Nessus uses nmap for scanning&amp;rdquo; showed my years a bit. That statement is now a falsehood. Nessus uses it&amp;rsquo;s own &amp;ldquo;optimized&amp;rdquo; port scanner. I put quotes around the word &amp;ldquo;optimized&amp;rdquo; simply because I don&amp;rsquo;t know what tweaks that have been done. Paul Asadorian from PaulDotCom Security Weekly sent an email into Securabit letting us know of the error.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t take the news very gallantly, but Paul was nice enough to lay out how someone would go about using nmap with Nessus these day. Those steps are pretty drawn out too, which I find kinda disheartining that not only do you not have nmap as your base port scanner, but the NASL scripts to use nmap are no longer included in the base install of Nessus (according to Paul, I haven&amp;rsquo;t confirmed that, but he does work for the company). And who knows why they decided to leave those script out, but you will have your chance to ask those questions because Paul will be on Securabit LIVE tonight to tie up any loose ends and talk about Nessus tonight at 8 PM EST (September 16th 2009).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more info about tonight&amp;rsquo;s show:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.securabit.com/2009/09/15/securabit-live-wednesday-with-paul-asadoorian-from-pauldotcom/&#34;&gt;http://www.securabit.com/2009/09/15/securabit-live-wednesday-with-paul-asadoorian-from-pauldotcom/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simplicity is Security</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-08-13-simplicity-is-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Aug 2009 15:30:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-08-13-simplicity-is-security/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Per the best of the best in presenting, what breeds a good presentation slide deck? Simplicity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to pose a statement. &amp;ldquo;Simplicity is Security&amp;rdquo;. The reason I say this is that this day in age, at least in the US, &amp;lsquo;convenience&amp;rsquo; is king. And we try to protect those conveniences with &amp;lsquo;security&amp;rsquo;. Let me start over a bit, this train of thought all started when I started to explain the insecurities in WiMAX to my wife. We saw a WiMAX device that plugged straight into your computer. I told her this was bad because by connecting to this you have no barrier between you and the &amp;lsquo;bad guys&amp;rsquo; other than possibly the Windows Firewall. Her answer surprised me. &amp;lsquo;So?&amp;rsquo; is all she said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Japan doesn&amp;rsquo;t use &amp;lsquo;Check Cards&amp;rsquo; or even really credit cards for that matter. To get such a card you need to go through a book worth of paper work, so it&amp;rsquo;s just not &amp;lsquo;convenient&amp;rsquo; for most people, so they don&amp;rsquo;t get them. So guess what? They don&amp;rsquo;t bank online, and they don&amp;rsquo;t buy stuff online. I racked my brain to figure out what possibly could be on her computer that a &amp;lsquo;bad guy&amp;rsquo; would want. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t think of anything (maybe you can). The government relies on paper backups of anything electronic (so they hardly make electronic versions). Signatures are based on stamps that are difficult to copy. The worst a hacker could do on her computer is use it as a zombie, and even then, their ISPs detect and disconnect excessive use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Where did we as &amp;ldquo;Security Professionals&amp;rdquo; go wrong? Was it the fat paychecks we wanted? Was it the fear of the &amp;lsquo;underground&amp;rsquo;? Reality seems to dictate that we will continue on this path from the analog to the digital, from paper and clerks to networks and AI. The question I want to ask you though is; Should we continue down the path of &amp;ldquo;MORE SECURITY&amp;rdquo; or should we deviate a bit for simpler, possibly non-technical practices?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In these last two posts you may assume that I favor the Japanese culture and way of life over a US one. You would be mistaken, I simply learn, take the best parts of what I learn, and try to apply them where I can. Learning from others triumphs and defeats, strengths and weaknesses is a basic human function that we a humanoids should embrace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Applied Network Security Density</title>
      <link>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-08-12-applied-network-security-density/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2009 15:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://malicious.link/post/2009/2009-08-12-applied-network-security-density/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently visited Tokyo, Japan. Just as always, my curiosity got the best of me and I started to calculate the population density of the buildings where I was staying. Giving fudge factor of non-populated apartments, I estimated 8,500 families in twelve 15 story buildings, living in a 1.5 mile square piece of land.That&amp;rsquo;s CRAZY. Mass transit and unrestricted modes of transit are not a whim, they are a requirement. I bet you&amp;rsquo;re asking how this applies to security, or for that matter computers at all. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t. But one of it&amp;rsquo;s effects does.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As an effect of this density, the Mom &amp;amp; Pap stores businesses flourish. In it&amp;rsquo;s density, the &amp;ldquo;big iron&amp;rdquo; is just too inconvenient, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. I used the reference for a reason. It was my own mental bridge between the &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; and security world (anyone who denies the difference is confused, and/or just left DefCon).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is the &amp;ldquo;Big Iron&amp;rdquo; in the security world? Central management, Correlation, and other ways of supposedly spending &amp;ldquo;less&amp;rdquo; on security by having less points of failure. So this is where I stray from the path. I think that networks need to mimic their worldly equivalent. Large organizations need to take an page from Tokyo and decentralize. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s hard getting &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; people, and trust is not something we easily come by in this industry, but from an offensive point of view, centralization just means a bigger payoff. Higher walls, maybe, but an &amp;lsquo;easier&amp;rsquo; target to zero in on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what does this mean? I eluded to it a bit in my previous paragraph, but what it means is more hands on. We need to train the &amp;lsquo;security guards&amp;rsquo; of our network and put them at every location we have a grouping of nodes. The smaller the grouping of nodes the better. VLANs are not enough. I&amp;rsquo;m going to use the the dreaded &amp;ldquo;Defense in Depth&amp;rdquo; phrase: We need to make our defense in depth smaller, more compact. Make it to the point where you don&amp;rsquo;t NEED &amp;ldquo;Big Iron&amp;rdquo; because you have such small perimeters that open source stuff on an old *nix box would work just fine. Yes, that&amp;rsquo;s a bit of an exaggeration but you get the point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every city is different and unique, as is any network, and I am by no means saying that decentralization is for everyone. What I do think is that big organizations are getting too hung up on devices and one stop shops where they can set up a NOC and expect a number, however many, of people to be able to watch everything going on. Exactly the way that corporations lose touch with their employees because of their size, they are loosing touch with their network and how it works. How many places have you worked that they have a good diagram of nodes (not just subnets) on their network? Much less documentation on those nodes. How exactly are you supposed to centrally monitor something you have very little knowledge of? Will it take as many years as it did with personnel to reconnect with the life of the network? Probably, but I hope not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As always, I am open to debate and hearing about flaws in my logic, so please leave a comment and tell me what you think.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
