<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Room362</title>
    <link>https://room362.com/categories/work/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Room362</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <atom:link href="https://room362.com/categories/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Toilet Peril</title>
      <link>https://room362.com/post/2005/2005-08-02-toilet-peril</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2005 01:17:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://room362.com/post/2005/2005-08-02-toilet-peril</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One should never be made to make a decision such as the one I&amp;rsquo;m about to share with you:  Where I work, there are two Male restrooms. One is downstairs, still within &amp;lsquo;hurry&amp;rsquo; distance, and the other is just across the hall. You are probably thinking, &amp;lsquo;Where is the decision in that?&amp;rsquo;. Well this is where it gets interesting. Both are alright for number 1 traffic. No big deal, in and out. But number 2 is a different story. Here are the stats on both restrooms:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Upstairs&lt;/strong&gt;: 3 stalls, one is out of order (Stall 2). Stall 1 never stops flushing (so when you wipe, your hand gets wet), Stall 3 will flush, so fast that it will actually make your pants wet.. no matter what.. (this thing gets distance) and the whole bathroom is pretty dirty. Although this bathroom is nice and warm. (See the next line for why this is an important statement)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Downstairs&lt;/strong&gt;: 2 stalls, freezing cold, so cold that constipation is a natural reaction. On the upside, it is always clean and hardly anyone is ever in there so, if you are &amp;lsquo;loud&amp;rsquo; you have the convience. Again, it is down a flight of stairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which would you choose?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>